{
	"description": "More Japanese expressions",
	"type": "text",
	"timeout": 20,
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "to be on one's mind; to worry one; to care about; to be bothered by; to feel uneasy; to be anxious; to be curious about\nto feel like; to feel inclined to\nto fancy; to like; to catch one's eye\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気になる", "きになる" ], "comment": "Rank #1 (14247 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to mind (negative nuance); to care about; to worry; to pay undue (amount of) attention to (something)\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気にする", "きにする" ], "comment": "Rank #2 (7642 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold (in one's hand); to take (into one's hand)\nto own; to obtain\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手にする", "てにする" ], "comment": "Rank #3 (7635 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to taste; to eat\nto speak of; to refer to\n\nHint: 口に・・・", "answers": [ "口にする", "くちにする" ], "comment": "Rank #4 (7589 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to open one's mouth (to talk)\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を開く", "くちをひらく" ], "comment": "Rank #5 (6946 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bow; to bow one's head\nto apologize; to apologise\nto bow to; to yield to; to admire\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を下げる", "あたまをさげる" ], "comment": "Rank #6 (6912 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise one's voice\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を上げる", "こえをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #7 (5162 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to experience\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を見る", "めをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #8 (4781 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be pleased with; to suit\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に入る", "きにいる" ], "comment": "Rank #9 (4602 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shrug one's shoulders\n\nHint: 肩を・・・", "answers": [ "肩をすくめる", "かたをすくめる" ], "comment": "Rank #10 (4135 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to obtain; to procure\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に入れる", "てにいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #11 (4105 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to act as an intermediary\n\nHint: 中に・・・", "answers": [ "中に入る", "なかにはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #12 (3966 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a breath; to take a short rest\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を吐く", "いきをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #13 (3734 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn up; to make an appearance; to put in an appearance\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔を出す", "かおをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #14 (3597 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to incline one's head to the side (in doubt); to tilt one's head to the side (in confusion); to be puzzled\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を傾げる", "くびをかしげる" ], "comment": "Rank #15 (3157 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be helpful; to be useful\n\nHint: 役に・・・", "answers": [ "役に立つ", "やくにたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #16 (2849 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pretend not to see; to turn one's back on\n\nHint: 背を・・・", "answers": [ "背を向ける", "せをむける" ], "comment": "Rank #17 (2594 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hear; to hear by chance; to hear by accident; to catch (the sound)\n\nHint: 耳に・・・", "answers": [ "耳にする", "みみにする" ], "comment": "Rank #18 (2463 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "just right; ideal; perfectly suitable\nfetch!; bring me ...\n\nHint: 持っ・・・", "answers": [ "持って来い", "もってこい" ], "comment": "Rank #19 (2425 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn one's hand to; to reach out one's hand\nto get involved in; to make a move on\nto start a fight; to make a move in violence\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を出す", "てをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #20 (2381 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shift one's attention to; to shift one's focus on\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を向ける", "めをむける" ], "comment": "Rank #21 (2378 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to disappear\n\nHint: 姿を・・・", "answers": [ "姿を消す", "すがたをけす" ], "comment": "Rank #22 (2375 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shake one's head\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を横に振る", "くびをよこにふる" ], "comment": "Rank #23 (2364 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to receive favor (favour); to be much obliged to someone; to be indebted\n\nHint: 世話に・・・", "answers": [ "世話になる", "せわになる" ], "comment": "Rank #24 (2276 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to see; to witness; to observe; to catch sight of; to get a glimpse of; to encounter\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目にする", "めにする" ], "comment": "Rank #25 (2097 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to dream; to have a dream\n\nHint: 夢を・・・", "answers": [ "夢を見る", "ゆめをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #26 (2044 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stare in wonder; to be amazed\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を丸くする", "めをまるくする" ], "comment": "Rank #27 (2026 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have an interest (in something); to feel inclined (toward doing something)\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気がある", "きがある" ], "comment": "Rank #28 (2014 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to wake up\nto sober up; to come to one's senses; to become enlightened\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を覚ます", "めをさます" ], "comment": "Rank #29 (1993 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put into words; to express\n\nHint: 口に・・・", "answers": [ "口に出す", "くちにだす" ], "comment": "Rank #30 (1945 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lie down (and rest)\n\nHint: 横に・・・", "answers": [ "横になる", "よこになる" ], "comment": "Rank #31 (1893 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to catch one's breath; to gulp; to have one's breath taken away; to gasp\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を呑む", "いきをのむ" ], "comment": "Rank #32 (1876 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to withdraw from (a deal); to wash one's hands of\nto lead by the hand\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を引く", "てをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #33 (1838 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fold one's arms\nto link arms with someone\n\nHint: 腕を・・・", "answers": [ "腕を組む", "うでをくむ" ], "comment": "Rank #34 (1770 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to catch sight of; to come into view; to happen to see\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に入る", "めにはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #35 (1694 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come to one's senses\nto calm down\n\nHint: 我に・・・", "answers": [ "我に返る", "われにかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #36 (1664 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be visible\nclear; distinct; apparent\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に見える", "めにみえる" ], "comment": "Rank #37 (1514 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hear of\n\nHint: 耳に・・・", "answers": [ "耳に入る", "みみにはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #38 (1491 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose consciousness; to faint; to black out\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を失う", "きをうしなう" ], "comment": "Rank #39 (1490 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get up (e.g. from bed)\nto make one's way in the world; to achieve in life\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を起こす", "みをおこす" ], "comment": "Rank #40 (1475 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take measures (in face of events being anticipated)\nto come to an agreement (in bargaining, etc.); to strike a bargain\nto clap one's hands together\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を打つ", "てをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #41 (1471 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to coo at; to behave like a spoiled child\nto snort; to sniff\n\nHint: 鼻を・・・", "answers": [ "鼻を鳴らす", "はなをならす" ], "comment": "Rank #42 (1452 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get angry; to take offense; to take offence; to be furious\n\nHint: 腹が・・・", "answers": [ "腹が立つ", "はらがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #43 (1431 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to notice; to become aware; to perceive; to realize; to realise\nto be scrupulous; to be attentive\nto recover consciousness; to come to oneself\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が付く", "きがつく" ], "comment": "Rank #44 (1420 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be noticeable; to notice; to catch one's eye\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目につく", "めにつく" ], "comment": "Rank #45 (1371 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cast down one's eyes\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を伏せる", "めをふせる" ], "comment": "Rank #46 (1364 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to set foot into; to enter; to step inside; to cross the threshold\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を踏み入れる", "あしをふみいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #47 (1355 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise one's hand or hands\nto surrender\nto raise a hand to someone (as a threat to strike)\nto improve\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を上げる", "てをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #48 (1354 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to meet; to face someone\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔を合わせる", "かおをあわせる" ], "comment": "Rank #49 (1339 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take offense; to take offence; to get angry; to lose one's temper\n\nHint: 腹を・・・", "answers": [ "腹を立てる", "はらをたてる" ], "comment": "Rank #50 (1309 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to awaken; to perk up; to snap out (of something)\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が覚める", "めがさめる" ], "comment": "Rank #51 (1271 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw out one's chest; to be puffed up with pride\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を張る", "むねをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #52 (1245 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pause; to have a short intermission\n\nHint: 間を・・・", "answers": [ "間を置く", "まをおく" ], "comment": "Rank #53 (1218 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shut one's eyes\nto ignore; to pretend not to know\nto die\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目をつぶる", "めをつぶる" ], "comment": "Rank #54 (1193 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be greatly perplexed; to be troubled; to be at wits' end\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を抱える", "あたまをかかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #55 (1188 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make sure of; to call attention to; to emphasize; to emphasise\n\nHint: 念を・・・", "answers": [ "念を押す", "ねんをおす" ], "comment": "Rank #56 (1187 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make fun of; to look down on; to make light of\n\nHint: 馬鹿に・・・", "answers": [ "馬鹿にする", "ばかにする" ], "comment": "Rank #57 (1175 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cut into (a conversation); to interject\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を挟む", "くちをはさむ" ], "comment": "Rank #58 (1134 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shake one's head (in denial)\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を振る", "かぶりをふる" ], "comment": "Rank #59 (1126 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to place both hands on the ground (to express respect, apology or to present a request)\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を突く", "てをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #60 (1122 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lend an ear; to hearken; to give an ear to; to listen carefully\n\nHint: 耳を・・・", "answers": [ "耳を傾ける", "みみをかたむける" ], "comment": "Rank #61 (1072 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take someone's hand\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を取る", "てをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #62 (1038 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come together; to join\n\nHint: 一緒に・・・", "answers": [ "一緒になる", "いっしょになる" ], "comment": "Rank #63 (1033 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to listen carefully; to strain one's ears\n\nHint: 耳を・・・", "answers": [ "耳を澄ます", "みみをすます" ], "comment": "Rank #64 (1026 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lead; to take the initiative\nto take precedence (e.g. sadness taking precedence over anger)\nto be most essential\n\nHint: 先に・・・", "answers": [ "先に立つ", "さきにたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #65 (1021 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to perspire; to sweat\n\nHint: 汗を・・・", "answers": [ "汗をかく", "あせをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #66 (1009 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look away; to avert one's eyes\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を逸らす", "めをそらす" ], "comment": "Rank #67 (1003 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go; to come; to turn out (at a meeting, event, etc.); to show up; to make your way to\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を運ぶ", "あしをはこぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #68 (992 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to interrupt a conversation\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を出す", "くちをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #69 (988 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unacceptable; no good; complete failure; inadequate\n\nHint: なっ・・・", "answers": [ "なっていない", "なっていない" ], "comment": "Rank #70 (988 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to prove successful; to come to good; to take hold\n\nHint: 物に・・・", "answers": [ "物になる", "ものになる" ], "comment": "Rank #71 (987 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to greet; to call out to someone\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を掛ける", "こえをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #72 (978 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shed light; to cast light\n\nHint: 光を・・・", "answers": [ "光を放つ", "ひかりをはなつ" ], "comment": "Rank #73 (962 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn on one's heel; to turn back; to return\n\nHint: 踵を・・・", "answers": [ "踵を返す", "きびすをかえす", "くびすをかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #74 (961 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It's no joke\nGimme a break!; Sod that!\n\nHint: 冗談・・・", "answers": [ "冗談じゃない", "じょうだんじゃない" ], "comment": "Rank #76 (944 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "natural; understandable\n\nHint: 無理も・・・", "answers": [ "無理もない", "むりもない" ], "comment": "Rank #77 (928 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to correct; to touch up; to smarten up\nto put one's hand in (e.g. pocket)\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を入れる", "てをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #78 (899 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come to mind; to pop into one's head\n\nHint: 頭に・・・", "answers": [ "頭に浮かぶ", "あたまにうかぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #79 (870 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "droop one's shoulders (in disappointment); to drop one's shoulders\n\nHint: 肩を・・・", "answers": [ "肩を落とす", "かたをおとす" ], "comment": "Rank #80 (868 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to strain one's eyes; to look closely; to stare at\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を凝らす", "めをこらす" ], "comment": "Rank #81 (851 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "at disadvantage; having no edge; having poor prospects\n\nHint: 分が・・・", "answers": [ "分が悪い", "ぶがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #82 (848 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lend a hand; to help\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を貸す", "てをかす" ], "comment": "Rank #83 (848 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to half-rise to one's feet\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を浮かす", "こしをうかす" ], "comment": "Rank #84 (845 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to act as an intermediary; to step in; to come between; to intervene; to interject\n\nHint: 間に・・・", "answers": [ "間に入る", "あいだにはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #85 (841 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a fist; to clench one's fist\n\nHint: 拳を・・・", "answers": [ "拳を握る", "こぶしをにぎる" ], "comment": "Rank #86 (841 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take one's eyes off\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を離す", "めをはなす" ], "comment": "Rank #87 (831 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be helpful; to be dependable\n\nHint: 力に・・・", "answers": [ "力になる", "ちからになる" ], "comment": "Rank #88 (823 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have an eye on; to zero in on\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目をつける", "めをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #89 (801 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to float in the air\nto be unfinished; to be unsettled; to be undecided\n\nHint: 宙に・・・", "answers": [ "宙に浮く", "ちゅうにうく" ], "comment": "Rank #90 (794 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be wide-eyed (in surprise); to open one's eyes wide (in wonder); to be amazed (at, by)\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を見張る", "めをみはる" ], "comment": "Rank #91 (773 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to scan; to look over\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を通す", "めをとおす" ], "comment": "Rank #92 (763 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to live under another's roof; to become a dependent on\nto flatten oneself (against); to lean in close to\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を寄せる", "みをよせる" ], "comment": "Rank #93 (760 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise one's voice; to shout\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を張り上げる", "こえをはりあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #94 (753 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be careful; to pay attention; to take care\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を付ける", "きをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #95 (743 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(Stand to) attention!\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を付け", "きをつけ" ], "comment": "Rank #96 (743 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn one's back on\nto be uninterested in\n\nHint: 背中を・・・", "answers": [ "背中を向ける", "せなかをむける" ], "comment": "Rank #97 (742 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put effort into; to strain; to put strength into; to put forth effort\n\nHint: 力を・・・", "answers": [ "力を入れる", "ちからをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #98 (712 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn one's back to\n\nHint: 背に・・・", "answers": [ "背にする", "せにする" ], "comment": "Rank #99 (697 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to join hands together\nto join forces; to collaborate\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を組む", "てをくむ" ], "comment": "Rank #100 (676 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to open one's eyes wide (in anger, surprise, etc.); to goggle at\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を剥く", "めをむく" ], "comment": "Rank #101 (652 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get up (from sitting)\nto finally start to do something; to get off one's arse (ass)\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を上げる", "こしをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #102 (648 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to force one's way through\n\nHint: 割っ・・・", "answers": [ "割って入る", "わってはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #103 (647 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to exchange words\n\nHint: 言葉を・・・", "answers": [ "言葉を交わす", "ことばをかわす" ], "comment": "Rank #104 (641 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bear up in tragedy; to stand pain well; to hold one's temper\nto clench one's teeth; to grit one's teeth\n\nHint: 歯を・・・", "answers": [ "歯を食いしばる", "はをくいしばる" ], "comment": "Rank #105 (629 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become blue; to turn green\nto turn pale; to blanch (with fear)\n\nHint: 青く・・・", "answers": [ "青くなる", "あおくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #106 (609 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cock one's head in puzzlement; to tilt one's head in contemplation; to wrack one's brain; to think hard\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を捻る", "くびをひねる" ], "comment": "Rank #107 (608 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "no matter what it takes; by any means necessary; at all costs; by hook or by crook\n\nHint: 何と・・・", "answers": [ "何としても", "なんとしても" ], "comment": "Rank #108 (599 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to care for someone; to look after someone\n\nHint: 面倒を・・・", "answers": [ "面倒を見る", "めんどうをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #109 (590 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make use of aizuchi; to back-channel; to throw in interjections to show that one is paying attention\n\nHint: 相槌を・・・", "answers": [ "相槌を打つ", "あいづちをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #110 (589 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to completely rethink; to pull one's self together\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を取り直す", "きをとりなおす" ], "comment": "Rank #111 (585 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do one good; to be beneficial; to be good for the body; to be helpful\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身になる", "みになる" ], "comment": "Rank #112 (584 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put out one's tongue; to stick out one's tongue\n\nHint: 舌を・・・", "answers": [ "舌を出す", "したをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #113 (576 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be at a loss; to be puzzled\n\nHint: 途方に・・・", "answers": [ "途方に暮れる", "とほうにくれる" ], "comment": "Rank #114 (572 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to laugh scornfully\n\nHint: 鼻で・・・", "answers": [ "鼻で笑う", "はなでわらう" ], "comment": "Rank #115 (554 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become good-looking; to start looking appropriate (for something)\n\nHint: 様に・・・", "answers": [ "様になる", "さまになる" ], "comment": "Rank #116 (532 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get; to secure; to take possession of; to make one's own; to win (someone's heart)\nto learn; to master\nto complete\n\nHint: 物に・・・", "answers": [ "物にする", "ものにする" ], "comment": "Rank #117 (530 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look away; to turn away\n\nHint: 横を・・・", "answers": [ "横を向く", "よこをむく" ], "comment": "Rank #118 (521 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to open the lid; to lift a lid\nto open the lid (on); to make public\nto start (something)\nto look at the results (consequences, outcome, effect); to look at the condition of something\nto open (of a theatre)\n\nHint: 蓋を・・・", "answers": [ "蓋を開ける", "ふたをあける" ], "comment": "Rank #119 (515 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be elated; to be excited; to be caught up in the moment; to be carried away; to get cocky\nto get up to speed; to move into gear\n\nHint: 調子に・・・", "answers": [ "調子に乗る", "ちょうしにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #120 (501 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to speak; to utter\nto mediate\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を利く", "くちをきく" ], "comment": "Rank #121 (496 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fire from a job; to dismiss; to discharge\nto behead\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を切る", "くびをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #122 (468 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose one's life\n\nHint: 命を・・・", "answers": [ "命を落とす", "いのちをおとす" ], "comment": "Rank #123 (463 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be satisfied; to feel good\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が済む", "きがすむ" ], "comment": "Rank #124 (463 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be taken aback; to be astonished; to be dumbfounded\n\nHint: 呆気に・・・", "answers": [ "呆気にとられる", "あっけにとられる" ], "comment": "Rank #125 (463 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to picture; to come into one's mind; to remember\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に浮かぶ", "めにうかぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #126 (456 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to assist; to help out\n\nHint: 力を・・・", "answers": [ "力を貸す", "ちからをかす" ], "comment": "Rank #127 (451 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep a watchful eye on\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を光らす", "めをひからす" ], "comment": "Rank #128 (451 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to leave a trail; to leave traces; to have a lasting effect\n\nHint: 尾を・・・", "answers": [ "尾を引く", "おをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #129 (439 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pay attention; to be watchful\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を配る", "きをくばる" ], "comment": "Rank #130 (437 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bare one's fangs; to snarl at\n\nHint: 牙を・・・", "answers": [ "牙を剥く", "きばをむく" ], "comment": "Rank #131 (435 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do oneself; to do by oneself\nto start work (on); to commence\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を下す", "てをくだす" ], "comment": "Rank #132 (435 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold one's breath; to catch one's breath\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を殺す", "いきをころす" ], "comment": "Rank #133 (434 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose focus; to let one's mind wander; to relax one's attention\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を抜く", "きをぬく" ], "comment": "Rank #134 (431 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make the necessary preparations in secret\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を回す", "てをまわす" ], "comment": "Rank #135 (429 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to breathe heavily (e.g. with much movement of the shoulders)\n\nHint: 肩で・・・", "answers": [ "肩で息をする", "かたでいきをする" ], "comment": "Rank #136 (428 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a matter of time; matter of hours; question of time\n\nHint: 時間の・・・", "answers": [ "時間の問題", "じかんのもんだい" ], "comment": "Rank #137 (428 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be embarrassed; to lose face\n\nHint: 恥を・・・", "answers": [ "恥をかく", "はじをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #138 (425 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to let out a cry; to shout\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を立てる", "こえをたてる" ], "comment": "Rank #139 (424 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to devote oneself; to do one thing exclusively; to make a job of\nto decide to\n\nHint: 事と・・・", "answers": [ "事とする", "こととする" ], "comment": "Rank #140 (418 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep one's mouth shut; to refuse to talk\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を閉ざす", "くちをとざす" ], "comment": "Rank #141 (414 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "profitable; lucrative\n\nHint: 金に・・・", "answers": [ "金になる", "かねになる" ], "comment": "Rank #142 (414 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "having a headache\nracking one's brains; troubling over something\n\nHint: 頭が・・・", "answers": [ "頭が痛い", "あたまがいたい" ], "comment": "Rank #143 (411 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "depressed; bummed out; down; heavy-hearted; heavy-spirited; feeling reluctant (to do)\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が重い", "きがおもい" ], "comment": "Rank #144 (399 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to work hard; to sweat\nto wash off one's sweat\n\nHint: 汗を・・・", "answers": [ "汗を流す", "あせをながす" ], "comment": "Rank #145 (393 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "quickly, suddenly (while one is watching); before one's eyes\n\nHint: 見る・・・", "answers": [ "見る間に", "みるまに" ], "comment": "Rank #146 (392 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw oneself (e.g. off a cliff, etc.)\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を投げる", "みをなげる" ], "comment": "Rank #147 (391 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bend one's head slightly to one side; to look slightly doubtful\n\nHint: 小首を・・・", "answers": [ "小首を傾げる", "こくびをかしげる" ], "comment": "Rank #148 (388 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pout\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を尖らせる", "くちをとがらせる" ], "comment": "Rank #149 (386 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to faint; to lose consciousness\nto feel overwhelmed; to be astounded\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が遠くなる", "きがとおくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #150 (384 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to blush\n\nHint: 頬を・・・", "answers": [ "頬を染める", "ほおをそめる" ], "comment": "Rank #151 (378 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to experience chest pain; to have a pain in one's chest\nto feel sick at heart; to have one's heart ache; to be anguished\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が痛む", "むねがいたむ" ], "comment": "Rank #152 (372 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go flying along; to move fast (against the wind)\n\nHint: 風を・・・", "answers": [ "風を切る", "かぜをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #153 (369 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not worth considering; out of the question\n\nHint: 話に・・・", "answers": [ "話にならない", "はなしにならない" ], "comment": "Rank #154 (365 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to require much effort; to be hard to do\n\nHint: 骨が・・・", "answers": [ "骨が折れる", "ほねがおれる" ], "comment": "Rank #155 (359 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be evasive; to not commit oneself\n\nHint: 言葉を・・・", "answers": [ "言葉を濁す", "ことばをにごす" ], "comment": "Rank #156 (353 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "presenting no difficulty; not hard\n\nHint: 物な・・・", "answers": [ "物ならず", "ものならず" ], "comment": "Rank #157 (353 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to attract someone's affection\nto sound out somebody\nto get one's hooks into\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を引く", "きをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #158 (352 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have one's attention attracted (caught); to be preoccupied with\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を取られる", "きをとられる" ], "comment": "Rank #159 (348 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It's no use\n\nHint: 始ま・・・", "answers": [ "始まらない", "はじまらない" ], "comment": "Rank #160 (347 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stand, walk, etc. shoulder-to-shoulder\nto be on a par with\n\nHint: 肩を・・・", "answers": [ "肩を並べる", "かたをならべる" ], "comment": "Rank #161 (339 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to attract notice; to catch the eye; to stand out\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を引く", "めをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #162 (337 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be able to reach; to be within one's reach; to be able to afford; to have the means to buy\nto be near (a certain age)\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が届く", "てがとどく" ], "comment": "Rank #163 (336 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "serves you right!; see what happens!\n\nHint: 様を・・・", "answers": [ "様を見ろ", "ざまをみろ" ], "comment": "Rank #164 (334 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be descended from; to inherit (a disposition, etc.) from one's ancestors\n\nHint: 血を・・・", "answers": [ "血を引く", "ちをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #165 (333 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to not believe one's ears\n\nHint: 耳を・・・", "answers": [ "耳を疑う", "みみをうたがう" ], "comment": "Rank #166 (329 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make efforts; to take pains\nto break one's bone\n\nHint: 骨を・・・", "answers": [ "骨を折る", "ほねをおる" ], "comment": "Rank #167 (326 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to dislocate one's back\nto be unable to stand up due to fear or surprise\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を抜かす", "こしをぬかす" ], "comment": "Rank #168 (323 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be excited about; to get all worked up about\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が立つ", "きがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #169 (323 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to mediate; to intervene\n\nHint: 間に・・・", "answers": [ "間に立つ", "あいだにたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #170 (319 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold one's breath\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を詰める", "いきをつめる" ], "comment": "Rank #171 (318 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "nonchalant air; unruffled air\n\nHint: 涼し・・・", "answers": [ "涼しい顔", "すずしいかお" ], "comment": "Rank #172 (313 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pay attention to another's needs; to attend to; to fuss about; to take into consideration\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を使う", "きをつかう" ], "comment": "Rank #173 (311 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to reply; to respond; to answer\n\nHint: 言葉を・・・", "answers": [ "言葉を返す", "ことばをかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #174 (308 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to accept help; to get help; to ask for help\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を借りる", "てをかりる" ], "comment": "Rank #175 (306 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold one's tongue; to shut up\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を噤む", "くちをつぐむ" ], "comment": "Rank #176 (306 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to doubt one's own eyes\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を疑う", "めをうたがう" ], "comment": "Rank #177 (305 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to solve a mystery\n\nHint: 謎を・・・", "answers": [ "謎を解く", "なぞをとく" ], "comment": "Rank #178 (299 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to outwit; to outsmart; to counterplot; to defeat\nto pierce something all the way through\n\nHint: 裏を・・・", "answers": [ "裏をかく", "うらをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #179 (299 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "cannot understand; doesn't make sense; unconvincing; hard to swallow; doesn't ring true\n\nHint: 腑に・・・", "answers": [ "腑に落ちない", "ふにおちない" ], "comment": "Rank #180 (292 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "beyond imagination; unimaginable\n\nHint: 想像を・・・", "answers": [ "想像を絶する", "そうぞうをぜっする" ], "comment": "Rank #181 (292 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "after all is said and done; to say the least\n\nHint: 何と・・・", "answers": [ "何と言っても", "なんといっても" ], "comment": "Rank #182 (290 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "reluctant to; not inclined to; disinclined; unwilling\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が進まない", "きがすすまない" ], "comment": "Rank #183 (289 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give off sparks; to spark; to scintillate\nto have a heated argument; to combat; to do something fiercely\n\nHint: 火花を・・・", "answers": [ "火花を散らす", "ひばなをちらす" ], "comment": "Rank #184 (289 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to meet face-to-face\n\nHint: 面と・・・", "answers": [ "面と向かう", "めんとむかう" ], "comment": "Rank #185 (288 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pant; to gasp; to be short of breath; to be excited\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を弾ませる", "いきをはずませる" ], "comment": "Rank #186 (287 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to forget oneself; to lose control of oneself\n\nHint: 我を・・・", "answers": [ "我を忘れる", "われをわすれる" ], "comment": "Rank #187 (282 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to dart one's eyes about; to be surprised; to be bewildered; to be confused; to be flustered\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を白黒させる", "めをしろくろさせる" ], "comment": "Rank #188 (281 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get goosebumps\n\nHint: 鳥肌が・・・", "answers": [ "鳥肌が立つ", "とりはだがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #189 (281 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take seriously; to believe\n\nHint: 真に・・・", "answers": [ "真に受ける", "まにうける" ], "comment": "Rank #190 (280 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pay attention to; to make sure; to double check\n\nHint: 念を・・・", "answers": [ "念を入れる", "ねんをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #191 (278 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to choke; to have trouble breathing\n\nHint: 息が・・・", "answers": [ "息が詰まる", "いきがつまる" ], "comment": "Rank #192 (278 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "usual; mediocre; monotonous\n\nHint: 変哲も・・・", "answers": [ "変哲もない", "へんてつもない" ], "comment": "Rank #193 (276 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to settle down; to get a steady job; to marry and raise a family\nto attire oneself; to outfit oneself\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を固める", "みをかためる" ], "comment": "Rank #194 (276 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to ease up (on an opponent); to cut corners; to be shoddy\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を抜く", "てをぬく" ], "comment": "Rank #195 (273 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give advice; to counsel; to take part in a consultation\n\nHint: 相談に・・・", "answers": [ "相談に乗る", "そうだんにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #196 (271 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be astonished\n\nHint: 舌を・・・", "answers": [ "舌を巻く", "したをまく" ], "comment": "Rank #197 (271 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to grow old; to age\n\nHint: 年を・・・", "answers": [ "年を取る", "としをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #198 (270 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be thirsty\n\nHint: 喉が・・・", "answers": [ "喉が渇く", "のどがかわく" ], "comment": "Rank #199 (268 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to knit one's brows (in discomfort, unease, disapproval, etc.); to raise one's eyebrows; to frown; to scowl\n\nHint: 眉を・・・", "answers": [ "眉を顰める", "まゆをひそめる" ], "comment": "Rank #200 (268 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become an expert; to be master at\n\nHint: 堂に・・・", "answers": [ "堂に入る", "どうにいる" ], "comment": "Rank #201 (265 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to flare up at\n\nHint: 食っ・・・", "answers": [ "食ってかかる", "くってかかる" ], "comment": "Rank #202 (264 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel awkward; to feel ashamed; to feel inferior; to feel shy (about doing something)\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が引ける", "きがひける" ], "comment": "Rank #203 (263 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel exhausted (after having been stressed); to feel spent; to feel relieved (from stress)\nto become stale (i.e. of a carbonated beverage); to go flat; to lose flavor; to lose flavour\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が抜ける", "きがぬける" ], "comment": "Rank #204 (263 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn over (in one's sleep); to toss and turn (in bed)\nto change sides; to double-cross; to betray\n\nHint: 寝返りを・・・", "answers": [ "寝返りを打つ", "ねがえりをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #205 (262 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get along (with someone)\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が合う", "きがあう" ], "comment": "Rank #206 (260 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "knowing only too well; being fully aware of\n\nHint: 百も・・・", "answers": [ "百も承知", "ひゃくもしょうち" ], "comment": "Rank #207 (260 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to poke one's nose into another's affairs; to have a hand in; to take a (deep) interest in; to meddle in\nto poke one's head (into a room)\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を突っ込む", "くびをつっこむ" ], "comment": "Rank #208 (257 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to resolve to do; to make up one's mind to do; to set one's heart on; to have one's heart set on\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を決める", "こころをきめる" ], "comment": "Rank #209 (255 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to roll around laughing; to fold up; to hold one's sides with laughter\n\nHint: 腹を・・・", "answers": [ "腹を抱える", "はらをかかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #210 (252 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cut off (a relationship)\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を切る", "てをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #211 (251 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lend an ear to; to listen to\n\nHint: 耳を・・・", "answers": [ "耳を貸す", "みみをかす" ], "comment": "Rank #212 (250 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cross the ocean (i.e. to go to or come from overseas)\n\nHint: 海を・・・", "answers": [ "海を渡る", "うみをわたる" ], "comment": "Rank #213 (250 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give oneself to (esp. of a woman to a man); to surrender oneself to\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を任せる", "みをまかせる" ], "comment": "Rank #214 (248 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unusually; uncharacteristically\n\nHint: 常な・・・", "answers": [ "常ならず", "つねならず" ], "comment": "Rank #215 (248 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn pale; to lose color; to lose colour\n\nHint: 色を・・・", "answers": [ "色を失う", "いろをうしなう" ], "comment": "Rank #216 (248 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to stomach; sticking in one's throat; displeased with\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に食わない", "きにくわない" ], "comment": "Rank #217 (247 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to worry; to fret (over something); to be worried; to be anxious\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に病む", "きにやむ" ], "comment": "Rank #218 (246 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to confess; to speak out; to disclose; to tell\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を割る", "くちをわる" ], "comment": "Rank #219 (241 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in front of one's eyes; just nearby; within a stone's throw\n\nHint: 目と・・・", "answers": [ "目と鼻の先", "めとはなのさき" ], "comment": "Rank #220 (240 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "anything and everything; from top to toe; from A to Z\n\nHint: 何から・・・", "answers": [ "何から何まで", "なにからなにまで" ], "comment": "Rank #221 (232 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to nod one's head; to nod yes; to agree\n\nHint: 首を・・・", "answers": [ "首を縦に振る", "くびをたてにふる" ], "comment": "Rank #222 (232 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the New Year begins; the New Year starts\n\nHint: 年が・・・", "answers": [ "年が明ける", "としがあける" ], "comment": "Rank #223 (230 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be relieved; to feel relieved\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を撫で下ろす", "むねをなでおろす" ], "comment": "Rank #224 (230 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pull (the puppet) strings; to direct things from behind the scenes\nto stretch out (and keep going); to linger on\n\nHint: 糸を・・・", "answers": [ "糸を引く", "いとをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #225 (228 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bother; to meddle; to poke one's nose (into another's business); to be too helpful\n\nHint: 世話を・・・", "answers": [ "世話を焼く", "せわをやく" ], "comment": "Rank #226 (227 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do something behind someone's back; to do something stealthily\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を盗む", "めをぬすむ" ], "comment": "Rank #227 (225 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to rack one's brains\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を悩ます", "あたまをなやます" ], "comment": "Rank #228 (224 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take care of some business; to go on an errand\nto relieve oneself; to do one's business; to go to the toilet\n\nHint: 用を・・・", "answers": [ "用を足す", "ようをたす" ], "comment": "Rank #229 (224 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in a manner of speaking; as it were; so to speak; if you like; per se\n\nHint: 言っ・・・", "answers": [ "言ってみれば", "いってみれば" ], "comment": "Rank #230 (223 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to (relax and) stretch one's legs out\nto go for a further walk\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を伸ばす", "あしをのばす" ], "comment": "Rank #231 (222 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel like; to feel inclined to do\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が向く", "きがむく" ], "comment": "Rank #232 (221 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "I don't know about ... but; it may be possible for ... but\n\nHint: いざ・・・", "answers": [ "いざ知らず", "いざしらず" ], "comment": "Rank #233 (219 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to work hard; to work diligently\n\nHint: 精を・・・", "answers": [ "精を出す", "せいをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #234 (219 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to quit (a shady business); to wash one's hands of; to cut one's ties with; to turn over a new leaf; to go straight\nto wash one's feet\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を洗う", "あしをあらう" ], "comment": "Rank #235 (218 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cast a shadow (literal or figurative)\n\nHint: 影を・・・", "answers": [ "影を落とす", "かげをおとす" ], "comment": "Rank #236 (217 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be captivated (visually)\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を奪われる", "めをうばわれる" ], "comment": "Rank #237 (217 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unknown; obscure; insignificant\n\nHint: 名も・・・", "answers": [ "名もない", "なもない" ], "comment": "Rank #238 (217 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get mad; to be highly offended; to get pissed off; to get angry; to lose one's cool\n\nHint: 頭に・・・", "answers": [ "頭に来る", "あたまにくる" ], "comment": "Rank #239 (216 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "spoiled; unmanageable; uncontrollable; incorrigible; obstreperous\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に負えない", "てにおえない" ], "comment": "Rank #240 (215 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the very picture of ...\n\nHint: 絵に・・・", "answers": [ "絵に描いたよう", "えにかいたよう" ], "comment": "Rank #241 (214 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be reduced to ashes; to be cremated\n\nHint: 灰に・・・", "answers": [ "灰になる", "はいになる" ], "comment": "Rank #242 (212 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lay hands on; to touch\nto care for; to look after\nto make off with; to steal\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を掛ける", "てをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #243 (211 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to perform some process; to apply some treatment\nto revise; to correct\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を加える", "てをくわえる" ], "comment": "Rank #244 (211 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become famous\nto go out into the world; to make one's way in the world; to appear; to be published\n\nHint: 世に・・・", "answers": [ "世に出る", "よにでる" ], "comment": "Rank #245 (211 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to count on one's fingers\n\nHint: 指を・・・", "answers": [ "指を折る", "ゆびをおる" ], "comment": "Rank #246 (210 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "peremptorily; willy-nilly; forcibly\n\nHint: 有無を・・・", "answers": [ "有無を言わせず", "うむをいわせず" ], "comment": "Rank #247 (209 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take the form (of); to assume a shape\n\nHint: 形を・・・", "answers": [ "形を取る", "かたちをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #248 (208 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to impress; to move one's heart; to touch (a person's heart)\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を動かす", "こころをうごかす" ], "comment": "Rank #249 (207 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be congenial; to agree with one; to be in one's nature\n\nHint: 性に・・・", "answers": [ "性に合う", "しょうにあう" ], "comment": "Rank #250 (207 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pursue\nto die right after a loved one; to kill oneself (because one misses or longs to be with a loved one)\nto follow an example set by earlier generations (or one's master, etc.)\n\nHint: 跡を・・・", "answers": [ "跡を追う", "あとをおう" ], "comment": "Rank #251 (206 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "out of character; unlike one\n\nHint: 柄に・・・", "answers": [ "柄にもない", "がらにもない" ], "comment": "Rank #252 (206 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "strong-willed; strong of heart\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が強い", "きがつよい" ], "comment": "Rank #253 (204 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to run out of breath; to be short of breath; to lose one's breath\nto run out of steam; to be unable to continue; to collapse\nto die\n\nHint: 息が・・・", "answers": [ "息が切れる", "いきがきれる" ], "comment": "Rank #254 (204 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hurt one's feelings; to rub someone the wrong way\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に障る", "きにさわる" ], "comment": "Rank #255 (204 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold one's breath (in fear, anxiety, etc.)\n\nHint: 固唾を・・・", "answers": [ "固唾を呑む", "かたずをのむ" ], "comment": "Rank #256 (203 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to forestall; to beat to the punch; to anticipate\nto play the first move (e.g. in go)\n\nHint: 先手を・・・", "answers": [ "先手を打つ", "せんてをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #257 (201 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cause a loss\nto make a hole (in)\n\nHint: 穴を・・・", "answers": [ "穴をあける", "あなをあける" ], "comment": "Rank #258 (201 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be ready to cry; to be on the point of tears\n\nHint: べそを・・・", "answers": [ "べそをかく", "べそをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #259 (200 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "luckily or unluckily; for good or for evil\n\nHint: 幸か・・・", "answers": [ "幸か不幸か", "こうかふこうか" ], "comment": "Rank #260 (199 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to muffle one's voice; to speak (or sob, etc.) quietly\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を殺す", "こえをころす" ], "comment": "Rank #261 (199 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get a divorce; to sever connections\n\nHint: 縁を・・・", "answers": [ "縁を切る", "えんをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #262 (198 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to accept an offer; to be charmed by someone's kind words and do as he wishes\n\nHint: 言葉に・・・", "answers": [ "言葉に甘える", "ことばにあまえる" ], "comment": "Rank #263 (196 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go through; to suffer; to experience (something unpleasant)\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に会う", "めにあう" ], "comment": "Rank #264 (193 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to catch the eye; to attract attention\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に触れる", "めにふれる" ], "comment": "Rank #265 (192 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to resume breathing; to come around; to come back to life\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を吹き返す", "いきをふきかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #266 (191 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "at any rate; anyhow; anyway; in any case; because\n\nHint: 何に・・・", "answers": [ "何にせよ", "なんにせよ" ], "comment": "Rank #267 (191 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to set fire to\n\nHint: 火を・・・", "answers": [ "火を放つ", "ひをはなつ" ], "comment": "Rank #268 (190 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get involved (with); to begin (with); to have a hand (in)\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を染める", "てをそめる" ], "comment": "Rank #269 (190 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be bewitched by a fox; to be confused\n\nHint: 狐に・・・", "answers": [ "狐につままれる", "きつねにつままれる" ], "comment": "Rank #270 (190 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to probe; to search; to sound out; to investigate\n\nHint: 探りを・・・", "answers": [ "探りを入れる", "さぐりをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #271 (190 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to succeed; to bear fruit\n\nHint: 功を・・・", "answers": [ "功を奏する", "こうをそうする" ], "comment": "Rank #271 (190 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be tripped up\nto be too drunk to stand\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を取られる", "あしをとられる" ], "comment": "Rank #272 (187 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to wag one's tail\nto flatter; to butter up\n\nHint: 尻尾を・・・", "answers": [ "尻尾を振る", "しっぽをふる" ], "comment": "Rank #273 (186 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be on track; to be going to plan\nto enter orbit\n\nHint: 軌道に・・・", "answers": [ "軌道に乗る", "きどうにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #274 (186 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be bothered (by something); to suffer\n\nHint: 苦に・・・", "answers": [ "苦になる", "くになる" ], "comment": "Rank #275 (185 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep an eye on; to keep a watchful eye on\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を配る", "めをくばる" ], "comment": "Rank #276 (183 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take the initiative; to forestall; to beat to the punch\n\nHint: 先を・・・", "answers": [ "先を越す", "せんをこす", "さきをこす" ], "comment": "Rank #277 (183 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to interrupt (a story, etc.)\nto bend at the waist\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を折る", "こしをおる" ], "comment": "Rank #278 (183 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stop (plug) one's ears\n\nHint: 耳を・・・", "answers": [ "耳を塞ぐ", "みみをふさぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #280 (182 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not know what to do with; to be at a loss with; to have difficulty with; to be put out\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を焼く", "てをやく" ], "comment": "Rank #281 (181 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to join hands\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を結ぶ", "てをむすぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #282 (178 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to remain in memory (of sounds and words); to linger in one's ears\n\nHint: 耳に・・・", "answers": [ "耳に残る", "みみにのこる" ], "comment": "Rank #283 (178 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "as you see\n\nHint: 見ての・・・", "answers": [ "見ての通り", "みてのとおり" ], "comment": "Rank #284 (177 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to settle down (and deal with something); to concentrate all one's energy (on something)\nto settle oneself (in a place); to settle down (somewhere); to settle in\nto take a solid stance; to lower one's center of gravity (centre)\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を据える", "こしをすえる" ], "comment": "Rank #285 (176 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold back others from achieving success; to stand in the way of; to sabotage\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足を引っ張る", "あしをひっぱる" ], "comment": "Rank #286 (174 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "dazzlingly beautiful; brilliant\n\nHint: 目も・・・", "answers": [ "目もあや", "めもあや" ], "comment": "Rank #287 (174 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be captivated by ...; to be fascinated with ...\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を奪われる", "こころをうばわれる" ], "comment": "Rank #288 (171 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to exceed; to be even more (so); to exaggerate\n\nHint: 輪を・・・", "answers": [ "輪をかける", "わをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #289 (171 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel depressed; to be down\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が滅入る", "きがめいる" ], "comment": "Rank #290 (170 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "generous; soft-hearted; having a good personality\n\nHint: 人が・・・", "answers": [ "人が好い", "ひとがいい" ], "comment": "Rank #291 (168 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pass away; to breathe one's last\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を引き取る", "いきをひきとる" ], "comment": "Rank #292 (167 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be unable to stand; to be weak in the knees; to be paralyzed (e.g. with fear) (paralysed); to be dumbfounded\n\nHint: 腰が・・・", "answers": [ "腰が抜ける", "こしがぬける" ], "comment": "Rank #293 (167 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "None of your business!; Don't bother me!\n\nHint: 大き・・・", "answers": [ "大きなお世話", "おおきなおせわ" ], "comment": "Rank #294 (165 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cross over a pass; to finish the most difficult part; to be over the worst (e.g. an illness)\n\nHint: 峠を・・・", "answers": [ "峠を越す", "とうげをこす" ], "comment": "Rank #295 (165 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "incompetent; have no merit\n\nHint: 能が・・・", "answers": [ "能がない", "のうがない" ], "comment": "Rank #296 (164 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get (e.g. the gist of something); to understand\nto turn out as one thought\n\nHint: 意を・・・", "answers": [ "意を得る", "いをえる" ], "comment": "Rank #297 (164 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a distinction; to differ; to be different\n\nHint: 異に・・・", "answers": [ "異にする", "ことにする" ], "comment": "Rank #298 (163 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look towards\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を遣る", "めをやる" ], "comment": "Rank #299 (163 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to burst into flames\nto fire (of a gun)\nto fan a fire with one's breath\n\nHint: 火を・・・", "answers": [ "火を吹く", "ひをふく" ], "comment": "Rank #300 (163 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "as alike as two melons (two peas in a pod)\n\nHint: 瓜二・・・", "answers": [ "瓜二つ", "うりふたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #301 (162 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise an objection; to voice an opinion different from those of others\n\nHint: 異を・・・", "answers": [ "異を唱える", "いをとなえる" ], "comment": "Rank #302 (161 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a picture; to be perfect for a picture\npicture-perfect; picturesque\n\nHint: 絵に・・・", "answers": [ "絵になる", "えになる" ], "comment": "Rank #303 (161 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to trust; to relax one's guard (around)\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を許す", "こころをゆるす" ], "comment": "Rank #304 (161 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in short; in a nutshell; in a word; to cut a long story short\n\nHint: 早い・・・", "answers": [ "早い話が", "はやいはなしが" ], "comment": "Rank #305 (161 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take notice (of); to pay attention (to)\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を止める", "めをとめる" ], "comment": "Rank #306 (160 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have no way of knowing; to be completely ignorant of\n\nHint: 知る由も・・・", "answers": [ "知る由もない", "しるよしもない" ], "comment": "Rank #307 (160 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to master (e.g. a skill); to become accustomed to (e.g. a lifestyle); to acquire (e.g. a habit)\nto retain\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身に付く", "みにつく" ], "comment": "Rank #308 (160 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put on (of clothing); to put (arms) through sleeves\n\nHint: 袖を・・・", "answers": [ "袖を通す", "そでをとおす" ], "comment": "Rank #309 (159 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a limit; to go too far (e.g. joke)\n\nHint: 程が・・・", "answers": [ "程がある", "ほどがある" ], "comment": "Rank #310 (158 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be beyond one's capacities; to be beyond one's powers; to be beyond one's control; to be unmanageable\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に余る", "てにあまる" ], "comment": "Rank #311 (157 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "small mercy (from some misfortune); silver lining of a dark cloud; consolation in sadness; blessing in disguise\n\nHint: 不幸中の・・・", "answers": [ "不幸中の幸い", "ふこうちゅうのさいわい" ], "comment": "Rank #312 (157 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fall into (someone's) hands; to fall under someone's control; to become someone's property (e.g. of an object)\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に落ちる", "てにおちる" ], "comment": "Rank #313 (157 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be sensible; to be smart; to be tasteful\nto be thoughtful; to be tactful; to be sensitive\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が利く", "きがきく" ], "comment": "Rank #314 (157 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to (keep in) mind; to give heed to; to pay attention to\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に留める", "きにとめる" ], "comment": "Rank #315 (156 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to speak (of something)\nto be effective; to be powerful; to mean everything\n\nHint: 物を・・・", "answers": [ "物を言う", "ものをいう" ], "comment": "Rank #316 (156 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to attract attention\n\nHint: 注意を・・・", "answers": [ "注意を引く", "ちゅういをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #317 (156 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become fraught with emotion\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が熱くなる", "むねがあつくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #318 (155 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to think about; to send one's heart out to; to give more than a passing thought to; to think of something far away; to think nostalgically upon (esp. one's hometown)\n\nHint: 思いを・・・", "answers": [ "思いを馳せる", "おもいをはせる" ], "comment": "Rank #319 (155 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cause trouble; to cause a disturbance\n\nHint: 事を・・・", "answers": [ "事を起こす", "ことをおこす" ], "comment": "Rank #320 (155 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose one's temper; to be exasperated; to become irritated\n\nHint: 業を・・・", "answers": [ "業を煮やす", "ごうをにやす" ], "comment": "Rank #321 (154 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to move; held up; swamped; stuck between a rock and a hard place\n\nHint: 動きが・・・", "answers": [ "動きが取れない", "うごきがとれない" ], "comment": "Rank #322 (154 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold one's breath; to bate one's breath\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を潜める", "いきをひそめる" ], "comment": "Rank #323 (153 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give up; to admit defeat; to throw in the towel\n\nHint: 音を・・・", "answers": [ "音をあげる", "ねをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #324 (151 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to smile broadly; to grin widely\n\nHint: 相好を・・・", "answers": [ "相好を崩す", "そうごうをくずす" ], "comment": "Rank #325 (151 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "no big deal; no match; not worth worrying about\n\nHint: 目じ・・・", "answers": [ "目じゃない", "めじゃない" ], "comment": "Rank #326 (150 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to side with (someone); to support (someone)\n\nHint: 肩を・・・", "answers": [ "肩を持つ", "かたをもつ" ], "comment": "Rank #327 (148 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "losing everything; coming to nothing; having lost the interest and the principal\n\nHint: 元も・・・", "answers": [ "元も子もない", "もともこもない" ], "comment": "Rank #328 (147 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take off one's hat to a person; to acknowledge another's superiority\n\nHint: 一目・・・", "answers": [ "一目置く", "いちもくおく" ], "comment": "Rank #329 (146 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cool down one's anger\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を冷やす", "あたまをひやす" ], "comment": "Rank #330 (146 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be to the point; to be pertinent\n\nHint: 的を・・・", "answers": [ "的を射る", "まとをいる" ], "comment": "Rank #331 (146 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a chill runs down one's spine\n\nHint: 背筋が・・・", "answers": [ "背筋が寒くなる", "せすじがさむくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #332 (145 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be blind to one's shortcomings; to play innocent\n\nHint: 棚に・・・", "answers": [ "棚に上げる", "たなにあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #333 (145 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to let one's guard down\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を許す", "きをゆるす" ], "comment": "Rank #334 (145 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "by all means; by all costs\n\nHint: 何が・・・", "answers": [ "何が何でも", "なにがなんでも" ], "comment": "Rank #335 (144 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be overcome with emotion\n\nHint: 感極・・・", "answers": [ "感極まる", "かんきわまる" ], "comment": "Rank #336 (144 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to kill; to choke the life out of\n\nHint: 息の・・・", "answers": [ "息の根を止める", "いきのねをとめる" ], "comment": "Rank #337 (142 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to try all possible means\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を尽くす", "てをつくす" ], "comment": "Rank #338 (142 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fire oneself up; to give it one's all; to get psyched; to motivate oneself\nto fire someone up (with scolding, corporal punishment, etc.); to rouse\n\nHint: 気合を・・・", "answers": [ "気合を入れる", "きあいをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #339 (141 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to harmonize with; to keep in tune with\nto go along with; to keep in step\n\nHint: 調子を・・・", "answers": [ "調子を合わせる", "ちょうしをあわせる" ], "comment": "Rank #340 (140 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to improve one's skill (esp. at calligraphy or drinking larger amounts of alcohol)\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が上がる", "てがあがる" ], "comment": "Rank #341 (140 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "ill omened (as in \\\"Don't say such an ill omened thing!\\\"); unlucky\n\nHint: 縁起で・・・", "answers": [ "縁起でもない", "えんぎでもない" ], "comment": "Rank #342 (140 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to settle down\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を落ち着ける", "こしをおちつける" ], "comment": "Rank #343 (140 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pick a fight\n\nHint: 喧嘩を・・・", "answers": [ "喧嘩を売る", "けんかをうる" ], "comment": "Rank #344 (139 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to understand from experience\n\nHint: 肌で・・・", "answers": [ "肌で感じる", "はだでかんじる" ], "comment": "Rank #345 (139 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to demand gratitude; to do something for someone in order to create an obligation of gratitude from that person\n\nHint: 恩を・・・", "answers": [ "恩を売る", "おんをうる" ], "comment": "Rank #346 (139 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to incur someone's enmity\n\nHint: 恨みを・・・", "answers": [ "恨みを買う", "うらみをかう" ], "comment": "Rank #347 (138 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to start the debate; to get the ball rolling; to fire the first shot (fig. only); to start a conversation\n\nHint: 口火を・・・", "answers": [ "口火を切る", "くちびをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #348 (138 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to follow in order; to go through step-by-step\n\nHint: 順を・・・", "answers": [ "順を追う", "じゅんをおう" ], "comment": "Rank #349 (138 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to catch one's attention\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に留まる", "めにとまる" ], "comment": "Rank #350 (137 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn inside out; to turn the other way; to turn (something) over\nto look at it from another perspective\nto visit the same prostitute or geisha for a second time\n\nHint: 裏を・・・", "answers": [ "裏を返す", "うらをかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #351 (137 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold a grudge; to hold something against somebody\n\nHint: 根に・・・", "answers": [ "根に持つ", "ねにもつ" ], "comment": "Rank #352 (134 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to worry\n\nHint: 苦に・・・", "answers": [ "苦にする", "くにする" ], "comment": "Rank #353 (134 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to backfire; to produce a result opposite to what was expected or intended\n\nHint: 裏目に・・・", "answers": [ "裏目に出る", "うらめにでる" ], "comment": "Rank #354 (133 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to the core; to the bone; to the marrow\n\nHint: 骨の・・・", "answers": [ "骨の髄まで", "ほねのずいまで" ], "comment": "Rank #355 (133 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get (a joke or explanation); to strike home; to know intuitively\n\nHint: ぴんと・・・", "answers": [ "ぴんと来る", "ぴんとくる" ], "comment": "Rank #356 (133 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "feel uneasy; on tenterhooks; in suspense\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が気でない", "きがきでない" ], "comment": "Rank #357 (132 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to avert one's eyes; to avoid looking straight at something; to cover one's eyes\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を覆う", "めをおおう" ], "comment": "Rank #358 (132 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to behave modestly\n\nHint: 下手に・・・", "answers": [ "下手に出る", "したてにでる" ], "comment": "Rank #359 (132 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be fooled by something; to be taken in\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に乗る", "てにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #360 (132 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "taking a stab at arousing someone's interest\n(of a shrine maiden) presenting water to spirits while invoking them\noffering water before a grave\n\nHint: 水を・・・", "answers": [ "水を向ける", "みずをむける" ], "comment": "Rank #361 (132 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "that's not what you said (before); that's not what was promised\n\nHint: 話が・・・", "answers": [ "話が違う", "はなしがちがう" ], "comment": "Rank #362 (131 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to forgive and forget; to let bygones be bygones; to sweep under the carpet; to wipe the slate clean\n\nHint: 水に・・・", "answers": [ "水に流す", "みずにながす" ], "comment": "Rank #363 (131 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "natural (ability)\n\nHint: 持っ・・・", "answers": [ "持って生まれた", "もってうまれた" ], "comment": "Rank #364 (130 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being dealt a bad hand (in mahjong, card games, etc.)\npoor (handwriting)\nunscrupulous\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が悪い", "てがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #365 (130 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be grieved at heart; to be troubled; to be worried; to trouble oneself (about something)\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を痛める", "こころをいためる" ], "comment": "Rank #366 (129 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to exert oneself; to devote oneself to\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を入れる", "みをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #367 (129 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel oneself indebted to\n\nHint: 恩に・・・", "answers": [ "恩に着る", "おんにきる" ], "comment": "Rank #368 (129 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to confuse someone; to befuddle someone; to create a smokescreen\n\nHint: 煙に・・・", "answers": [ "煙に巻く", "けむにまく" ], "comment": "Rank #369 (128 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to read too much into things; to get wrong ideas by letting one's imagination run wild; to have a groundless suspicion\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を回す", "きをまわす" ], "comment": "Rank #370 (127 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(I) won't (say) anything no matter what (expression is followed by negative verb relating to say, answer, etc.) to not (tell) even under any threat\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口が裂けても", "くちがさけても" ], "comment": "Rank #371 (126 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "stark-naked\n\nHint: 一糸まと・・・", "answers": [ "一糸まとわず", "いっしまとわず", "一糸まとわぬ", "いっしまとわぬ" ], "comment": "Rank #372 (126 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have readied a bow and stand at ready; to watch for an opportunity; to bide one's time; to wait until the time is ripe\n\nHint: 満を・・・", "answers": [ "満を持す", "まんをじす" ], "comment": "Rank #373 (125 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to devote oneself wholeheartedly to; to sacrifice one's health for; to risk one's life\n\nHint: 体を・・・", "answers": [ "体を張る", "からだをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #374 (125 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to laugh (someone) down\n\nHint: 一笑に・・・", "answers": [ "一笑に付す", "いっしょうにふす" ], "comment": "Rank #375 (125 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give one's life; to lay down one's life\n\nHint: 命を・・・", "answers": [ "命を捨てる", "いのちをすてる" ], "comment": "Rank #376 (122 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to puzzle over; to think deeply about; to rack one's brains over (wrack)\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭をひねる", "あたまをひねる" ], "comment": "Rank #377 (122 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to harm one's health\n\nHint: 体を・・・", "answers": [ "体をこわす", "からだをこわす" ], "comment": "Rank #378 (121 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be delirious with fever; to have a feverish dream\nto be crazy about something\n\nHint: 熱に・・・", "answers": [ "熱に浮かされる", "ねつにうかされる" ], "comment": "Rank #379 (120 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bend one's back; to bow; to stoop\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を屈める", "こしをかがめる" ], "comment": "Rank #380 (120 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to draw a bow; to oppose; to defy; to disobey one's superiors\n\nHint: 弓を・・・", "answers": [ "弓を引く", "ゆみをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #381 (120 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make fun of; to look down on; to make light of\nto take a tea break; to rest\n\nHint: 茶に・・・", "answers": [ "茶にする", "ちゃにする" ], "comment": "Rank #382 (120 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be pretentious; to put on airs\n\nHint: 見栄を・・・", "answers": [ "見栄を張る", "みえをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #383 (120 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to finish off; to ensure (something) is dead; to deliver the coup de grace\nto put an end to; to deliver the final blow\nto be the best for A\n\nHint: 止めを・・・", "answers": [ "止めを刺す", "とどめをさす" ], "comment": "Rank #384 (119 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to learn; to acquire knowledge\nto carry; to wear (clothes, etc.); to put on\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身に付ける", "みにつける" ], "comment": "Rank #385 (118 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "cannot do a thing; feeling handcuffed; being at the end of one's tether; being at one's wit's end\n\nHint: 手も・・・", "answers": [ "手も足も出ない", "てもあしもでない" ], "comment": "Rank #386 (118 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a lot on one's shoulders; to bear a lot of responsibility\n\nHint: 荷が・・・", "answers": [ "荷が重い", "にがおもい" ], "comment": "Rank #387 (117 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to speak unanimously; to speak in chorus; to speak in unison; to speak in one voice\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を揃える", "くちをそろえる" ], "comment": "Rank #388 (117 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be scared\n\nHint: 恐れを・・・", "answers": [ "恐れをなす", "おそれをなす" ], "comment": "Rank #389 (117 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give a warning; to remind (a person) of\n\nHint: 釘を・・・", "answers": [ "釘をさす", "くぎをさす" ], "comment": "Rank #390 (117 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "rightly or wrongly; by all possible means\n\nHint: 是が・・・", "answers": [ "是が非でも", "ぜがひでも" ], "comment": "Rank #391 (116 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sit cross-legged\nto rest on one's laurels\n\nHint: 胡坐を・・・", "answers": [ "胡坐をかく", "あぐらをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #392 (116 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become independent\nto leave one's hands; to leave one's possession\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を離れる", "てをはなれる" ], "comment": "Rank #393 (116 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be dizzy; to feel faint; to feel giddy\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が回る", "めがまわる" ], "comment": "Rank #394 (115 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unthinkable; count for nothing; not matter; out of the question\n\nHint: 問題に・・・", "answers": [ "問題にならない", "もんだいにならない" ], "comment": "Rank #395 (115 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to spread one's roots (of a tree, etc.); to take root (of an ideology, etc.)\n\nHint: 根を・・・", "answers": [ "根を張る", "ねをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #396 (115 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be consistent; to be coherent\n\nHint: 辻褄が・・・", "answers": [ "辻褄が合う", "つじつまがあう" ], "comment": "Rank #397 (114 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make one's best effort; to be enthused; to put your back into it\n\nHint: 身が・・・", "answers": [ "身が入る", "みがはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #398 (113 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to attack the enemy in his unguarded moment\n\nHint: 虚を・・・", "answers": [ "虚を衝く", "きょをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #399 (113 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be struck with terror; to be terrified; to be scared to death\n\nHint: 肝を・・・", "answers": [ "肝を冷やす", "きもをひやす" ], "comment": "Rank #400 (112 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be palatable; to suit one's taste\n\nHint: 口に・・・", "answers": [ "口に合う", "くちにあう" ], "comment": "Rank #401 (112 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "awkward; uncomfortable; embarrassing\n\nHint: ばつが・・・", "answers": [ "ばつが悪い", "ばつがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #402 (112 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sink deeply into one's mind; to come home to; to go to one's heart\nto pierce one's body (e.g. of wind, cold, etc.)\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身に沁みる", "みにしみる" ], "comment": "Rank #403 (111 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do in earnest; to concentrate on; to apply one's mind to\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を入れる", "きをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #404 (111 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to resolve; to make up one's mind; to decide\n\nHint: 腹を・・・", "answers": [ "腹を決める", "はらをきめる" ], "comment": "Rank #405 (111 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to dirty one's hands\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を汚す", "てをよごす" ], "comment": "Rank #406 (111 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep in mind; to memorize\n\nHint: 頭に・・・", "answers": [ "頭に入れる", "あたまにいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #407 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be sacked; to be fired; to be dismissed\nto be beheaded\n\nHint: 首に・・・", "answers": [ "首になる", "くびになる" ], "comment": "Rank #408 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become a habit\n\nHint: 癖に・・・", "answers": [ "癖になる", "くせになる" ], "comment": "Rank #409 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to take one's eyes off of something; having to keep a watchful eye on\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が離せない", "めがはなせない" ], "comment": "Rank #410 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take (adopt) measures\n\nHint: 策を・・・", "answers": [ "策を講ずる", "さくをこうずる" ], "comment": "Rank #411 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose one's presence of mind; be flummoxed; to get flustered\n\nHint: 度を・・・", "answers": [ "度を失う", "どをうしなう" ], "comment": "Rank #412 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to originate with; to start with; to stem from\n\nHint: 端を・・・", "answers": [ "端を発する", "たんをはっする" ], "comment": "Rank #413 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be pleased; to gloat; to glow with self-satisfaction\n\nHint: 悦に・・・", "answers": [ "悦に入る", "えつにいる" ], "comment": "Rank #414 (110 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to faint; to swoon; to lose consciousness\nto be astounded; to astonished\nto have a busy time; to be hectic\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を回す", "めをまわす" ], "comment": "Rank #415 (109 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stay in one's heart; to be enduringly memorable; to be unforgettable\n\nHint: 心に・・・", "answers": [ "心に残る", "こころにのこる" ], "comment": "Rank #416 (109 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to worry; to fret; to get anxious\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を揉む", "きをもむ" ], "comment": "Rank #417 (109 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be adrift in the streets; to be out in the cold\n\nHint: 路頭に・・・", "answers": [ "路頭に迷う", "ろとうにまよう" ], "comment": "Rank #418 (108 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be free; to be available\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が空く", "てがあく" ], "comment": "Rank #419 (107 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to win fame; to be widely-known; to be well known; to make a name for oneself\n\nHint: 名を・・・", "answers": [ "名を馳せる", "なをはせる" ], "comment": "Rank #420 (107 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to meddle; to poke one's nose into; to interfere\nto make a pass at; to flirt with; to make a move on\n\nHint: ちょっかいを・・・", "answers": [ "ちょっかいを出す", "ちょっかいをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #421 (106 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel under pressure; to feel impatient; to be in a hurry\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が急く", "きがせく" ], "comment": "Rank #422 (106 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stay up all night; to sit up all night; to do something all night\n\nHint: 夜を・・・", "answers": [ "夜を徹する", "よをてっする" ], "comment": "Rank #423 (106 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to beat someone to the punch; to get the drop on (someone); to forestall\n\nHint: 機先を・・・", "answers": [ "機先を制する", "きせんをせいする" ], "comment": "Rank #424 (106 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "right on the heels of yesterday, then today ...; soon after something, and yet now ...\n\nHint: 昨日の・・・", "answers": [ "昨日の今日", "きのうのきょう" ], "comment": "Rank #425 (105 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "point blank; blunt\n\nHint: 身も・・・", "answers": [ "身も蓋もない", "みもふたもない" ], "comment": "Rank #426 (105 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bear fruit\n\nHint: 実を・・・", "answers": [ "実を結ぶ", "みをむすぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #427 (105 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be touching; to be moving\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を打つ", "むねをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #428 (105 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make the smart move (after taking in the situation, etc.)\nto do the tactful or helpful thing (after considering someone's feelings)\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を利かせる", "きをきかせる" ], "comment": "Rank #429 (103 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to assume a posture; to pose; to make a defiant (proud) gesture\n\nHint: 見得を・・・", "answers": [ "見得を切る", "みえをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #430 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be away from home; to be out of the house\n\nHint: 家を・・・", "answers": [ "家を空ける", "いえをあける" ], "comment": "Rank #431 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be widely known; to be famous\n\nHint: 音に・・・", "answers": [ "音に聞く", "おとにきく" ], "comment": "Rank #432 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be away from home; to be out of the house\n\nHint: 家を・・・", "answers": [ "家を空ける", "うちをあける" ], "comment": "Rank #433 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be bloodthirsty\n\nHint: 血に・・・", "answers": [ "血に飢える", "ちにうえる" ], "comment": "Rank #434 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to spare time (for)\n\nHint: 時間を・・・", "answers": [ "時間を割く", "じかんをさく" ], "comment": "Rank #435 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being painfully-true (e.g. reprimand); making one's ears burn; striking home (e.g. remark)\nhaving an earache; feeling pain in one's ear\n\nHint: 耳が・・・", "answers": [ "耳が痛い", "みみがいたい" ], "comment": "Rank #436 (102 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stand side by side; to stand in a row\n\nHint: 軒を・・・", "answers": [ "軒を連ねる", "のきをつらねる" ], "comment": "Rank #437 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "forming a crowd; ganging up on; joining forces against\n\nHint: 寄っ・・・", "answers": [ "寄ってたかって", "よってたかって" ], "comment": "Rank #438 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to curry favour; to butter up; to fawn over; to humour someone (humor); to put in a good mood (e.g. a baby)\n\nHint: 機嫌を・・・", "answers": [ "機嫌を取る", "きげんをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #439 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go too far; to go to excess; to carry too far\n\nHint: 度が・・・", "answers": [ "度が過ぎる", "どがすぎる" ], "comment": "Rank #440 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a mess of; to sacrifice; to waste\n\nHint: 棒に・・・", "answers": [ "棒に振る", "ぼうにふる" ], "comment": "Rank #441 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose one's cool; to blow one's top; to flip one's lid; to get angry\n\nHint: 頭に・・・", "answers": [ "頭に血がのぼる", "あたまにちがのぼる" ], "comment": "Rank #442 (101 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "There is nothing more that can be done\n\nHint: 万事・・・", "answers": [ "万事休す", "ばんじきゅうす" ], "comment": "Rank #443 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to trip someone up; to pull the carpet from under\n\nHint: 足を・・・", "answers": [ "足をすくう", "あしをすくう" ], "comment": "Rank #444 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "just like that; in the twinkling of an eye; in the blink of an eye; in the time it takes to say \"ah!\"\n\nHint: あっと・・・", "answers": [ "あっと言う間に", "あっというまに" ], "comment": "Rank #445 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do something unexpected\n\nHint: 意表を・・・", "answers": [ "意表を突く", "いひょうをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #446 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be struck by lightning\nto be yelled at (by someone of higher status); to be scolded harshly\n\nHint: 雷が・・・", "answers": [ "雷が落ちる", "かみなりがおちる" ], "comment": "Rank #447 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be taken aback; to be dumbfounded\n\nHint: 毒気を・・・", "answers": [ "毒気を抜かれる", "どっけをぬかれる" ], "comment": "Rank #448 (100 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unfounded (e.g. rumour); groundless; baseless; completely untrue\n\nHint: 根も・・・", "answers": [ "根も葉もない", "ねもはもない" ], "comment": "Rank #449 (98 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "embarrassed; awkward\nunlucky; inopportune\n\nHint: 間が・・・", "answers": [ "間が悪い", "まがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #450 (98 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "narrow gate; obstacle; school (position) hard to enter (get)\n\nHint: 狭き・・・", "answers": [ "狭き門", "せまきもん" ], "comment": "Rank #451 (97 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "long-awaited; eagerly awaited\n\nHint: 待ちに・・・", "answers": [ "待ちに待った", "まちにまった" ], "comment": "Rank #452 (97 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be remembered; to go down in history\n\nHint: 名を・・・", "answers": [ "名を残す", "なをのこす" ], "comment": "Rank #453 (97 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to compete with; not able to make a dent in (e.g. a problem); not able to get a solid hit in (e.g. in a fight)\nhard to chew\n\nHint: 歯が・・・", "answers": [ "歯が立たない", "はがたたない" ], "comment": "Rank #454 (96 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to encourage to do (something); to urge a person on; to demand action\nto spank; to give a spanking; to hit someone on the bottom; to beat someone's backside\n\nHint: 尻を・・・", "answers": [ "尻を叩く", "しりをたたく" ], "comment": "Rank #455 (96 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "sink or swim; high-stakes; desperate\n\nHint: 一か・・・", "answers": [ "一か八か", "いちかばちか" ], "comment": "Rank #456 (95 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "gushing forth; bursting out\n\nHint: 堰を・・・", "answers": [ "堰を切ったよう", "せきをきったよう" ], "comment": "Rank #457 (95 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a good showing\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を吐く", "きをはく" ], "comment": "Rank #458 (95 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to steel oneself to; to brace oneself\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を張る", "きをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #459 (95 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to envision how things will turn out (usu. unfortunate)\nto have foresight; to be able to see the future\n\nHint: 先が・・・", "answers": [ "先が見える", "さきがみえる" ], "comment": "Rank #460 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to enter a New Year\n\nHint: 年を・・・", "answers": [ "年を越す", "としをこす" ], "comment": "Rank #461 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to rack one's brain\n\nHint: 知恵を・・・", "answers": [ "知恵を絞る", "ちえをしぼる" ], "comment": "Rank #462 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unexpected; unforeseen; inconceivable\n\nHint: 思いも・・・", "answers": [ "思いも寄らない", "おもいもよらない" ], "comment": "Rank #463 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pin a crime on\n\nHint: 罪を・・・", "answers": [ "罪を着せる", "つみをきせる" ], "comment": "Rank #464 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to smile with one's whole face\nto squint\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を細くする", "めをほそくする" ], "comment": "Rank #465 (94 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the more one looks (at it) the more...\n\nHint: 見れ・・・", "answers": [ "見れば見るほど", "みればみるほど" ], "comment": "Rank #466 (93 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be deceived\n\nHint: 一杯・・・", "answers": [ "一杯食う", "いっぱいくう" ], "comment": "Rank #467 (93 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "bolt from the blue; great surprise\n\nHint: 寝耳に・・・", "answers": [ "寝耳に水", "ねみみにみず" ], "comment": "Rank #468 (93 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look stupid; to have a critical lack\n\nHint: 間が・・・", "answers": [ "間が抜ける", "まがぬける" ], "comment": "Rank #469 (93 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel refreshed; to feel more cheerful; to feel better\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が晴れる", "きがはれる" ], "comment": "Rank #470 (92 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pour oil on (something); to anoint with oil\nto turn up; to add fuel (e.g. to a dispute); to rev up; to encourage\n\nHint: 油を・・・", "answers": [ "油を注ぐ", "あぶらをそそぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #471 (92 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bring to naught; to bring to nought; to waste\n\nHint: 無に・・・", "answers": [ "無にする", "むにする" ], "comment": "Rank #472 (91 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the end of the line; the end of the road; curtains\n\nHint: 一巻の・・・", "answers": [ "一巻の終り", "いっかんのおわり" ], "comment": "Rank #473 (91 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "liberated woman\n\nHint: 新し・・・", "answers": [ "新しい女", "あたらしいおんな" ], "comment": "Rank #474 (91 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be dizzy; to be disoriented\nto be dazzled\nto be lost in (greed, lust, etc.)\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が眩む", "めがくらむ" ], "comment": "Rank #475 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have the the end in sight; to see the mountains\n\nHint: 山が・・・", "answers": [ "山が見える", "やまがみえる" ], "comment": "Rank #476 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become stiff; to tense\n\nHint: 堅く・・・", "answers": [ "堅くなる", "かたくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #477 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look on enviously while doing nothing\n\nHint: 指を・・・", "answers": [ "指をくわえる", "ゆびをくわえる" ], "comment": "Rank #478 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get carried away; to push one's luck; to push a good thing too far\n\nHint: 図に・・・", "answers": [ "図に乗る", "ずにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #479 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to speak to; to give a (something) talk to; to speak words of (something)\n\nHint: 言葉を・・・", "answers": [ "言葉を掛ける", "ことばをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #480 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get distracted; to jump off the track\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が散る", "きがちる" ], "comment": "Rank #481 (90 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be attentive to small details\nto be attentive to others (or others' concerns)\nto have one's mind turn groundlessly to something negative\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が回る", "きがまわる" ], "comment": "Rank #482 (89 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "incorrigible; dogged\n\nHint: 性懲りも・・・", "answers": [ "性懲りもない", "しょうこりもない" ], "comment": "Rank #483 (89 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to carry in one's pocket; to own\nto take; to carry about\n\nHint: 懐に・・・", "answers": [ "懐にする", "ふところにする" ], "comment": "Rank #484 (89 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a solid stance\nto put one's back in it; to exert oneself\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を入れる", "こしをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #485 (89 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "before or since; neither before nor after; no other time in one's life; stressing a particular moment or event as being unique or most extreme\n\nHint: 後に・・・", "answers": [ "後にも先にも", "あとにもさきにも" ], "comment": "Rank #486 (88 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(a person) to admit defeat; to turn tail (and run)\n(a dog) to tuck one's tail between one's legs\n\nHint: 尻尾を・・・", "answers": [ "尻尾を巻く", "しっぽをまく" ], "comment": "Rank #487 (88 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to apply the art of resuscitation (in judo, etc.)\nto breathe life into; to stimulate; to encourage someone; to give someone a pep talk\n\nHint: 活を・・・", "answers": [ "活を入れる", "かつをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #488 (87 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go with the flow; to go with the times\n\nHint: 波に・・・", "answers": [ "波に乗る", "なみにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #489 (87 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make the sign of the cross; to bless oneself; to cross oneself\n\nHint: 十字を・・・", "answers": [ "十字を切る", "じゅうじをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #490 (87 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(carrying) close to one's person; next to the skin\n\nHint: 肌身・・・", "answers": [ "肌身離さず", "はだみはなさず" ], "comment": "Rank #491 (87 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be flurried; to be confused; to lose one's head\n\nHint: 泡を・・・", "answers": [ "泡を食う", "あわをくう" ], "comment": "Rank #492 (87 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "sick; nauseated\nangry; irritated\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が悪い", "むねがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #493 (86 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to tag along; to follow; to tail; to shadow\nto leave tracks; to leave footprints\n\nHint: 跡を・・・", "answers": [ "跡をつける", "あとをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #494 (86 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to happen to hear; to overhear\n\nHint: 小耳に・・・", "answers": [ "小耳に挟む", "こみみにはさむ" ], "comment": "Rank #495 (86 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become independent\nto leave one's hands; to leave one's possession\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が離れる", "てがはなれる" ], "comment": "Rank #496 (85 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose hope\n\nHint: 目の・・・", "answers": [ "目の前が暗くなる", "めのまえがくらくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #497 (85 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to welter in blood; to be covered in blood\n\nHint: 朱に・・・", "answers": [ "朱に染まる", "あけにそまる" ], "comment": "Rank #498 (84 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be in a tizzy; to be in a frenzy; to have one's eyes light up; to have a different look in one's eyes\n\nHint: 目の・・・", "answers": [ "目の色を変える", "めのいろをかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #499 (84 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "poor hearing\n\nHint: 耳が・・・", "answers": [ "耳が遠い", "みみがとおい" ], "comment": "Rank #500 (84 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(suddenly) quiet\n\nHint: 水を・・・", "answers": [ "水を打ったよう", "みずをうったよう" ], "comment": "Rank #501 (83 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to save face; to show deference; to make someone look good\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔を立てる", "かおをたてる" ], "comment": "Rank #502 (83 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to count on one's fingers\n\nHint: 指折・・・", "answers": [ "指折り数える", "ゆびおりかぞえる" ], "comment": "Rank #503 (83 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feign innocence; to feign ignorance\nto wipe one's mouth\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を拭う", "くちをぬぐう" ], "comment": "Rank #504 (83 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to arrange beforehand to tell the same story; to get the stories straight\n\nHint: 口裏を・・・", "answers": [ "口裏を合わせる", "くちうらをあわせる" ], "comment": "Rank #505 (83 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come to nothing\n\nHint: 水泡に・・・", "answers": [ "水泡に帰す", "すいほうにきす" ], "comment": "Rank #506 (83 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "selfish; asking too much\n\nHint: 虫が・・・", "answers": [ "虫がいい", "むしがいい" ], "comment": "Rank #507 (82 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pour water (into); to dilute with water\nto hinder; to hamper; to throw cold water (on); to put a damper on; to estrange (people)\n\nHint: 水を・・・", "answers": [ "水をさす", "みずをさす" ], "comment": "Rank #508 (82 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not very appealing; pretty disgusting\n\nHint: ぞっと・・・", "answers": [ "ぞっとしない", "ぞっとしない" ], "comment": "Rank #509 (82 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to interfere; to butt in; to interrupt someone\n\nHint: 話の・・・", "answers": [ "話の腰を折る", "はなしのこしをおる" ], "comment": "Rank #510 (82 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to grab attention; to attract notice; to be eye-catching\n\nHint: 人目を・・・", "answers": [ "人目を引く", "ひとめをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #511 (81 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being outnumbered (e.g. in a military context)\n\nHint: 多勢に・・・", "answers": [ "多勢に無勢", "たぜいにぶぜい" ], "comment": "Rank #512 (80 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "very thin voice\n\nHint: 蚊の・・・", "answers": [ "蚊の鳴くような声", "かのなくようなこえ" ], "comment": "Rank #513 (80 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "timid; faint-hearted; wimpish\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が小さい", "きがちいさい" ], "comment": "Rank #514 (79 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to loaf (particularly on the job); to idle one's time away; to dawdle\n\nHint: 油を・・・", "answers": [ "油を売る", "あぶらをうる" ], "comment": "Rank #515 (79 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bring calamity upon oneself; to put your foot in it\n\nHint: 墓穴を・・・", "answers": [ "墓穴を掘る", "ぼけつをほる" ], "comment": "Rank #516 (79 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to resign; to abandon; to step aside; to back out of; to retire; to get away; to lean back; to back away; to pull back\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を退く", "みをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #517 (79 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be in complete attendance\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔を揃える", "かおをそろえる" ], "comment": "Rank #518 (79 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to surpass the rest (e.g. of a large group); to stand out from the crowd; to be the best by far\n\nHint: 群を・・・", "answers": [ "群を抜く", "ぐんをぬく" ], "comment": "Rank #519 (79 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to irritate one; to get on one's nerves\n\nHint: 癇に・・・", "answers": [ "癇に障る", "かんにさわる" ], "comment": "Rank #520 (78 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel guilty; to suffer from a guilty conscience; to feel uneasy; to have qualms about; to have scruples about; to feel regret\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が咎める", "きがとがめる" ], "comment": "Rank #521 (78 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Make assurance double sure\n\nHint: 念に・・・", "answers": [ "念には念を入れよ", "ねんにはねんをいれよ" ], "comment": "Rank #522 (78 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come to an end; to close the curtain\n\nHint: 幕を・・・", "answers": [ "幕を閉じる", "まくをとじる" ], "comment": "Rank #523 (78 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fill in a hole; to plug up a hole; to fill in for a vacancy\n\nHint: 穴を・・・", "answers": [ "穴を埋める", "あなをうめる" ], "comment": "Rank #524 (78 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be no match for (e.g. outclassed in authority, strength or in debt to); to be unable to act on an equal basis with\n\nHint: 頭が・・・", "answers": [ "頭が上がらない", "あたまがあがらない" ], "comment": "Rank #525 (77 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "sarcastic; having a sharp tongue; having a sharp nasty tongue\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口が悪い", "くちがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #526 (77 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to strain every nerve; to feel nervous\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が張る", "きがはる" ], "comment": "Rank #527 (77 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come to a settlement\n\nHint: 埒が・・・", "answers": [ "埒が明く", "らちがあく" ], "comment": "Rank #528 (77 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to irritate; to grate on one's nerves; to aggravate; to be galling; to be invidious\n\nHint: 癪に・・・", "answers": [ "癪に障る", "しゃくにさわる" ], "comment": "Rank #529 (76 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get excited; to be roused (to action); to get the itch (to do)\n\nHint: 血が・・・", "answers": [ "血が騒ぐ", "ちがさわぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #530 (76 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in the end; after all is said and done; at the striped mullet's ultimate maturity (when the striped mullet is fully grown)\n\nHint: とどの・・・", "answers": [ "とどのつまり", "とどのつまり" ], "comment": "Rank #531 (76 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "fickle\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が多い", "きがおおい" ], "comment": "Rank #532 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be of benefit; to be useful; to be good for you\n\nHint: 為に・・・", "answers": [ "為になる", "ためになる" ], "comment": "Rank #533 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get tired of waiting; to grow impatient\n\nHint: 痺れを・・・", "answers": [ "痺れを切らす", "しびれをきらす" ], "comment": "Rank #534 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be moreish; to have a quality that encourages you to eat (drink) more of them after\nto have lingering effects\n\nHint: 後を・・・", "answers": [ "後を引く", "あとをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #535 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to besmirch; to sully\n\nHint: 泥を・・・", "answers": [ "泥を塗る", "どろをぬる" ], "comment": "Rank #536 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pen; to write; to draw\n\nHint: 筆を・・・", "answers": [ "筆を執る", "ふでをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #537 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to set one's hand to; to start work on\nto embezzle; to use (money obtained in illegal fashion)\nto have sexual relations; to have an affair\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を付ける", "てをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #538 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to set about in earnest; to put one's back into something\n\nHint: 本腰を・・・", "answers": [ "本腰を入れる", "ほんごしをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #539 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be sacked; to be dismissed\n\nHint: 首が・・・", "answers": [ "首が飛ぶ", "くびがとぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #540 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "if one is unlucky; if one is careless; if things don't go well\n\nHint: 下手すると・・・", "answers": [ "下手すると", "へたすると" ], "comment": "Rank #541 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be full of pride; to be boastful\n\nHint: 鼻に・・・", "answers": [ "鼻にかける", "はなにかける" ], "comment": "Rank #542 (75 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look toward; to have one's eyes attracted towards something\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が行く", "めがゆく" ], "comment": "Rank #543 (74 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put one's life on the line; to risk one's life; to put everything one has into it\n\nHint: 命を・・・", "answers": [ "命を懸ける", "いのちをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #544 (74 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make good use of one's spare moments\nto weave one's way (e.g. through a crowd)\n\nHint: 合間を・・・", "answers": [ "合間を縫う", "あいまをぬう" ], "comment": "Rank #545 (74 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "somehow unimpressive; plain; mediocre; lackluster; undistinguished\n\nHint: ぱっと・・・", "answers": [ "ぱっとしない", "ぱっとしない" ], "comment": "Rank #546 (74 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take on a role; to take part\n\nHint: 一役・・・", "answers": [ "一役買う", "ひとやくかう" ], "comment": "Rank #547 (73 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to etch into one's mind; to remember well\n\nHint: 心に・・・", "answers": [ "心に刻む", "こころにきざむ" ], "comment": "Rank #548 (73 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fess up; to come clean; to confess one's crimes; to spill the beans\n\nHint: 泥を・・・", "answers": [ "泥を吐く", "どろをはく" ], "comment": "Rank #549 (73 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "one after another; in rapid succession\n\nHint: 後か・・・", "answers": [ "後から後から", "あとからあとから" ], "comment": "Rank #550 (73 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make an apology\n\nHint: 詫びを・・・", "answers": [ "詫びを入れる", "わびをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #551 (72 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take advantage (e.g. of a weak situation); to size up (e.g. customer when setting a high price); from palanquin bearers gauging how weary a traveler's feet are, and raising the price accordingly\n\nHint: 足下を・・・", "answers": [ "足下を見る", "あしもとをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #552 (72 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "having a loose tongue; being talkative; speaking without thinking; being unable to keep a secret\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口が軽い", "くちがかるい" ], "comment": "Rank #553 (72 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be disgusted with; to run out of patience; to fall out of love\n\nHint: 愛想を・・・", "answers": [ "愛想を尽かす", "あいそをつかす" ], "comment": "Rank #554 (72 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to drool; to dribble; to slobber\n\nHint: 涎を・・・", "answers": [ "涎を垂らす", "よだれをたらす" ], "comment": "Rank #555 (72 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be wide-awake; to be wakeful; to be unable to sleep\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が冴える", "めがさえる" ], "comment": "Rank #556 (72 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "proud\nhaving a prominent nose\n\nHint: 鼻が・・・", "answers": [ "鼻が高い", "はながたかい" ], "comment": "Rank #557 (71 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be worth it; to pay\n\nHint: 割に・・・", "answers": [ "割に合う", "わりにあう" ], "comment": "Rank #558 (71 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to show one's true colors (colours); to expose one's faults; to give oneself away\n\nHint: 尻尾を・・・", "answers": [ "尻尾を出す", "しっぽをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #559 (71 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to draw a line between; to clearly differentiate; to distinguish between\n\nHint: 一線を・・・", "answers": [ "一線を画する", "いっせんをかくする" ], "comment": "Rank #560 (71 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make one's own; to take possession of\n\nHint: 手中に・・・", "answers": [ "手中に収める", "しゅちゅうにおさめる" ], "comment": "Rank #561 (71 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "quick-tempered; having little patience; impatient\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が短い", "きがみじかい" ], "comment": "Rank #562 (70 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to know shame; to have a sense of shame; to be ashamed\n\nHint: 恥を・・・", "answers": [ "恥を知る", "はじをしる" ], "comment": "Rank #563 (70 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go to bed; to be sick in bed; to be laid up\n\nHint: 床に・・・", "answers": [ "床に就く", "とこにつく" ], "comment": "Rank #564 (70 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to knock at the gate\nto request an apprenticeship; to ask to be made a pupil\n\nHint: 門を・・・", "answers": [ "門を叩く", "もんをたたく" ], "comment": "Rank #565 (70 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be unwilling but to give in\n\nHint: 百歩・・・", "answers": [ "百歩譲る", "ひゃっぽゆずる" ], "comment": "Rank #566 (69 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to participate in (as a member); to get involved in\n\nHint: 一枚・・・", "answers": [ "一枚噛む", "いちまいかむ" ], "comment": "Rank #567 (69 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be frank; to drop all pretense\n\nHint: 腹を・・・", "answers": [ "腹を割る", "はらをわる" ], "comment": "Rank #568 (69 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel relieved; to feel satisfied; to feel refreshed\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸がすく", "むねがすく" ], "comment": "Rank #569 (69 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being a spectator; observing (out of curiosity) as a disinterested party\n\nHint: 高みの・・・", "answers": [ "高みの見物", "たかみのけんぶつ" ], "comment": "Rank #570 (69 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "at the top of one's voice\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を限りに", "こえをかぎりに" ], "comment": "Rank #571 (69 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "There's no place to stand in\n\nHint: 足の・・・", "answers": [ "足の踏み場もない", "あしのふみばもない" ], "comment": "Rank #572 (68 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take up one's chopsticks (to begin a meal); to start to eat; to eat\n\nHint: 箸を・・・", "answers": [ "箸を取る", "はしをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #573 (68 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to speak sharply (e.g. during a heated discussion or argument)\n\nHint: 啖呵を・・・", "answers": [ "啖呵を切る", "たんかをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #574 (68 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "warming of water (in spring)\n\nHint: 水温・・・", "answers": [ "水温む", "みずぬるむ" ], "comment": "Rank #575 (68 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to see eye to eye; to be on the same wavelength; to talk the same language\n\nHint: 話が・・・", "answers": [ "話が合う", "はなしがあう" ], "comment": "Rank #576 (68 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "from A to Z; without exception; in every particular\n\nHint: 一から十まで・・・", "answers": [ "一から十まで", "いちからじゅうまで" ], "comment": "Rank #577 (67 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to say enough (as much as required); to say plenty\nto say well; to say cleverly; to say elegantly\nto say often; to say frequently\nto say without shame; to say impudently\n\nHint: 良く・・・", "answers": [ "良く言う", "よくいう" ], "comment": "Rank #578 (67 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in the background; not standing out\n\nHint: 影が・・・", "answers": [ "影が薄い", "かげがうすい" ], "comment": "Rank #579 (67 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "short-tempered; quick-tempered; hasty\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が早い", "きがはやい" ], "comment": "Rank #580 (67 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a success in life\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を立てる", "みをたてる" ], "comment": "Rank #581 (67 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to leave one's seat; to temporarily excuse oneself (from a meeting, etc.); to step outside; to be away (from one's desk, etc.)\n\nHint: 席を・・・", "answers": [ "席をはずす", "せきをはずす" ], "comment": "Rank #582 (67 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hesitate; to think twice; to shy or flinch\n\nHint: 二の・・・", "answers": [ "二の足を踏む", "にのあしをふむ" ], "comment": "Rank #583 (66 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take by surprise\n\nHint: 不意を・・・", "answers": [ "不意を衝く", "ふいをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #584 (66 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to proceed in a logical manner; to go through the proper channels\n\nHint: 筋を・・・", "answers": [ "筋を通す", "すじをとおす" ], "comment": "Rank #585 (66 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "accidental resemblance\n\nHint: 他人の・・・", "answers": [ "他人の空似", "たにんのそらに" ], "comment": "Rank #586 (66 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unbecoming; unsuitable; disgraceful; wrong for one's age; unworthy of one's years; thoughtless for one's age\n\nHint: 年甲斐も・・・", "answers": [ "年甲斐もない", "としがいもない" ], "comment": "Rank #587 (65 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to wear a mask\nto hide one's true intentions\n\nHint: 仮面を・・・", "answers": [ "仮面を被る", "かめんをかぶる" ], "comment": "Rank #588 (65 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to burn (with jealousy, desire, etc.)\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を焼く", "みをやく" ], "comment": "Rank #589 (65 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to relax one's efforts; to let up; to let one's guard down\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を緩める", "きをゆるめる" ], "comment": "Rank #590 (64 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stomp out (of a room, etc.); to storm out\n\nHint: 席を・・・", "answers": [ "席を蹴る", "せきをける" ], "comment": "Rank #591 (64 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "godsend; lifesaver; timely offer; windfall\n\nHint: 渡りに・・・", "answers": [ "渡りに船", "わたりにふね" ], "comment": "Rank #592 (64 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sit down; to take a seat\n\nHint: 腰を・・・", "answers": [ "腰を掛ける", "こしをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #593 (64 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to a greater or lesser extent (degree); more or less\n\nHint: 大な・・・", "answers": [ "大なり小なり", "だいなりしょうなり" ], "comment": "Rank #594 (64 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "well connected; well known; having a large, diverse circle of acquaintances\n\nHint: 顔が・・・", "answers": [ "顔が広い", "かおがひろい" ], "comment": "Rank #595 (63 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give your seat to someone; to offer your seat\n\nHint: 席を・・・", "answers": [ "席を譲る", "せきをゆずる" ], "comment": "Rank #596 (63 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take to; to let one's heart go out to\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を寄せる", "こころをよせる" ], "comment": "Rank #597 (63 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be smelly; to stink\n\nHint: 鼻を・・・", "answers": [ "鼻を突く", "はなをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #598 (63 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "well-known only to those in the know; be well-known but to the few; highly regarded by a select few\n\nHint: 知る・・・", "answers": [ "知る人ぞ知る", "しるひとぞしる" ], "comment": "Rank #599 (63 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a pulse; to be alive\nto have a chance; to be not altogether hopeless\n\nHint: 脈が・・・", "answers": [ "脈がある", "みゃくがある" ], "comment": "Rank #600 (63 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to polish one's skills\n\nHint: 腕を・・・", "answers": [ "腕を磨く", "うでをみがく" ], "comment": "Rank #601 (62 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put one's heart into; to devote oneself to\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を入れる", "こころをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #602 (62 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to swing one's arms greatly while walking\nto be brazen\n\nHint: 大手を・・・", "answers": [ "大手を振る", "おおでをふる" ], "comment": "Rank #603 (62 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to perform the last rites over the deceased\nto give someone their final notice (e.g. when firing them); to give someone the final word\n\nHint: 引導を・・・", "answers": [ "引導を渡す", "いんどうをわたす" ], "comment": "Rank #604 (62 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to tread on thin ice; to go out on a limb; to walk a tightrope; to take risks; to cross a dangerous bridge\n\nHint: 危ない橋を・・・", "answers": [ "危ない橋を渡る", "あぶないはしをわたる" ], "comment": "Rank #605 (62 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have an uneasy conscience\n\nHint: 寝覚めが・・・", "answers": [ "寝覚めが悪い", "ねざめがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #606 (61 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "glib; slick (sounds good but no substance); all talk\nin good form; in great shape; having things progress well\n\nHint: 調子が・・・", "answers": [ "調子がいい", "ちょうしがいい" ], "comment": "Rank #607 (61 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be responsive; to show immediate results\n\nHint: 打て・・・", "answers": [ "打てば響く", "うてばひびく" ], "comment": "Rank #608 (61 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be true to nature; to be lifelike\n\nHint: 真に・・・", "answers": [ "真に迫る", "しんにせまる" ], "comment": "Rank #609 (61 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Don't be absurd; That's out of the question; Nonsense; Don't mention it\n\nHint: 滅相も・・・", "answers": [ "滅相もない", "めっそうもない" ], "comment": "Rank #610 (61 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to warm oneself (e.g. at a fire)\n\nHint: 暖を・・・", "answers": [ "暖を取る", "だんをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #611 (61 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to disappear; to vanish\n\nHint: 影を・・・", "answers": [ "影をひそめる", "かげをひそめる" ], "comment": "Rank #612 (61 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not worrying about one's reputation or appearance; not caring what others think\n\nHint: 恥も・・・", "answers": [ "恥も外聞もない", "はじもがいぶんもない" ], "comment": "Rank #613 (61 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to slim down; to lose weight\n\nHint: 肉が・・・", "answers": [ "肉が落ちる", "にくがおちる" ], "comment": "Rank #614 (61 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to plane off the corners\n\nHint: 面を・・・", "answers": [ "面を取る", "めんをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #615 (60 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "out of one's reach; beyond one's grasp\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が出ない", "てがでない" ], "comment": "Rank #616 (60 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bud; to sprout; to germinate\nto have luck on one's side; to get lucky\n\nHint: 芽が・・・", "answers": [ "芽が出る", "めがでる" ], "comment": "Rank #617 (60 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "generous; big-hearted\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が大きい", "きがおおきい" ], "comment": "Rank #618 (60 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a dime a dozen; two a penny\n\nHint: 掃い・・・", "answers": [ "掃いて捨てるほど", "はいてすてるほど" ], "comment": "Rank #619 (60 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "one's legs being leaden (through tiredness, etc.)\n\nHint: 足が・・・", "answers": [ "足が重い", "あしがおもい" ], "comment": "Rank #620 (60 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be discouraged; to be disheartened\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を落とす", "きをおとす" ], "comment": "Rank #621 (60 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be sharp; to be keen; to be on the ball; to have a mind like a steel trap; to be clever\n\nHint: 頭が・・・", "answers": [ "頭が切れる", "あたまがきれる" ], "comment": "Rank #622 (59 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "something not insignificant; not to be sneezed at\n\nHint: 馬鹿に・・・", "answers": [ "馬鹿にならない", "ばかにならない" ], "comment": "Rank #623 (59 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cause a person trouble\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を煩わす", "てをわずらわす" ], "comment": "Rank #624 (59 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take part in\n\nHint: 片棒を・・・", "answers": [ "片棒を担ぐ", "かたぼうをかつぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #625 (59 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to undergo great hardships; to waste away from great effort and worry\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を削る", "みをけずる" ], "comment": "Rank #626 (58 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "cannot suppress one's anger; cannot stomach\n\nHint: 腹に・・・", "answers": [ "腹に据えかねる", "はらにすえかねる" ], "comment": "Rank #627 (58 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to understand each other well; to call forth a response in another's heart; to relate to\n\nHint: 心が・・・", "answers": [ "心が通う", "こころがかよう" ], "comment": "Rank #628 (58 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be beyond words; to defy description\n\nHint: 言語に・・・", "answers": [ "言語に絶する", "げんごにぜっする" ], "comment": "Rank #629 (58 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to invent a pretext for a quarrel; to pick a fight\n\nHint: 因縁を・・・", "answers": [ "因縁をつける", "いんねんをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #630 (58 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have an ulterior motive; to have an axe to grind\n\nHint: 為に・・・", "answers": [ "為にする", "ためにする" ], "comment": "Rank #631 (58 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to encourage someone to expect something; to raise someone's hopes\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を持たす", "きをもたす" ], "comment": "Rank #632 (58 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel uneasy; to worry (about something)\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が差す", "きがさす" ], "comment": "Rank #633 (57 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in all conscience; in honour; in duty bound\n\nHint: 義理に・・・", "answers": [ "義理にも", "ぎりにも" ], "comment": "Rank #634 (57 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give thought to; to bear in mind; to keep in mind\n\nHint: 念頭に・・・", "answers": [ "念頭に置く", "ねんとうにおく" ], "comment": "Rank #635 (57 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "out of luck; (at the) end of one's rope\n\nHint: 運の・・・", "answers": [ "運の尽き", "うんのつき" ], "comment": "Rank #636 (57 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "with one's own body; by one's own action; through one's own experience; firsthand\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を以て", "みをもって" ], "comment": "Rank #637 (57 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have an eye for\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が利く", "めがきく" ], "comment": "Rank #638 (57 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be talented; to be able\n\nHint: 腕が・・・", "answers": [ "腕が立つ", "うでがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #639 (57 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a slip of the tongue; to let something slip\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口が滑る", "くちがすべる" ], "comment": "Rank #640 (56 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "skin and bones\n\nHint: 骨と・・・", "answers": [ "骨と皮", "ほねとかわ" ], "comment": "Rank #641 (56 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in no time; in a flash\n\nHint: 間髪を・・・", "answers": [ "間髪を容れず", "かんはつをいれず" ], "comment": "Rank #642 (56 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "one's future course\n\nHint: 身の・・・", "answers": [ "身の振り方", "みのふりかた" ], "comment": "Rank #643 (56 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be cold (to); to ignore (someone)\n\nHint: 袖に・・・", "answers": [ "袖にする", "そでにする" ], "comment": "Rank #644 (56 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lead someone around by the nose\n\nHint: 手玉に・・・", "answers": [ "手玉に取る", "てだまにとる" ], "comment": "Rank #645 (56 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "lacking skill; uninspiring; unexciting; dull; unrefined; boring (from being too plain)\n\nHint: 芸が・・・", "answers": [ "芸がない", "げいがない" ], "comment": "Rank #646 (56 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to draw closed the curtain (of a theatre, etc.); to come to an end\n\nHint: 幕を・・・", "answers": [ "幕を引く", "まくをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #647 (55 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a lot of influence; to have clout; to be well known\n\nHint: 顔が・・・", "answers": [ "顔が利く", "かおがきく" ], "comment": "Rank #648 (55 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go underground; to go into hiding\n\nHint: 地下に・・・", "answers": [ "地下に潜る", "ちかにもぐる" ], "comment": "Rank #649 (55 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to assume an air of importance; to be self-important; to put on airs\n\nHint: お高くと・・・", "answers": [ "お高くとまる", "おたかくとまる" ], "comment": "Rank #650 (55 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to engage in a bloody feud; to have a family quarrel; to quarrel with one's own flesh and blood; to wash blood for blood\n\nHint: 血で・・・", "answers": [ "血で血を洗う", "ちでちをあらう" ], "comment": "Rank #651 (55 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "incommunicative; taciturn\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口が重い", "くちがおもい" ], "comment": "Rank #652 (55 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unusual\n\nHint: 何時に・・・", "answers": [ "何時にない", "いつにない" ], "comment": "Rank #653 (55 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "tight-lipped; able to keep a secret\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口が堅い", "くちがかたい" ], "comment": "Rank #654 (55 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not revealing (thoughts, feelings); not breathing a word\n\nHint: おくびに・・・", "answers": [ "おくびにも出さない", "おくびにもださない" ], "comment": "Rank #655 (55 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to rack one's brains; to wrack one's brains\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を砕く", "こころをくだく" ], "comment": "Rank #656 (55 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to let pass unnoticed; unable to be indifferent; unable to just watch (without doing anything); can't bear to see; can't stand watching; can't just stand by\n\nHint: 見るに・・・", "answers": [ "見るに見かねる", "みるにみかねる" ], "comment": "Rank #657 (54 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "springlike; like wind blowing through the spring sunshine\n\nHint: 風光・・・", "answers": [ "風光る", "かぜひかる" ], "comment": "Rank #658 (54 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to touch up one's makeup\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔を直す", "かおをなおす" ], "comment": "Rank #659 (54 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "taking a story with a grain of salt; hearing only half the story\n\nHint: 話半・・・", "answers": [ "話半分", "はなしはんぶん" ], "comment": "Rank #660 (54 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to want something desperately; to want something (so badly one can taste it)\n\nHint: 喉から手が・・・", "answers": [ "喉から手が出る", "のどからてがでる" ], "comment": "Rank #661 (53 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to avoid being seen; to be clandestine\n\nHint: 人目を・・・", "answers": [ "人目を忍ぶ", "ひとめをしのぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #662 (53 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "already embarked (and hence cannot go back); already started\n\nHint: 乗り・・・", "answers": [ "乗りかかった船", "のりかかったふね" ], "comment": "Rank #663 (53 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "it hasn't been long since\n\nHint: 日が・・・", "answers": [ "日が浅い", "ひがあさい" ], "comment": "Rank #664 (53 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to worry oneself (about)\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を痛める", "むねをいためる" ], "comment": "Rank #665 (53 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(followed by a negative verb form) not uttering a single word; not giving even the slightest response\n\nHint: うんと・・・", "answers": [ "うんともすんとも", "うんともすんとも" ], "comment": "Rank #666 (53 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to label (someone as)\n\nHint: レッテルを・・・", "answers": [ "レッテルを貼る", "レッテルをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #667 (53 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "each and every one of them; every last one of them; all a bunch of\n\nHint: 揃いも・・・", "answers": [ "揃いも揃って", "そろいもそろって" ], "comment": "Rank #668 (52 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to head towards; to be inclined to go towards; to head for a place naturally\n\nHint: 足が・・・", "answers": [ "足が向く", "あしがむく" ], "comment": "Rank #669 (52 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise one's voice\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を励ます", "こえをはげます" ], "comment": "Rank #670 (52 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fire someone; to discharge someone\nto divorce one's wife\n\nHint: 暇を・・・", "answers": [ "暇を出す", "ひまをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #671 (52 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take someone's pulse\n\nHint: 脈を・・・", "answers": [ "脈を取る", "みゃくをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #672 (52 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to part from; to part company with; to split with; to break off relations with\n\nHint: 袂を・・・", "answers": [ "袂を分かつ", "たもとをわかつ" ], "comment": "Rank #673 (52 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put in a word for; to second; to support\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を添える", "くちをそえる" ], "comment": "Rank #674 (52 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to avenge oneself\n\nHint: 恨みを・・・", "answers": [ "恨みを晴らす", "うらみをはらす" ], "comment": "Rank #675 (51 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to knock or scare (someone) out of his or her wits; to strike a person dumb; to dumbfound; to take (someone) aback\n\nHint: 度胆を・・・", "answers": [ "度胆を抜く", "どぎもをぬく" ], "comment": "Rank #676 (51 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to gulp in astonishment; to be taken aback speechless\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を呑む", "こえをのむ" ], "comment": "Rank #677 (51 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to follow suit; to imitate or follow someone blindly\nto ride on someone's back; to ride someone's coattails; to take advantage (e.g. of another's popularity)\n\nHint: 尻馬に・・・", "answers": [ "尻馬に乗る", "しりうまにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #678 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to add fuel to the fire; to make things worse; to stir things up\n\nHint: 火に・・・", "answers": [ "火に油を注ぐ", "ひにあぶらをそそぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #679 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "having a high threshold; awkward to approach or go to\n\nHint: 敷居が・・・", "answers": [ "敷居が高い", "しきいがたかい" ], "comment": "Rank #680 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be tired of; to be sick of; to get fed up with\n\nHint: 嫌気が・・・", "answers": [ "嫌気が差す", "いやけがさす" ], "comment": "Rank #681 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become the subject of rumours or conversations\n\nHint: 口に・・・", "answers": [ "口にのぼる", "くちにのぼる" ], "comment": "Rank #682 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "sour (expression, as if having swallowed a bitter bug)\n\nHint: 苦虫を・・・", "answers": [ "苦虫を噛みつぶしたよう", "にがむしをかみつぶしたよう" ], "comment": "Rank #683 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be branded a ...; to be labelled a ...\n\nHint: 烙印を・・・", "answers": [ "烙印を押される", "らくいんをおされる" ], "comment": "Rank #684 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be of use (service)\n\nHint: 用に・・・", "answers": [ "用に立つ", "ようにたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #685 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "that's just what I thought; that's exactly like I feel; that's exactly what I think, too\n\nHint: 我が・・・", "answers": [ "我が意を得たり", "わがいをえたり" ], "comment": "Rank #686 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be flowing (of blood); to be alive\nto be humane; to show signs of humanity\n\nHint: 血が・・・", "answers": [ "血が通う", "ちがかよう" ], "comment": "Rank #687 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pretend to not be home; to pretend to be out\n\nHint: 留守を・・・", "answers": [ "留守を使う", "るすをつかう" ], "comment": "Rank #688 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not all bad; not as dissatisfied (or annoyed) as one would have others believe\n\nHint: 満更で・・・", "answers": [ "満更でもない", "まんざらでもない" ], "comment": "Rank #689 (50 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "tit for tat (verbally)\n\nHint: 売り言葉に・・・", "answers": [ "売り言葉に買い言葉", "うりことばにかいことば" ], "comment": "Rank #690 (49 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give up (something as hopeless); to throw in the towel\n\nHint: 匙を・・・", "answers": [ "匙を投げる", "さじをなげる" ], "comment": "Rank #691 (49 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in perfect order\n\nHint: 一糸・・・", "answers": [ "一糸乱れず", "いっしみだれず" ], "comment": "Rank #692 (49 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "one of two (possibilities, alternatives, etc.)\n\nHint: 二つに・・・", "answers": [ "二つに一つ", "ふたつにひとつ" ], "comment": "Rank #693 (49 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a narrow escape from death\n\nHint: 九死に・・・", "answers": [ "九死に一生を得る", "きゅうしにいっしょうをうる", "きゅうしにいっしょうをえる" ], "comment": "Rank #694 (49 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be frank with you; to tell you the truth; I'm going to lay my cards on the table\n\nHint: 何を・・・", "answers": [ "何を隠そう", "なにをかくそう" ], "comment": "Rank #695 (49 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become very angry; to be furious; to fly into a rage\n\nHint: 怒り心頭に・・・", "answers": [ "怒り心頭に発する", "いかりしんとうにはっする" ], "comment": "Rank #696 (49 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cast a shadow; to appear\nto loom (of a threat, etc.); to manifest (of symptoms, etc.)\n\nHint: 影が・・・", "answers": [ "影が差す", "かげがさす" ], "comment": "Rank #697 (49 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be outdone by; to compare unfavorably with\n\nHint: 引けを・・・", "answers": [ "引けを取る", "ひけをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #698 (49 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be forestalled; to fall behind\n\nHint: 後手に・・・", "answers": [ "後手に回る", "ごてにまわる" ], "comment": "Rank #699 (49 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be performed (on the stage)\nto be in the limelight\n\nHint: 脚光を・・・", "answers": [ "脚光を浴びる", "きゃっこうをあびる" ], "comment": "Rank #700 (48 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have one's hair stand on end\n\nHint: 身の・・・", "answers": [ "身の毛がよだつ", "みのけがよだつ" ], "comment": "Rank #701 (48 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be incomparable; to be completely different matters; to be completely different things\n\nHint: 訳が・・・", "answers": [ "訳が違う", "わけがちがう" ], "comment": "Rank #702 (48 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to couch (a sword)\nto look at cynically or ironically\nto stand ready (to do); to adopt a formal attitude\n\nHint: 斜に・・・", "answers": [ "斜に構える", "しゃにかまえる" ], "comment": "Rank #703 (48 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to let slip a secret; to let the cat out of the bag\n\nHint: 語るに・・・", "answers": [ "語るに落ちる", "かたるにおちる" ], "comment": "Rank #704 (48 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw away as useless; to scrap\nto make null and void; to renege; to annul; to revoke\n\nHint: 反故に・・・", "answers": [ "反故にする", "ほごにする" ], "comment": "Rank #705 (47 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "strike while the iron is hot\n\nHint: 善は・・・", "answers": [ "善は急げ", "ぜんはいそげ" ], "comment": "Rank #706 (47 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be settled; to be brought to an end\n\nHint: けりが・・・", "answers": [ "けりがつく", "けりがつく" ], "comment": "Rank #707 (47 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to repeat a mistake (of somebody); to make the same mistake as that of ...; to follow the rut (left by someone else)\n\nHint: 轍を・・・", "answers": [ "轍を踏む", "てつをふむ" ], "comment": "Rank #708 (47 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to dominate (usu. one's husband)\n\nHint: 尻に・・・", "answers": [ "尻に敷く", "しりにしく" ], "comment": "Rank #709 (47 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be oversensitive; to be nervous; to be overly concerned; to worry too much\n\nHint: 神経を・・・", "answers": [ "神経を尖らせる", "しんけいをとがらせる" ], "comment": "Rank #710 (47 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "feeling ashamed\n\nHint: 肩身が・・・", "answers": [ "肩身が狭い", "かたみがせまい" ], "comment": "Rank #711 (47 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not without its worth; not to be undervalued\n\nHint: 捨てたも・・・", "answers": [ "捨てたものではない", "すてたものではない" ], "comment": "Rank #712 (47 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look at the long term\n\nHint: 長い目で・・・", "answers": [ "長い目で見る", "ながいめでみる" ], "comment": "Rank #713 (47 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep an eye on; to take care of\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が届く", "めがとどく" ], "comment": "Rank #714 (47 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to gain experience; to get accustomed (with something)\n\nHint: 場数を・・・", "answers": [ "場数を踏む", "ばかずをふむ" ], "comment": "Rank #715 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to knit one's brows; to frown\n\nHint: 眉を・・・", "answers": [ "眉を曇らす", "まゆをくもらす" ], "comment": "Rank #716 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "at a loss for words; dumbfounded; struck dumb\n\nHint: 二の・・・", "answers": [ "二の句が継げない", "にのくがつげない" ], "comment": "Rank #717 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stay bottled up inside oneself; to be introverted\nto have a melancholic appearance, atmosphere (of a person, object, place); to have a gloomy appearance\n\nHint: 陰に・・・", "answers": [ "陰にこもる", "いんにこもる" ], "comment": "Rank #718 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come to an end; to lower the curtain\n\nHint: 幕を・・・", "answers": [ "幕を下ろす", "まくをおろす" ], "comment": "Rank #719 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to reach a situation about which nothing can be done\n\nHint: 事ここに・・・", "answers": [ "事ここに至る", "ことここにいたる" ], "comment": "Rank #720 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to exceed the budget; to overrun the budget\nto have a secret revealed\n\nHint: 足が・・・", "answers": [ "足が出る", "あしがでる" ], "comment": "Rank #721 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "stubborn; hardheaded\n\nHint: 情が・・・", "answers": [ "情が強い", "じょうがこわい" ], "comment": "Rank #722 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be stunned; to be surprised; one's eyes turn into dots (like a cartoon character)\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が点になる", "めがてんになる" ], "comment": "Rank #723 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "of little importance; trivial; worthless; valueless\n\nHint: 取るに・・・", "answers": [ "取るに足りない", "とるにたりない" ], "comment": "Rank #724 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sympathize deeply with; to strike a chord of sympathy\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身につまされる", "みにつまされる" ], "comment": "Rank #725 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to grumble about something (trivial)\n\nHint: 四の・・・", "answers": [ "四の五の言う", "しのごのいう" ], "comment": "Rank #726 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "sticky (situation); finding oneself trapped\n\nHint: 抜き・・・", "answers": [ "抜き差しならぬ", "ぬきさしならぬ" ], "comment": "Rank #727 (46 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to save one's face; to maintain one's status\n\nHint: 顔が・・・", "answers": [ "顔が立つ", "かおがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #728 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "cold-blooded; unfeeling; heartless; heart of stone; inconsiderate\n\nHint: 血も・・・", "answers": [ "血も涙もない", "ちもなみだもない" ], "comment": "Rank #729 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lock; to fasten a lock\n\nHint: 錠を・・・", "answers": [ "錠をおろす", "じょうをおろす" ], "comment": "Rank #730 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be fast at walking and running\nto be quick to spoil (of foodstuffs)\n\nHint: 足が・・・", "answers": [ "足が早い", "あしがはやい" ], "comment": "Rank #731 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become famous\n\nHint: 名を・・・", "answers": [ "名を取る", "なをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #732 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to wipe the slate clean; to start anew\n\nHint: 白紙に・・・", "answers": [ "白紙に戻す", "はくしにもどす" ], "comment": "Rank #733 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be undeserved; to be more than one deserves\nto be more than one can handle\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身に余る", "みにあまる" ], "comment": "Rank #734 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "heartrending; desperate; hopeless; full of grief\n\nHint: 身も・・・", "answers": [ "身も世もない", "みもよもない" ], "comment": "Rank #735 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give one's life (e.g. in battle); to devote one's life (e.g. to a cause)\n\nHint: 命を・・・", "answers": [ "命を捧げる", "いのちをささげる" ], "comment": "Rank #736 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "too ashamed to meet; having no face to meet\n\nHint: 合わせる顔が・・・", "answers": [ "合わせる顔がない", "あわせるかおがない" ], "comment": "Rank #737 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the end of the world; the world is beyond saving; there's no hope for the future; this degenerate age\n\nHint: 世も・・・", "answers": [ "世も末", "よもすえ" ], "comment": "Rank #738 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to beat time; to mark time\n\nHint: 調子を・・・", "answers": [ "調子を取る", "ちょうしをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #739 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to distinguish oneself; to stand out\n\nHint: 頭角を・・・", "answers": [ "頭角を現す", "とうかくをあらわす" ], "comment": "Rank #740 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be obstinate\n\nHint: 情を・・・", "answers": [ "情を張る", "じょうをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #741 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a hot bath\n\nHint: 湯を・・・", "answers": [ "湯を使う", "ゆをつかう" ], "comment": "Rank #742 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "give-and-take\n\nHint: 持ち・・・", "answers": [ "持ちつ持たれつ", "もちつもたれつ" ], "comment": "Rank #743 (45 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to burn with love\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を焦がす", "みをこがす" ], "comment": "Rank #744 (44 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lay out one's bedding\n\nHint: 床を・・・", "answers": [ "床をとる", "とこをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #745 (44 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fill one's own pocket by taking advantage of a position\n\nHint: 私腹を・・・", "answers": [ "私腹を肥やす", "しふくをこやす" ], "comment": "Rank #746 (44 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be excited; to be elated\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が躍る", "むねがおどる" ], "comment": "Rank #747 (44 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get on well (with a person); to be a good match with one's horse (e.g. of a rider)\n\nHint: 馬が・・・", "answers": [ "馬が合う", "うまがあう" ], "comment": "Rank #748 (44 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to work hard; to make an effort\n\nHint: 精が・・・", "answers": [ "精が出る", "せいがでる" ], "comment": "Rank #749 (44 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be bad for health; to affect one's health\n\nHint: 体に・・・", "answers": [ "体に障る", "からだにさわる" ], "comment": "Rank #750 (44 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "something bound to fail due to inadequate effort, assistance, etc.; pouring water on a hot stone\n\nHint: 焼け石に・・・", "answers": [ "焼け石に水", "やけいしにみず" ], "comment": "Rank #751 (44 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "without noticing; before one realizes; before one is aware of\n\nHint: 思わ・・・", "answers": [ "思わず知らず", "おもわずしらず" ], "comment": "Rank #752 (43 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to prepare oneself for the worst; to strengthen one's resolve; to accept one's fate; to prepare oneself\n\nHint: 腹を・・・", "answers": [ "腹を括る", "はらをくくる" ], "comment": "Rank #753 (43 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be distracted from feelings of depression, boredom, tension, etc.\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が紛れる", "きがまぎれる" ], "comment": "Rank #754 (43 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to trick someone (into confirming or revealing the truth); to ask a leading question\n\nHint: 鎌を・・・", "answers": [ "鎌をかける", "かまをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #755 (43 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bear in mind; to keep remembering; to note\n\nHint: 心に・・・", "answers": [ "心に留める", "こころにとめる" ], "comment": "Rank #756 (43 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "can be easily guessed\n\nHint: 推し・・・", "answers": [ "推して知るべし", "おしてしるべし" ], "comment": "Rank #757 (43 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a seat; to sit\nto occupy a position (e.g. committee president)\n\nHint: 座を・・・", "answers": [ "座を占める", "ざをしめる" ], "comment": "Rank #758 (43 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "having one's back to the wall; having nowhere to go; having no way out; not having another chance\n\nHint: 後が・・・", "answers": [ "後がない", "あとがない" ], "comment": "Rank #759 (43 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to collect evidence\n\nHint: 裏を・・・", "answers": [ "裏を取る", "うらをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #760 (42 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be possessed by an evil spirit; to be tempted; to give in to an urge; to succumb to temptation\n\nHint: 魔が・・・", "answers": [ "魔が差す", "まがさす" ], "comment": "Rank #761 (42 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "fully; thoroughly\n\nHint: 余すと・・・", "answers": [ "余すところなく", "あますところなく" ], "comment": "Rank #762 (42 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hate the very sight of; to hold a grudge against; to treat like an enemy; to bear constant enmity; to be gunning for; to have it in for\n\nHint: 目の・・・", "answers": [ "目の敵にする", "めのかたきにする" ], "comment": "Rank #763 (42 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "lost for words; not knowing what to say by way of excuse (refutation)\n\nHint: ぐうの・・・", "answers": [ "ぐうの音も出ない", "ぐうのねもでない" ], "comment": "Rank #764 (42 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "pearls thrown before swine; unused possession; useless possession; waste of talent\n\nHint: 宝の・・・", "answers": [ "宝の持ち腐れ", "たからのもちぐされ" ], "comment": "Rank #765 (42 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to admire greatly; to salute (in admiration); to take one's hat off to\n\nHint: 頭が・・・", "answers": [ "頭が下がる", "あたまがさがる" ], "comment": "Rank #766 (42 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "uninvited guest\n\nHint: 招か・・・", "answers": [ "招かれざる客", "まねかれざるきゃく" ], "comment": "Rank #767 (41 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to declare impressively\n\nHint: 大見得を・・・", "answers": [ "大見得を切る", "おおみえをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #768 (41 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a showdown; to settle (e.g. a dispute)\n\nHint: 雌雄を・・・", "answers": [ "雌雄を決する", "しゆうをけっする" ], "comment": "Rank #769 (41 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be impolite; to be discourteous\n\nHint: 礼を・・・", "answers": [ "礼を失する", "れいをしっする" ], "comment": "Rank #770 (41 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to quieten down; to fall silent\nto lay low; to keep a low profile\n\nHint: 鳴りを・・・", "answers": [ "鳴りをひそめる", "なりをひそめる" ], "comment": "Rank #771 (41 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw away one's life\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を捨てる", "みをすてる" ], "comment": "Rank #772 (41 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "ending up right back where one started\n\nHint: 元の・・・", "answers": [ "元の木阿弥", "もとのもくあみ" ], "comment": "Rank #773 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cut loose; to act without restraint\n\nHint: 羽目を・・・", "answers": [ "羽目を外す", "はめをはずす" ], "comment": "Rank #774 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to visit less often\n\nHint: 足が・・・", "answers": [ "足が遠のく", "あしがとおのく" ], "comment": "Rank #775 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn over a new leaf; to mend one's ways; to reform\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を入れ替える", "こころをいれかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #776 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to collapse; to give up; to lose one's nerve; to have one's knees give way\n\nHint: 腰が・・・", "answers": [ "腰が砕ける", "こしがくだける" ], "comment": "Rank #777 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to examine one's pulse\n\nHint: 脈を・・・", "answers": [ "脈を見る", "みゃくをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #778 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to survive; to continue living; to escape death\n\nHint: 命を・・・", "answers": [ "命をつなぐ", "いのちをつなぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #779 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "chance; stroke of luck; (curious) turn of events\n\nHint: 風の・・・", "answers": [ "風の吹きまわし", "かぜのふきまわし" ], "comment": "Rank #780 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be overwhelmed; to be overawed\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を呑まれる", "きをのまれる" ], "comment": "Rank #781 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a breath; to pause for a breath; to catch one's breath\n\nHint: 息を・・・", "answers": [ "息を継ぐ", "いきをつぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #782 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "clear as day; perfectly obvious; plain as daylight\n\nHint: 火を・・・", "answers": [ "火を見るよりも明らか", "ひをみるよりもあきらか" ], "comment": "Rank #783 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "far beyond one's power; not at all equal; no match for\n\nHint: 及びも・・・", "answers": [ "及びもつかない", "およびもつかない" ], "comment": "Rank #784 (40 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unthinkable; extraordinary; preposterous; cannot be\n\nHint: 図が・・・", "answers": [ "図がない", "ずがない" ], "comment": "Rank #785 (39 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give one's heart to; to fall in love\nto turn one's mind towards; to think of\n\nHint: 思いを・・・", "answers": [ "思いを寄せる", "おもいをよせる" ], "comment": "Rank #786 (39 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become attached; to begin to love\n\nHint: 情が・・・", "answers": [ "情が移る", "じょうがうつる" ], "comment": "Rank #787 (39 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to play a trick on\n\nHint: 一杯・・・", "answers": [ "一杯食わす", "いっぱいくわす" ], "comment": "Rank #788 (39 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to row a boat\nto nod off; to doze off\n\nHint: 船を・・・", "answers": [ "船を漕ぐ", "ふねをこぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #789 (39 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to scatter in all directions (like baby spiders)\n\nHint: 蜘蛛の・・・", "answers": [ "蜘蛛の子を散らす", "くものこをちらす" ], "comment": "Rank #790 (39 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to not understand what somebody is getting at; to not understand what is being talked about\n\nHint: 話が・・・", "answers": [ "話が見えない", "はなしがみえない" ], "comment": "Rank #791 (39 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to harden one's heart\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を鬼にする", "こころをおににする" ], "comment": "Rank #792 (39 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unfinished dream; unfulfilled dream; impossible dream\n\nHint: 見果・・・", "answers": [ "見果てぬ夢", "みはてぬゆめ" ], "comment": "Rank #793 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take root\n\nHint: 根を・・・", "answers": [ "根を下ろす", "ねをおろす" ], "comment": "Rank #794 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make one's heart flutter; to be excited\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を躍らせる", "むねをおどらせる" ], "comment": "Rank #795 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pile up; to form into a (huge) pile\n\nHint: 山を・・・", "answers": [ "山をなす", "やまをなす" ], "comment": "Rank #796 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "having an expert eye; having a discerning eye\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が高い", "めがたかい" ], "comment": "Rank #797 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "stereotyped; stereotypical; invariable; like clockwork; regular\n\nHint: 判で・・・", "answers": [ "判で押したよう", "はんでおしたよう" ], "comment": "Rank #798 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "before one knows; before one becomes aware of; unnoticed; unawares\n\nHint: 何時の・・・", "answers": [ "何時の間にか", "いつのまにか" ], "comment": "Rank #799 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "shrewd; astute; cunning; alert\n\nHint: 抜け目が・・・", "answers": [ "抜け目がない", "ぬけめがない" ], "comment": "Rank #800 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not at all inferior to; rival or surpass; compare favorably (with)\n\nHint: 勝ると・・・", "answers": [ "勝るとも劣らない", "まさるともおとらない" ], "comment": "Rank #801 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become enthusiastic; to have a crush (on); to lose one's head (to)\n\nHint: 熱を・・・", "answers": [ "熱をあげる", "ねつをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #802 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be superstitious; to believe in omens\n\nHint: 縁起を・・・", "answers": [ "縁起をかつぐ", "えんぎをかつぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #803 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be choked up; to be crushed (emotionally); to be overcome (with emotion); to be shocked; to be horrified\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が潰れる", "むねがつぶれる" ], "comment": "Rank #804 (38 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to emphasize; to state emphatically; to speak loudly about; to raise one's voice; to lift one's voice\n\nHint: 声を・・・", "answers": [ "声を大にする", "こえをだいにする" ], "comment": "Rank #805 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel uneasy; to get into a panic; to feel excited; to have one's heart beat wildly; to have a presentiment\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が騒ぐ", "むねがさわぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #806 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "what I want to say is ...; the fact of the matter is ...\n\nHint: 外で・・・", "answers": [ "外でもない", "ほかでもない" ], "comment": "Rank #807 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to straighten oneself; to straighten one's clothes and one's posture; to adopt a more serious attitude\n\nHint: 襟を・・・", "answers": [ "襟を正す", "えりをただす" ], "comment": "Rank #808 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be out of patience; to be unable to put up with something anymore\n\nHint: 堪忍袋の・・・", "answers": [ "堪忍袋の緒が切れる", "かんにんぶくろのおがきれる" ], "comment": "Rank #809 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be a quick worker\nto be fast in forming relationships with women\nto be quick to resort to violence\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が早い", "てがはやい" ], "comment": "Rank #810 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to wear the mantle of (borrowed) authority and misuse it\n\nHint: 笠に・・・", "answers": [ "笠に着る", "かさにきる" ], "comment": "Rank #811 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sleep like a log; to sleep like a baby\n\nHint: 泥の・・・", "answers": [ "泥のように眠る", "どろのようにねむる" ], "comment": "Rank #812 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "daily; day by day\n\nHint: 日を・・・", "answers": [ "日を追って", "ひをおって" ], "comment": "Rank #813 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "honeymouthed; glib; fair-spoken; cajoling; talking glibly\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口がうまい", "くちがうまい" ], "comment": "Rank #814 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to persevere; to keep at something (regardless of one's fatigue)\n\nHint: 根を・・・", "answers": [ "根を詰める", "こんをつめる" ], "comment": "Rank #815 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take an aggressive position; to stir up trouble\n\nHint: 事を・・・", "answers": [ "事を構える", "ことをかまえる" ], "comment": "Rank #816 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "incompatible; (going together) like oil and water\n\nHint: 水と・・・", "answers": [ "水と油", "みずとあぶら" ], "comment": "Rank #817 (37 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to underrate; to make light of\n\nHint: 高を・・・", "answers": [ "高を括る", "たかをくくる" ], "comment": "Rank #818 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to wave a flag\nto show the way\n\nHint: 旗を・・・", "answers": [ "旗を振る", "はたをふる" ], "comment": "Rank #819 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "one must constantly be on one's guard with ...; one cannot be too careful of ...\n\nHint: 油断も・・・", "answers": [ "油断も隙もない", "ゆだんもすきもない" ], "comment": "Rank #820 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be selected (from among many people)\n\nHint: 白羽の・・・", "answers": [ "白羽の矢が立つ", "しらはのやがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #821 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "take the world by storm; to hold sway over the minds of the people\n\nHint: 一世を・・・", "answers": [ "一世を風靡する", "いっせいをふうびする" ], "comment": "Rank #822 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "empty; meaningless; worthless\n\nHint: 実も・・・", "answers": [ "実もない", "みもない" ], "comment": "Rank #823 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose face; to disgrace oneself\n\nHint: 面目を・・・", "answers": [ "面目を失う", "めんぼくをうしなう" ], "comment": "Rank #824 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put one's heart into; to completely devote oneself to\n\nHint: 心血を・・・", "answers": [ "心血を注ぐ", "しんけつをそそぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #825 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a good thing out of (something)\n\nHint: 甘い汁を・・・", "answers": [ "甘い汁を吸う", "あまいしるをすう" ], "comment": "Rank #826 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to coquet (of a woman); to entice a customer (of a prostitute)\nto flatter; to butter up\n\nHint: 媚を・・・", "answers": [ "媚を売る", "こびをうる" ], "comment": "Rank #827 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise an army\n\nHint: 兵を・・・", "answers": [ "兵を挙げる", "へいをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #828 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "completely; thoroughly; horribly; without exception; until there's no untouched (undamaged) part\n\nHint: 完膚無きまで・・・", "answers": [ "完膚無きまで", "かんぷなきまで" ], "comment": "Rank #829 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to settle (a problem); to put an end to (a dispute); to be disposed of; to be settled; to come to an end\n\nHint: 片が・・・", "answers": [ "片が付く", "かたがつく" ], "comment": "Rank #830 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "this very day; today is the day (that ...); today for sure\n\nHint: 今日と・・・", "answers": [ "今日という今日", "きょうというきょう" ], "comment": "Rank #831 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feign ignorance; to pretend to be ignorant of; to play innocent; to brazen it out\n\nHint: 白を・・・", "answers": [ "白を切る", "しらをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #832 (36 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to descend; to stoop; to degrade oneself; to be reduced to\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を落とす", "みをおとす" ], "comment": "Rank #833 (35 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to understand (reason, motive, etc.)\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が知れない", "きがしれない" ], "comment": "Rank #834 (35 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do for real; to do in real life; to carry (a story) into actual practice\n\nHint: 地で・・・", "answers": [ "地で行く", "じでいく" ], "comment": "Rank #835 (35 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become experienced (after many years of practice)\n\nHint: 年季が・・・", "answers": [ "年季が入る", "ねんきがはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #837 (35 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come into the light of day; to come to light; to become recognized; to surface\n\nHint: 日の・・・", "answers": [ "日の目を見る", "ひのめをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #838 (35 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to draw a line\n\nHint: 棒を・・・", "answers": [ "棒を引く", "ぼうをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #839 (35 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be intricate; to be elaborate; to be complicated; to be complex\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が込む", "てがこむ" ], "comment": "Rank #840 (35 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sting one's eyes; to make one's eyes smart\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に染みる", "めにしみる" ], "comment": "Rank #841 (35 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put one's trust in\n\nHint: 信を・・・", "answers": [ "信を置く", "しんをおく" ], "comment": "Rank #842 (35 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hit a nerve; to get on one's nerves\n\nHint: 神経に・・・", "answers": [ "神経に障る", "しんけいにさわる" ], "comment": "Rank #843 (35 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lead; to direct; to take command\n\nHint: 采配を・・・", "answers": [ "采配を振る", "さいはいをふる" ], "comment": "Rank #844 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look happy; to look pleased\nto make eyes at (someone); to ogle\n\nHint: 目尻を・・・", "answers": [ "目尻を下げる", "めじりをさげる" ], "comment": "Rank #845 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to exercise authority\n\nHint: 威を・・・", "answers": [ "威を振るう", "いをふるう" ], "comment": "Rank #846 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be descended from; to be drawn from (the tradition of); to be derived from; to follow the school (tradition) of\n\nHint: 流れを・・・", "answers": [ "流れを汲む", "ながれをくむ" ], "comment": "Rank #847 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "incomparable\n\nHint: 物に・・・", "answers": [ "物に似ず", "ものににず" ], "comment": "Rank #848 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be uninterested\nindifferent; listless\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が無い", "きがない" ], "comment": "Rank #849 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be excited; to be elated\n\nHint: 心が・・・", "answers": [ "心が弾む", "こころがはずむ" ], "comment": "Rank #850 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be astonished to hear; to be incredulous about; to express disbelief\nwho do you think you're kidding by saying; What a laugh!\n\nHint: 聞い・・・", "answers": [ "聞いて呆れる", "きいてあきれる" ], "comment": "Rank #851 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get more blessing than one deserves\n\nHint: 冥利に・・・", "answers": [ "冥利に尽きる", "みょうりにつきる" ], "comment": "Rank #852 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to strain one's eyes; to stare\n\nHint: 瞳を・・・", "answers": [ "瞳を凝らす", "ひとみをこらす" ], "comment": "Rank #853 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be in a miserable state; to be down and out\n\nHint: 尾羽・・・", "answers": [ "尾羽打ち枯らす", "おはうちからす" ], "comment": "Rank #854 (34 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to work assiduously; to give one's all; to make the utmost effort; to make (grind) one's body into dust\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を粉にする", "みをこにする" ], "comment": "Rank #855 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to swagger about\n\nHint: 肩で・・・", "answers": [ "肩で風を切る", "かたでかぜをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #856 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have glazed eyes (when drunk, angry, etc.); to have glassy eyes\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が据わる", "めがすわる" ], "comment": "Rank #857 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to withdraw from someone's presence; to leave the room\n\nHint: 座を・・・", "answers": [ "座を外す", "ざをはずす" ], "comment": "Rank #858 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "paying for one's mistakes; getting one's just deserts; suffering the consequences (of one's own actions); reap what you sow\n\nHint: 身か・・・", "answers": [ "身から出た錆", "みからでたさび" ], "comment": "Rank #859 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a start\n\nHint: スタートを・・・", "answers": [ "スタートを切る", "スタートをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #860 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to win favour; to win favor\n\nHint: 歓心を・・・", "answers": [ "歓心を買う", "かんしんをかう" ], "comment": "Rank #861 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shame the name (of); to blot the reputation (of)\n\nHint: 名を・・・", "answers": [ "名を汚す", "なをけがす" ], "comment": "Rank #862 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "inseparable (esp. bond, relationship); inextricable; joined at the hip; integral; essential; cannot be broken (cut, separated); indissoluble\n\nHint: 切っても・・・", "answers": [ "切っても切れない", "きってもきれない" ], "comment": "Rank #863 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not able to escape an urgent problem without making some sacrifice\n\nHint: 背に・・・", "answers": [ "背に腹はかえられぬ", "せにはらはかえられぬ", "背に腹はかえられない", "せにはらはかえられない" ], "comment": "Rank #864 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to die; to become earth\n\nHint: 土に・・・", "answers": [ "土になる", "つちになる" ], "comment": "Rank #865 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have one's knees be about to give way\n\nHint: 膝が・・・", "answers": [ "膝が笑う", "ひざがわらう" ], "comment": "Rank #866 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel like an idiot; to make a fool of yourself\n\nHint: 馬鹿を・・・", "answers": [ "馬鹿を見る", "ばかをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #867 (33 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "thickheaded; obstinate; inflexible; stubborn\n\nHint: 頭が・・・", "answers": [ "頭が固い", "あたまがかたい" ], "comment": "Rank #868 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "of no concern at all; no skin off my nose\n\nHint: 痛くも・・・", "answers": [ "痛くも痒くもない", "いたくもかゆくもない" ], "comment": "Rank #869 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to rise in revolt; to raise the standard of revolt\n\nHint: 反旗を・・・", "answers": [ "反旗を翻す", "はんきをひるがえす" ], "comment": "Rank #870 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "taking no notice of; paying no attention to\n\nHint: 歯牙に・・・", "answers": [ "歯牙にもかけない", "しがにもかけない" ], "comment": "Rank #871 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a load off\n\nHint: 荷を・・・", "answers": [ "荷を下ろす", "にをおろす" ], "comment": "Rank #872 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to surge like an avalanche; to flood; to swarm; to stampede\n\nHint: 雪崩を・・・", "answers": [ "雪崩を打つ", "なだれをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #873 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to worsen (of a relationship); to get stormy\n\nHint: 角が・・・", "answers": [ "角が立つ", "かどがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #874 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give birth to\nto have a stomachache\n\nHint: 腹を・・・", "answers": [ "腹を痛める", "はらをいためる" ], "comment": "Rank #875 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to suffer an embarrassing defeat\n\nHint: 不覚を・・・", "answers": [ "不覚を取る", "ふかくをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #876 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get married; to contract a marriage\nto form a connection (with Buddha)\n\nHint: 縁を・・・", "answers": [ "縁を結ぶ", "えんをむすぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #877 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to forebode; to have a presentiment\n\nHint: 虫が・・・", "answers": [ "虫が知らせる", "むしがしらせる" ], "comment": "Rank #878 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "perfectly fitting phrase\n\nHint: 言い・・・", "answers": [ "言い得て妙", "いいえてみょう" ], "comment": "Rank #879 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pocket an insult; to choke back one's tears\n\nHint: 涙を・・・", "answers": [ "涙を呑む", "なみだをのむ" ], "comment": "Rank #880 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a lewd look on one's face; to ogle\n\nHint: 鼻の・・・", "answers": [ "鼻の下を伸ばす", "はなのしたをのばす" ], "comment": "Rank #881 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to issue a manifesto; to appeal\n\nHint: 檄を・・・", "answers": [ "檄を飛ばす", "げきをとばす" ], "comment": "Rank #882 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Ignorance is bliss\n\nHint: 知らぬが・・・", "answers": [ "知らぬが仏", "しらぬがほとけ" ], "comment": "Rank #883 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be engrossed; to be enthralled\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を奪われる", "きをうばわれる" ], "comment": "Rank #884 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be expensive\n\nHint: 値が・・・", "answers": [ "値が張る", "ねがはる" ], "comment": "Rank #885 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make one's way in the world; to earn one's living; to live\n\nHint: 世を・・・", "answers": [ "世を渡る", "よをわたる" ], "comment": "Rank #886 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have guts; to be plucky; to have nerves of steel\n\nHint: 肝が・・・", "answers": [ "肝が据わる", "きもがすわる" ], "comment": "Rank #887 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be intolerable; to be unpardonable\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に余る", "めにあまる" ], "comment": "Rank #888 (32 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be pleased; to be in a good mood\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を良くする", "きをよくする" ], "comment": "Rank #889 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fill in time; to stall (e.g. an audience)\n\nHint: 間を・・・", "answers": [ "間を持たす", "まをもたす" ], "comment": "Rank #890 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "disliking; having an antipathy to\n\nHint: 虫が・・・", "answers": [ "虫が好かない", "むしがすかない" ], "comment": "Rank #891 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to weigh on one's mind; to be worried about (something)\n\nHint: 気に・・・", "answers": [ "気に掛かる", "きにかかる" ], "comment": "Rank #892 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn on the light\n\nHint: 火を・・・", "answers": [ "火を付ける", "ひをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #893 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "everything working out as desired\n\nHint: 願っ・・・", "answers": [ "願ったり叶ったり", "ねがったりかなったり" ], "comment": "Rank #894 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "intimidating; capable of hushing crying children\n\nHint: 泣く子も・・・", "answers": [ "泣く子も黙る", "なくこもだまる" ], "comment": "Rank #895 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to displease someone; to make someone disgusted; to be frowned at\n\nHint: 顰蹙を・・・", "answers": [ "顰蹙を買う", "ひんしゅくをかう" ], "comment": "Rank #896 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to die in (a foreign land); to engage in something until death comes; to do something for the rest of one's life\n\nHint: 骨を・・・", "answers": [ "骨を埋める", "ほねをうずめる" ], "comment": "Rank #897 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to receive permission\nto leave (with someone's permission); to retire\nto refuse; to beg off doing\n\nHint: 御免・・・", "answers": [ "御免蒙る", "ごめんこうむる" ], "comment": "Rank #898 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "perfect; complete; thorough; leaving nothing to be desired; more than satisfactory\n\nHint: 至れ・・・", "answers": [ "至れり尽くせり", "いたれりつくせり" ], "comment": "Rank #899 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be of no importance\n\nHint: 高が・・・", "answers": [ "高が知れる", "たかがしれる" ], "comment": "Rank #900 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to play a trick; to put up a false show; to deceive someone\nto put on a play; to present a play; to give a play\n\nHint: 芝居を・・・", "answers": [ "芝居を打つ", "しばいをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #901 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to leave to chance; to resign oneself to one's fate\n\nHint: 運を・・・", "answers": [ "運を天に任せる", "うんをてんにまかせる" ], "comment": "Rank #902 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stay within bounds; to not get carried to extremes\n\nHint: 大概に・・・", "answers": [ "大概にする", "たいがいにする" ], "comment": "Rank #903 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to achieve enlightenment; to attain enlightenment\n\nHint: 悟りを・・・", "answers": [ "悟りを開く", "さとりをひらく" ], "comment": "Rank #904 (31 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a good appetite\n\nHint: 食が・・・", "answers": [ "食が進む", "しょくがすすむ" ], "comment": "Rank #905 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sit on the edge of one's seat; to be in breathless suspense\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に汗を握る", "てにあせをにぎる" ], "comment": "Rank #906 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "innocent; not guilty; harmless\n\nHint: 罪が・・・", "answers": [ "罪がない", "つみがない" ], "comment": "Rank #907 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stamp one's feet (in frustration, impatience, etc.)\n\nHint: 地団・・・", "answers": [ "地団駄踏む", "じだんだふむ" ], "comment": "Rank #908 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make sense; to be consistent\n\nHint: 筋が・・・", "answers": [ "筋が立つ", "すじがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #909 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to (work, talk, etc.) together smoothly\n\nHint: 息が・・・", "answers": [ "息が合う", "いきがあう" ], "comment": "Rank #910 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "That will do neither harm nor good\n\nHint: 毒に・・・", "answers": [ "毒にも薬にもならない", "どくにもくすりにもならない" ], "comment": "Rank #911 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have the memory of having done something oneself\n\nHint: 身に・・・", "answers": [ "身に覚えがある", "みにおぼえがある" ], "comment": "Rank #912 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "slight superiority (in knowledge, experience, ability, etc.)\n\nHint: 一日の・・・", "answers": [ "一日の長", "いちじつのちょう" ], "comment": "Rank #913 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make contact with somebody; to get in touch with somebody\n\nHint: 渡りを・・・", "answers": [ "渡りをつける", "わたりをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #914 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to collect the ashes of the deceased\nto look after someone's affairs after he dies\n\nHint: 骨を・・・", "answers": [ "骨を拾う", "ほねをひろう" ], "comment": "Rank #915 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to leave the government service\n\nHint: 野に・・・", "answers": [ "野に下る", "やにくだる" ], "comment": "Rank #916 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be in order; to be right\n\nHint: 当を・・・", "answers": [ "当を得る", "とうをえる" ], "comment": "Rank #917 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "setting a bad example to others\n\nHint: 示しが・・・", "answers": [ "示しがつかない", "しめしがつかない" ], "comment": "Rank #918 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sit at ease\n\nHint: 膝を・・・", "answers": [ "膝を崩す", "ひざをくずす" ], "comment": "Rank #919 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel relieved; to feel happy after having been relieved of a responsibility; to be relieved from a duty\n\nHint: 荷が・・・", "answers": [ "荷が下りる", "にがおりる" ], "comment": "Rank #920 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "attentively; with great attention to detail (e.g. when teaching); patiently\n\nHint: 手取・・・", "answers": [ "手取り足取り", "てとりあしとり" ], "comment": "Rank #921 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to plant oneself; to settle in\nto be well-established (e.g. of a religion in a particular area); to have taken root\n\nHint: 根を・・・", "answers": [ "根を生やす", "ねをはやす" ], "comment": "Rank #922 (30 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "fly in the ointment\n\nHint: 玉に・・・", "answers": [ "玉に瑕", "たまにきず" ], "comment": "Rank #923 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "patient; having a long fuse\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が長い", "きがながい" ], "comment": "Rank #924 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to let your hair down; to have fun after a period of work or stress\n\nHint: 羽を・・・", "answers": [ "羽を伸ばす", "はねをのばす" ], "comment": "Rank #925 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the clouds look menacing\nthings don't look good\n\nHint: 雲行きが・・・", "answers": [ "雲行きが怪しい", "くもゆきがあやしい" ], "comment": "Rank #926 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have something on someone; to catch someone out; to trip someone up; to have evidence; to get a lead\nto grab by the tail\n\nHint: 尻尾を・・・", "answers": [ "尻尾を掴む", "しっぽをつかむ" ], "comment": "Rank #927 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pull out nostril hairs\nto outwit; to fool\n\nHint: 鼻毛を・・・", "answers": [ "鼻毛を抜く", "はなげをぬく" ], "comment": "Rank #928 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to steer a ship\nto manage; to take command; to take the helm\n\nHint: 舵を・・・", "answers": [ "舵を取る", "かじをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #929 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to play for time; to use delaying tactics\n\nHint: 時を・・・", "answers": [ "時を稼ぐ", "ときをかせぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #930 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lead a group of people\n\nHint: 音頭を・・・", "answers": [ "音頭を取る", "おんどをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #931 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "at very frequent intervals; almost every other day; constantly\n\nHint: 三日に・・・", "answers": [ "三日にあげず", "みっかにあげず" ], "comment": "Rank #932 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "two blessings at once; flanked by two beautiful women\n\nHint: 両手に・・・", "answers": [ "両手に花", "りょうてにはな" ], "comment": "Rank #933 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "there being no backing out; gone too far to retreat\n\nHint: 引っ込みが・・・", "answers": [ "引っ込みがつかない", "ひっこみがつかない" ], "comment": "Rank #934 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to start an act (of a play); to have curtains open; to have an (event, period of history, etc.) start\n\nHint: 幕が・・・", "answers": [ "幕が開く", "まくがあく" ], "comment": "Rank #935 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be careful in speech\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を慎む", "くちをつつしむ" ], "comment": "Rank #936 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to die; to expire\n\nHint: 空し・・・", "answers": [ "空しくなる", "むなしくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #937 (29 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "fortunate error; lucky break; fluke\n\nHint: 怪我の・・・", "answers": [ "怪我の功名", "けがのこうみょう" ], "comment": "Rank #938 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be conspicuous; to attract public attention\n\nHint: 人目に・・・", "answers": [ "人目に立つ", "ひとめにたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #939 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take the blame\n\nHint: 責めを・・・", "answers": [ "責めを負う", "せめをおう" ], "comment": "Rank #940 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the proof of the pudding is in the eating; evidence is better than debate\n\nHint: 論よ・・・", "answers": [ "論より証拠", "ろんよりしょうこ" ], "comment": "Rank #941 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "that's not a nice thing to say; that's not a nice way of putting it; there was no need to say that\n\nHint: 言うに・・・", "answers": [ "言うに事欠いて", "いうにことかいて" ], "comment": "Rank #942 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to bring disgrace (dishonor, dishonour) on; to fling mud at; to put to shame\n\nHint: 顔に・・・", "answers": [ "顔に泥を塗る", "かおにどろをぬる" ], "comment": "Rank #943 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to break off with (e.g. one's lover)\nto be sharp enough to cut one's skin (of a new banknote, etc.)\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が切れる", "てがきれる" ], "comment": "Rank #944 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "While there's life, there's hope\n\nHint: 命あっての・・・", "answers": [ "命あっての物種", "いのちあってのものだね" ], "comment": "Rank #945 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be extremely embarrassed; to burn with shame\n\nHint: 顔から火が・・・", "answers": [ "顔から火が出る", "かおからひがでる" ], "comment": "Rank #946 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "waking or sleeping; constantly; at all times; twenty-four hours a day\n\nHint: 寝ても・・・", "answers": [ "寝ても覚めても", "ねてもさめても" ], "comment": "Rank #947 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get a salary (from); to receive a stipend (from); to be on the payroll (of)\n\nHint: 禄を・・・", "answers": [ "禄を食む", "ろくをはむ" ], "comment": "Rank #948 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "quite unconcerned; nonchalant\n\nHint: 平気の・・・", "answers": [ "平気の平左", "へいきのへいざ" ], "comment": "Rank #949 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get a lump in one's throat; to overflow with feelings; to be overwhelmed with emotion\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が一杯になる", "むねがいっぱいになる" ], "comment": "Rank #950 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw in a suggestion\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を入れる", "くちをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #951 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to crack down on (e.g. crime, corruption); to deal a crushing blow to; to bring down the hammer on\n\nHint: 鉄槌を・・・", "answers": [ "鉄槌を下す", "てっついをくだす" ], "comment": "Rank #952 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "teaching your grandmother to suck eggs; teaching something to someone who knows more than you; preaching to the choir; lecturing to the Buddha\n\nHint: 釈迦に・・・", "answers": [ "釈迦に説法", "しゃかにせっぽう" ], "comment": "Rank #953 (28 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "imperious; proud\n\nHint: 鼻息が・・・", "answers": [ "鼻息が荒い", "はないきがあらい" ], "comment": "Rank #954 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be too late (to be of use)\n\nHint: 遅きに・・・", "answers": [ "遅きに失する", "おそきにしっする" ], "comment": "Rank #955 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to meet (someone of higher status)\nto be recognized (esp. by someone of higher status); to be visible; to be seen; to be noticed\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に掛かる", "めにかかる" ], "comment": "Rank #956 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go up in smoke; to burn down; to be cremated; to vanish into thin air\n\nHint: 煙に・・・", "answers": [ "煙になる", "けむりになる" ], "comment": "Rank #957 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to screw up one's courage; to take heart\n\nHint: 勇を・・・", "answers": [ "勇を鼓す", "ゆうをこす" ], "comment": "Rank #958 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to ruin oneself\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を持ち崩す", "みをもちくずす" ], "comment": "Rank #959 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(living) from hand to mouth; living on the fringe of subsistance\n\nHint: 食う・・・", "answers": [ "食うや食わず", "くうやくわず" ], "comment": "Rank #960 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be unequal to the burden (job); to be too heavy a load for\n\nHint: 荷が・・・", "answers": [ "荷が勝つ", "にがかつ" ], "comment": "Rank #961 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fold one's arms; to stand and watch (without interfering)\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を拱く", "てをこまぬく" ], "comment": "Rank #962 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to compete ruthlessly; to sharpen swords\n\nHint: 鎬を・・・", "answers": [ "鎬を削る", "しのぎをけずる" ], "comment": "Rank #963 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go up in smoke; to burn down; to be cremated; to vanish into thin air\n\nHint: 煙に・・・", "answers": [ "煙になる", "けむになる" ], "comment": "Rank #964 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to waste time; to kill time\n\nHint: 暇を・・・", "answers": [ "暇を潰す", "ひまをつぶす" ], "comment": "Rank #965 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "it is none of one's business; it is not one's place to say (do) something\n\nHint: 出る幕で・・・", "answers": [ "出る幕ではない", "でるまくではない" ], "comment": "Rank #966 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go mad; to go crazy; to lose one's mind\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が触れる", "きがふれる" ], "comment": "Rank #967 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to rush out from one's mouth (words, phrases, etc.)\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を衝いて出る", "くちをついてでる" ], "comment": "Rank #968 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise (hoist) a flag\nto raise an army\nto start a new business\n\nHint: 旗を・・・", "answers": [ "旗を揚げる", "はたをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #969 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hold a memorial service for the dead, praying for their happiness in the next life by chanting sutras\n\nHint: 菩提を・・・", "answers": [ "菩提を弔う", "ぼだいをとむらう" ], "comment": "Rank #970 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to set somebody to work in an arrogant fashion; to push somebody around; to indicate by pointing one's chin\nto chatter; to jaw; to jabber\n\nHint: 顎で・・・", "answers": [ "顎で使う", "あごでつかう" ], "comment": "Rank #971 (27 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to insist on one's own ideas\n\nHint: 我を・・・", "answers": [ "我を張る", "がをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #972 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give attention\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を配る", "こころをくばる" ], "comment": "Rank #973 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put the scalpel to; to perform an operation on\nto take drastic measures to get to the bottom of something; to make a searching inquiry; to put something under the microscope\n\nHint: メスを・・・", "answers": [ "メスを入れる", "メスをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #974 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to win over; to win (someone's) heart and mind\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を掴む", "こころをつかむ" ], "comment": "Rank #975 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel relieved of one's burden; to have a weight removed from one's mind\n\nHint: 肩の・・・", "answers": [ "肩の荷が下りる", "かたのにがおりる" ], "comment": "Rank #976 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to break the tape (at the finishing line); to breast the tape\n\nHint: テープを・・・", "answers": [ "テープを切る", "テープをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #977 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "apple of one's eye\n\nHint: 掌中の・・・", "answers": [ "掌中の珠", "しょうちゅうのたま" ], "comment": "Rank #978 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be within others' sight; to be visible; to be conspicuous; to attract public attention; to come under observation\n\nHint: 人目に・・・", "answers": [ "人目に付く", "ひとめにつく" ], "comment": "Rank #979 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sleep together (for a man and a woman); to bring one's bodies together (e.g. for warmth)\n\nHint: 肌を・・・", "answers": [ "肌を合わせる", "はだをあわせる" ], "comment": "Rank #980 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "of established reputation\n\nHint: 押しも・・・", "answers": [ "押しも押されもせぬ", "おしもおされもせぬ" ], "comment": "Rank #981 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "arrogant; insolent; overbearing\n\nHint: 人も・・・", "answers": [ "人も無げ", "ひともなげ" ], "comment": "Rank #982 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to work out a compromise\n\nHint: 中を・・・", "answers": [ "中を取る", "なかをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #983 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to demand gratitude; to make a favour of something; to remind of a favour done to someone; to emphasize the favour one has done\n\nHint: 恩に・・・", "answers": [ "恩に着せる", "おんにきせる" ], "comment": "Rank #984 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be highhanded; to be arrogant; to be overbearing\n\nHint: 嵩に・・・", "answers": [ "嵩にかかる", "かさにかかる" ], "comment": "Rank #985 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lose one's composure\n\nHint: 心が・・・", "answers": [ "心が乱れる", "こころがみだれる" ], "comment": "Rank #986 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give an address (before a large number of people); to give a forceful speech\n\nHint: 一席・・・", "answers": [ "一席ぶつ", "いっせきぶつ" ], "comment": "Rank #987 (26 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pay for with your own money\n\nHint: 自腹を・・・", "answers": [ "自腹を切る", "じばらをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #988 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw one's weight around; to exercise one's authority; to make one's presence felt\n\nHint: 幅を・・・", "answers": [ "幅を利かせる", "はばをきかせる" ], "comment": "Rank #989 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take care of; to bring up under one's personal care\nto kill with one's own hands\nto do personally; to handle (e.g. a job)\nto request that someone deal with (something)\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に掛ける", "てにかける" ], "comment": "Rank #990 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be to the point\n\nHint: 要を・・・", "answers": [ "要を得る", "ようをえる" ], "comment": "Rank #991 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be a topic of conversation; to be made much of\nto be taken in\n\nHint: 口に・・・", "answers": [ "口に乗る", "くちにのる" ], "comment": "Rank #992 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be busy; to be tied up doing something\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が塞がる", "てがふさがる" ], "comment": "Rank #993 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get angry; to become perverse\n\nHint: 臍を・・・", "answers": [ "臍を曲げる", "へそをまげる" ], "comment": "Rank #994 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to boast; to brag\n\nHint: 法螺を・・・", "answers": [ "法螺を吹く", "ほらをふく" ], "comment": "Rank #995 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to gain in skill; to improve; to get better\n\nHint: 腕が・・・", "answers": [ "腕が上がる", "うでがあがる" ], "comment": "Rank #996 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to yearn for; to pine for\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を焦がす", "むねをこがす" ], "comment": "Rank #997 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to equivocate; to beat around the bush\n\nHint: 言を・・・", "answers": [ "言を左右にする", "げんをさゆうにする" ], "comment": "Rank #998 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to run out of; to dry up; to be depleted\nto hit the bottom; to bottom out\n\nHint: 底を・・・", "answers": [ "底を突く", "そこをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #999 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a single instance indicates what happens all the time; one case gives you an idea of what always happens\n\nHint: 一事が・・・", "answers": [ "一事が万事", "いちじがばんじ" ], "comment": "Rank #1000 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to build a fortune\n\nHint: 財を・・・", "answers": [ "財を成す", "ざいをなす" ], "comment": "Rank #1001 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to retaliate; to return a blow\n\nHint: 一矢を・・・", "answers": [ "一矢を報いる", "いっしをむくいる" ], "comment": "Rank #1002 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to close down a business; to shut a business\n\nHint: 店を・・・", "answers": [ "店をたたむ", "みせをたたむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1003 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "violent (fight); slashing and striking; hand-to-hand\n\nHint: 切っ・・・", "answers": [ "切った張った", "きったはった" ], "comment": "Rank #1004 (25 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a ceremonial hand movement when receiving the monetary award\n\nHint: 手刀を・・・", "answers": [ "手刀を切る", "てがたなをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #1005 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make advances (to); to woo; to work on someone\n\nHint: モーションを・・・", "answers": [ "モーションをかける", "モーションをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1006 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to gain a reputation; to make oneself famous\n\nHint: 名を・・・", "answers": [ "名を売る", "なをうる" ], "comment": "Rank #1007 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "weird; disgusting\n\nHint: 気色が・・・", "answers": [ "気色が悪い", "きしょくがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #1008 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to understand; to make out\n\nHint: 合点が・・・", "answers": [ "合点が行く", "がてんがゆく" ], "comment": "Rank #1009 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to impress; to charm\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を捉える", "こころをとらえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1010 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fray one's nerves; to wear out one's nerves; to frazzle one's nerves; to be a nervous wreck\n\nHint: 神経を・・・", "answers": [ "神経をすり減らす", "しんけいをすりへらす" ], "comment": "Rank #1011 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be disgusted with; to be fed up with; to run out of patience with\n\nHint: 愛想が・・・", "answers": [ "愛想が尽きる", "あいそがつきる" ], "comment": "Rank #1012 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to remove obstacles in the way of one's objective\n\nHint: 外堀を・・・", "answers": [ "外堀を埋める", "そとぼりをうめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1013 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(it's been) one thing after another\n\nHint: 一難・・・", "answers": [ "一難去ってまた一難", "いちなんさってまたいちなん" ], "comment": "Rank #1014 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be frightened out of one's wits; to be amazed; to be astounded; to be stunned\n\nHint: 肝を・・・", "answers": [ "肝を潰す", "きもをつぶす" ], "comment": "Rank #1015 (24 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to grant a person a moment\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔を貸す", "かおをかす" ], "comment": "Rank #1016 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to run aground; to strike a rock; to be stranded on a reef\nto be deadlocked\n\nHint: 暗礁に・・・", "answers": [ "暗礁に乗り上げる", "あんしょうにのりあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1017 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "anybody (without distinction); every Tom, Dick and Harry; anything\n\nHint: 猫も・・・", "answers": [ "猫も杓子も", "ねこもしゃくしも" ], "comment": "Rank #1018 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put on the brakes; to put a stop to\n\nHint: ブレーキを・・・", "answers": [ "ブレーキを掛ける", "ブレーキをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1019 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cut off the head of a sleeping person; to assassinate someone while he sleeps\nto catch someone off his guard by setting traps\n\nHint: 寝首を・・・", "answers": [ "寝首を掻く", "ねくびをかく" ], "comment": "Rank #1020 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to not make good use of (e.g. advice); to not take into consideration; to treat with disdain\n\nHint: 無下に・・・", "answers": [ "無下にする", "むげにする" ], "comment": "Rank #1021 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Columbus' egg\n\nHint: コロンブスの・・・", "answers": [ "コロンブスの卵", "コロンブスのたまご" ], "comment": "Rank #1022 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be burned to ashes; to come to nothing\n\nHint: 烏有に・・・", "answers": [ "烏有に帰す", "うゆうにきす" ], "comment": "Rank #1023 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cook; to heat\n\nHint: 火を・・・", "answers": [ "火を通す", "ひをとおす" ], "comment": "Rank #1024 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "making a strong person even stronger; as strong as can be; giving a metal rod to an ogre\n\nHint: 鬼に・・・", "answers": [ "鬼に金棒", "おににかなぼう" ], "comment": "Rank #1025 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pass away; to join the majority\n\nHint: 鬼籍に・・・", "answers": [ "鬼籍に入る", "きせきにいる" ], "comment": "Rank #1026 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "humble; modest\n\nHint: 腰が・・・", "answers": [ "腰が低い", "こしがひくい" ], "comment": "Rank #1027 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have one's teeth set on edge\nto get loose teeth\n\nHint: 歯が・・・", "answers": [ "歯が浮く", "はがうく" ], "comment": "Rank #1028 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to use up all of one's energy and willpower; to be exhausted (and have no will to go on)\n\nHint: 精も・・・", "answers": [ "精も根も尽き果てる", "せいもこんもつきはてる" ], "comment": "Rank #1029 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "openly and covertly; implicitly and explicitly\n\nHint: 陰に・・・", "answers": [ "陰に陽に", "いんにように" ], "comment": "Rank #1030 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "of no concern; nothing; trivial\n\nHint: 屁で・・・", "answers": [ "屁でもない", "へでもない" ], "comment": "Rank #1031 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to revel in trouble and discord; to be bent on making trouble; to like starting fights\n\nHint: 事を・・・", "answers": [ "事を好む", "ことをこのむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1032 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to persuade someone to accept the inevitable\n\nHint: 因果を・・・", "answers": [ "因果を含める", "いんがをふくめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1033 (23 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to carry around\nto be roundabout (speech, actions, etc.); to be indirect\n\nHint: 持っ・・・", "answers": [ "持って回る", "もってまわる" ], "comment": "Rank #1034 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to heckle; to jeer\n\nHint: 野次を・・・", "answers": [ "野次を飛ばす", "やじをとばす" ], "comment": "Rank #1035 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make up one's mind\n\nHint: 腹を・・・", "answers": [ "腹を据える", "はらをすえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1036 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "above all else\n\nHint: 一に・・・", "answers": [ "一にも二にも", "いちにもににも" ], "comment": "Rank #1037 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hit the bull's-eye; to go as expected\n\nHint: 図に・・・", "answers": [ "図に当たる", "ずにあたる" ], "comment": "Rank #1038 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be lost in thought\n\nHint: 思案に・・・", "answers": [ "思案に暮れる", "しあんにくれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1039 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to (prepare to) run away (from one's responsibilities, etc.)\n\nHint: 逃げを・・・", "answers": [ "逃げを打つ", "にげをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1040 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to outwit; to get the better of; to overcome a superior opponent and leave him speechless\n\nHint: 鼻を・・・", "answers": [ "鼻を明かす", "はなをあかす" ], "comment": "Rank #1041 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unsung hero; person who does a thankless task\n\nHint: 縁の・・・", "answers": [ "縁の下の力持ち", "えんのしたのちからもち" ], "comment": "Rank #1042 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the New Year begins; the New Year starts\n\nHint: 年が・・・", "answers": [ "年が改まる", "としがあらたまる" ], "comment": "Rank #1043 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "neither good nor bad\n\nHint: 可も・・・", "answers": [ "可もなく不可もなし", "かもなくふかもなし" ], "comment": "Rank #1044 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to speak without hesitation or problems; to speak fluently or skillfully; to be talkative; to have a glib tongue\n\nHint: 舌が・・・", "answers": [ "舌が回る", "したがまわる" ], "comment": "Rank #1045 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "put an end (to); close the books (on)\n\nHint: ピリオドを・・・", "answers": [ "ピリオドを打つ", "ピリオドをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1046 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "of all people\n\nHint: 人も・・・", "answers": [ "人もあろうに", "ひともあろうに" ], "comment": "Rank #1047 (22 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be onto a good thing; to make money without working; to line one's pockets\n\nHint: うまい汁を・・・", "answers": [ "うまい汁を吸う", "うまいしるをすう" ], "comment": "Rank #1048 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "tightly packed; full to capacity\n\nHint: 立錐の・・・", "answers": [ "立錐の余地もない", "りっすいのよちもない" ], "comment": "Rank #1049 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get along well with\n\nHint: 性が・・・", "answers": [ "性が合う", "しょうがあう" ], "comment": "Rank #1050 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to return evil for good\n\nHint: 恩を・・・", "answers": [ "恩を仇で返す", "おんをあだでかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #1051 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to combine parts of two different things into a new thing; to compromise; to balance out\n\nHint: 足して二で・・・", "answers": [ "足して二で割る", "たしてにでわる" ], "comment": "Rank #1052 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel relieved; to forget about one's troubles; to settle into peace of mind\n\nHint: 眉を・・・", "answers": [ "眉を開く", "まゆをひらく" ], "comment": "Rank #1053 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be a point of honor; to affect someone's good name\n\nHint: 沽券に・・・", "answers": [ "沽券に関わる", "こけんにかかわる" ], "comment": "Rank #1054 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "treacherous friend\n\nHint: 獅子身中の・・・", "answers": [ "獅子身中の虫", "しししんちゅうのむし" ], "comment": "Rank #1055 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put on a bold front; to act big; to be unyielding\nto act formally; to act stiffly\n\nHint: 肩肘・・・", "answers": [ "肩肘張る", "かたひじはる" ], "comment": "Rank #1056 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to rake over the coals; to scold; to chastise; to roast\nto burn moxa on the skin\n\nHint: 灸を・・・", "answers": [ "灸を据える", "きゅうをすえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1057 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to loiter (on the way); to waste time\n\nHint: 道草を・・・", "answers": [ "道草を食う", "みちくさをくう" ], "comment": "Rank #1058 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not heeding what others say; in one ear and out the other; reading the nenbutsu into a horse's ear\n\nHint: 馬の・・・", "answers": [ "馬の耳に念仏", "うまのみみにねんぶつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1059 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to mark the end; to spell the end\n\nHint: 終りを・・・", "answers": [ "終りを告げる", "おわりをつげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1060 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel relieved; to feel satisfied\n\nHint: 溜飲が・・・", "answers": [ "溜飲が下がる", "りゅういんがさがる" ], "comment": "Rank #1061 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to rhyme (with)\n\nHint: 韻を・・・", "answers": [ "韻を踏む", "いんをふむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1062 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get a laugh\n\nHint: 笑いを・・・", "answers": [ "笑いを取る", "わらいをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #1063 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to break one's heart\n\nHint: 胸が・・・", "answers": [ "胸が裂ける", "むねがさける" ], "comment": "Rank #1064 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in the face of; in defiance of\n\nHint: 物と・・・", "answers": [ "物ともせず", "ものともせず" ], "comment": "Rank #1065 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make oneself known to the public; to become popular; to gain influence\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔を売る", "かおをうる" ], "comment": "Rank #1066 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "sweetheart; person in one's thoughts (heart)\n\nHint: 意中の・・・", "answers": [ "意中の人", "いちゅうのひと" ], "comment": "Rank #1067 (21 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "calm before a storm; lull before the storm\n\nHint: 嵐の・・・", "answers": [ "嵐の前の静けさ", "あらしのまえのしずけさ" ], "comment": "Rank #1068 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "whether you like it or not; no matter what one may do; in any event; at all events\n\nHint: 泣いても・・・", "answers": [ "泣いても笑っても", "ないてもわらっても" ], "comment": "Rank #1069 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to harbor ill feeling\n\nHint: 含むと・・・", "answers": [ "含むところがある", "ふくむところがある" ], "comment": "Rank #1070 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "impossible proposition; unreasonable proposal; tall order\n\nHint: 出来・・・", "answers": [ "出来ない相談", "できないそうだん" ], "comment": "Rank #1071 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to find fault with someone; to flame someone; to trip up somebody\n\nHint: 揚げ足を・・・", "answers": [ "揚げ足を取る", "あげあしをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #1072 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "innocent-looking; looking as though butter would not melt in the mouth\n\nHint: 虫も・・・", "answers": [ "虫も殺さぬ", "むしもころさぬ", "虫も殺さない", "むしもころさない" ], "comment": "Rank #1073 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to startle; to surprise\n\nHint: あっと・・・", "answers": [ "あっと言わせる", "あっといわせる" ], "comment": "Rank #1074 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "at that very moment; coincidentally\n\nHint: 折も・・・", "answers": [ "折も折", "おりもおり" ], "comment": "Rank #1075 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to retouch; to correct\n\nHint: 朱を・・・", "answers": [ "朱を入れる", "しゅをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1076 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "birds of a feather flock together\n\nHint: 類は友を・・・", "answers": [ "類は友を呼ぶ", "るいはともをよぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #1077 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to come to grapples with\n\nHint: 四つに・・・", "answers": [ "四つに組む", "よつにくむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1078 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "even though one has fallen on hard times; however down on one's luck one may be\n\nHint: 痩せても・・・", "answers": [ "痩せても枯れても", "やせてもかれても" ], "comment": "Rank #1079 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "piling shame on top of shame\n\nHint: 恥の・・・", "answers": [ "恥の上塗り", "はじのうわぬり" ], "comment": "Rank #1080 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become famous; to make a name for oneself\n\nHint: 名を・・・", "answers": [ "名を成す", "なをなす" ], "comment": "Rank #1081 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unable to get along; unable to cooperate; unable to hit it off; not seeing eye to eye\n\nHint: 反りが・・・", "answers": [ "反りが合わない", "そりがあわない" ], "comment": "Rank #1082 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be crazy about; to be infatuated with; to be obsessively devoted to\n\nHint: 血道を・・・", "answers": [ "血道をあげる", "ちみちをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1083 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to betray one's country (to an enemy)\n\nHint: 国を・・・", "answers": [ "国を売る", "くにをうる" ], "comment": "Rank #1084 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "haughty; holding one's head high\n\nHint: 頭が・・・", "answers": [ "頭が高い", "ずがたかい" ], "comment": "Rank #1085 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to nip something in the bud; to nip the buds\n\nHint: 芽を・・・", "answers": [ "芽を摘む", "めをつむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1086 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be profoundly compatible; to be inseparable; to be so close as to reveal to each other the bottom of one's heart\n\nHint: 肝胆・・・", "answers": [ "肝胆相照らす", "かんたんあいてらす" ], "comment": "Rank #1087 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a cross to bear; to carry a heavy burden\n\nHint: 十字架を・・・", "answers": [ "十字架を背負う", "じゅうじかをせおう" ], "comment": "Rank #1088 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "knowing how to swim with the tide; being good at dealing with things\n\nHint: 要領が・・・", "answers": [ "要領がいい", "ようりょうがいい" ], "comment": "Rank #1089 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to try a new venue for eating, drinking, night amusement, etc.\n\nHint: 河岸を・・・", "answers": [ "河岸を変える", "かしをかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1090 (20 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to think of; to give one's thought to\n\nHint: 思いを・・・", "answers": [ "思いを致す", "おもいをいたす" ], "comment": "Rank #1091 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "above all else; more than anything\n\nHint: 何に・・・", "answers": [ "何にも増して", "なににもまして" ], "comment": "Rank #1092 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "extremely fond of; having a weakness for\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が無い", "めがない" ], "comment": "Rank #1093 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a person's blood run cold\n\nHint: 心胆を・・・", "answers": [ "心胆を寒からしめる", "しんたんをさむからしめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1094 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to apologize for a long neglect of friends (apologise)\n\nHint: 久闊を・・・", "answers": [ "久闊を叙する", "きゅうかつをじょする" ], "comment": "Rank #1095 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "every man knows his own business best; one should go to specialists for the best results\n\nHint: 餅は・・・", "answers": [ "餅は餅屋", "もちはもちや" ], "comment": "Rank #1096 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "house built on sand; house of cards\n\nHint: 砂上の・・・", "answers": [ "砂上の楼閣", "さじょうのろうかく" ], "comment": "Rank #1097 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "I can't die and leave things this way\n\nHint: 死んで・・・", "answers": [ "死んでも死にきれない", "しんでもしにきれない" ], "comment": "Rank #1098 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unapproachable\n\nHint: 取り付く島も・・・", "answers": [ "取り付く島もない", "とりつくしまもない" ], "comment": "Rank #1099 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to reminisce; to engage in a lively conversation; to discuss mutual interests\n\nHint: 話に・・・", "answers": [ "話に花が咲く", "はなしにはながさく" ], "comment": "Rank #1100 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to control one's temper\n\nHint: 虫を・・・", "answers": [ "虫を殺す", "むしをころす" ], "comment": "Rank #1101 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "crowded (e.g. with people); overflowing\n\nHint: 押す・・・", "answers": [ "押すな押すな", "おすなおすな" ], "comment": "Rank #1102 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "standing to reason; natural\n\nHint: 理の・・・", "answers": [ "理の当然", "りのとうぜん" ], "comment": "Rank #1103 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fight a battle; to have a fight\n\nHint: 一戦を・・・", "answers": [ "一戦を交える", "いっせんをまじえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1104 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do (someone) a wrong; to do (someone) an ill turn; to take revenge\nto resent; to bear a grudge\n\nHint: 仇を・・・", "answers": [ "仇をなす", "あだをなす" ], "comment": "Rank #1105 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "rushing to one's doom; (like a) moth flying into the flame\n\nHint: 飛んで・・・", "answers": [ "飛んで火に入る夏の虫", "とんでひにいるなつのむし" ], "comment": "Rank #1106 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cater to another's wish; to accommodate; to be agreeable\n\nHint: 意を・・・", "answers": [ "意を迎える", "いをむかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1107 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be tonsured; to have one's head shaved\nto become a monk\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を丸める", "あたまをまるめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1108 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look on with arms folded\n\nHint: 腕を・・・", "answers": [ "腕を拱く", "うでをこまぬく" ], "comment": "Rank #1109 (19 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "use an indirect expression\n\nHint: オブラートに・・・", "answers": [ "オブラートに包む", "オブラートにつつむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1110 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be eloquent; to have a way with words\n\nHint: 弁が・・・", "answers": [ "弁が立つ", "べんがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1111 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "you can get used to living anywhere; home is where you make it; wherever I lay my hat is home\n\nHint: 住め・・・", "answers": [ "住めば都", "すめばみやこ" ], "comment": "Rank #1112 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a veneer off something\n\nHint: 一皮・・・", "answers": [ "一皮剥く", "ひとかわむく" ], "comment": "Rank #1113 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being in a bad mood\n\nHint: 虫の・・・", "answers": [ "虫の居所が悪い", "むしのいどころがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #1114 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cut off a finger (as an act of apology)\nto catch one's finger (in a door, etc.)\n\nHint: 指を・・・", "answers": [ "指を詰める", "ゆびをつめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1115 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be disgusted; to be repulsed; to get the creeps\n\nHint: 虫酸が・・・", "answers": [ "虫酸が走る", "むしずがはしる" ], "comment": "Rank #1116 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "What happens twice will happen thrice\n\nHint: 二度あること・・・", "answers": [ "二度あることは三度ある", "にどあることはさんどある" ], "comment": "Rank #1117 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to boil with rage; to be infuriated\n\nHint: 怒髪天を・・・", "answers": [ "怒髪天を衝く", "どはつてんをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #1118 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "So miserable that it is painful to look at; can't bear to look at; painful to watch\n\nHint: 見るに・・・", "answers": [ "見るに忍びない", "みるにしのびない" ], "comment": "Rank #1119 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep one's wits about one; to be on one's guard; to be wary of trickery\n\nHint: 眉に・・・", "answers": [ "眉に唾をつける", "まゆにつばをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #1120 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be second to none (in)\n\nHint: 人後に・・・", "answers": [ "人後に落ちない", "じんごにおちない" ], "comment": "Rank #1121 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "once upon a time; a long time ago\n\nHint: 今は・・・", "answers": [ "今は昔", "いまはむかし" ], "comment": "Rank #1122 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get moldy; to get mouldy\nto get out-of-fashion\n\nHint: 黴が・・・", "answers": [ "黴が生える", "かびがはえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1123 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a commission; to take a cut; to take a piece of the action; to take a kickback\n\nHint: 上前を・・・", "answers": [ "上前をはねる", "うわまえをはねる" ], "comment": "Rank #1124 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to start (an argument, a battle, etc.)\n\nHint: 火蓋を・・・", "answers": [ "火蓋を切る", "ひぶたをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #1125 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "greatness is comparative; there is always someone better than you\n\nHint: 上に・・・", "answers": [ "上には上がある", "うえにはうえがある" ], "comment": "Rank #1126 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the future is unpredictable; unscrutable are the ways of heaven; the irony of fate\n\nHint: 塞翁が・・・", "answers": [ "塞翁が馬", "さいおうがうま" ], "comment": "Rank #1127 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "it is darkest under the lamp post; it's hard to see what is under your nose; go abroad to hear of home; you must go into the country to hear what news at London\n\nHint: 灯台・・・", "answers": [ "灯台下暗し", "とうだいもとくらし" ], "comment": "Rank #1128 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being quick-eared; having sharp ears; being first to know about something\n\nHint: 耳が・・・", "answers": [ "耳が早い", "みみがはやい" ], "comment": "Rank #1129 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "have an itch to; to have a craving for; to have an urge to; to have a desire for; to be eager to; to want to\n\nHint: 食指が・・・", "answers": [ "食指が動く", "しょくしがうごく" ], "comment": "Rank #1130 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to spurn; to snub; to treat with contempt\n\nHint: 鼻で・・・", "answers": [ "鼻であしらう", "はなであしらう" ], "comment": "Rank #1131 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cry and beg for mercy; to apologize in tears\n\nHint: 泣きを・・・", "answers": [ "泣きを入れる", "なきをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1132 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to retreat; to recede\n\nHint: 後へ・・・", "answers": [ "後へ引く", "あとへひく" ], "comment": "Rank #1133 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to oil (e.g. chains, hinges, etc.)\n\nHint: 油を・・・", "answers": [ "油を差す", "あぶらをさす" ], "comment": "Rank #1134 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Set a thief to catch a thief\n\nHint: 蛇の・・・", "answers": [ "蛇の道は蛇", "じゃのみちはへび" ], "comment": "Rank #1135 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the child is father to the man; the soul of a child of three (is the same) at 100\n\nHint: 三つ子の・・・", "answers": [ "三つ子の魂百まで", "みつごのたましいひゃくまで" ], "comment": "Rank #1136 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "some things are better left unsaid; silence is golden\n\nHint: 言わぬが・・・", "answers": [ "言わぬが花", "いわぬがはな" ], "comment": "Rank #1137 (18 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "third time lucky; third time's the charm\n\nHint: 三度目の・・・", "answers": [ "三度目の正直", "さんどめのしょうじき" ], "comment": "Rank #1138 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to gaze at; to stare at; to set one's eyes on\nto favor; to favour; to be partial to\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を掛ける", "めをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1139 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be suspected without cause\n\nHint: 痛くも・・・", "answers": [ "痛くもない腹を探られる", "いたくもないはらをさぐられる" ], "comment": "Rank #1140 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "extremely busy; so busy one would even welcome the help of a cat\n\nHint: 猫の・・・", "answers": [ "猫の手も借りたい", "ねこのてもかりたい" ], "comment": "Rank #1141 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "courageous but doomed resistance\n\nHint: 蟷螂の・・・", "answers": [ "蟷螂の斧", "とうろうのおの" ], "comment": "Rank #1142 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "delicate or ticklish situation; choice of two evils; mixed blessing\n\nHint: 痛し・・・", "answers": [ "痛し痒し", "いたしかゆし" ], "comment": "Rank #1143 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be itching to put one's skills to use\n\nHint: 腕が・・・", "answers": [ "腕が鳴る", "うでがなる" ], "comment": "Rank #1144 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be well-known; to be famous\n\nHint: 名が・・・", "answers": [ "名が通る", "ながとおる" ], "comment": "Rank #1145 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be eye-popping; to be staggering; to be amazing\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が飛び出る", "めがとびでる" ], "comment": "Rank #1146 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to break up and start anew; to break out of one's shell; to make a fresh start; to go outside oneself\n\nHint: 殻を・・・", "answers": [ "殻を破る", "からをやぶる" ], "comment": "Rank #1147 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to spread money around (e.g. to give, to loan, to invest, etc.)\n\nHint: 金を・・・", "answers": [ "金を回す", "かねをまわす" ], "comment": "Rank #1148 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make somebody lose face; to embarrass someone; to make someone look foolish\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔をつぶす", "かおをつぶす" ], "comment": "Rank #1149 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "open one's eyes wide; with eyes open like saucers\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を皿にする", "めをさらにする" ], "comment": "Rank #1150 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be quick-witted; to be tactful; to be sensible\n\nHint: 目端が・・・", "answers": [ "目端が利く", "めはしがきく" ], "comment": "Rank #1151 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become unrestrained and go to excess; to lose all restraint; to lose one's tension and become relaxed; to let go; to become disorderly; to be scattered; to lose one's self-control\n\nHint: 箍が・・・", "answers": [ "箍が外れる", "たががはずれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1152 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Unpreparedness is one's greatest enemy; He that is too secure is not safe\n\nHint: 油断・・・", "answers": [ "油断大敵", "ゆだんたいてき" ], "comment": "Rank #1153 (17 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "No one knows what the future holds; The future is a closed book\n\nHint: 一寸・・・", "answers": [ "一寸先は闇", "いっすんさきはやみ" ], "comment": "Rank #1154 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be famous; to be celebrated; to be worthy of the name\n\nHint: 名に・・・", "answers": [ "名にし負う", "なにしおう" ], "comment": "Rank #1155 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to start (e.g. a scene, a war, etc.)\nto end (e.g. a play, an episode, an event, etc.)\n\nHint: 幕を・・・", "answers": [ "幕を切る", "まくをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #1156 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw up a smoke screen\n\nHint: 煙幕を・・・", "answers": [ "煙幕を張る", "えんまくをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #1157 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cut with scissors; to put scissors to; to punch (e.g. ticket); to prune (e.g. shrub)\n\nHint: 鋏を・・・", "answers": [ "鋏を入れる", "はさみをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1158 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look daggers at someone; to be angry\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を三角にする", "めをさんかくにする" ], "comment": "Rank #1159 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "bringing up (one's daughter) like a princess\n\nHint: 蝶よ・・・", "answers": [ "蝶よ花よ", "ちょうよはなよ" ], "comment": "Rank #1160 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stand up\nto leave\n\nHint: 尻を・・・", "answers": [ "尻を上げる", "しりをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1161 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to capitulate; to surrender; to submit to; to concede\n\nHint: 軍門に・・・", "answers": [ "軍門に降る", "ぐんもんにくだる" ], "comment": "Rank #1162 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "I don't care what happens (after this)\n\nHint: 野と・・・", "answers": [ "野となれ山となれ", "のとなれやまとなれ" ], "comment": "Rank #1163 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to say something better left unsaid; to go too far (by saying something rude)\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口が過ぎる", "くちがすぎる" ], "comment": "Rank #1164 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get used to one's work; to become accustomed to one's position\nto be at home (on the stage)\n\nHint: 板に・・・", "answers": [ "板に付く", "いたにつく" ], "comment": "Rank #1165 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "useless messenger; doing only as one is told; fool's errand\n\nHint: 子供の・・・", "answers": [ "子供の使い", "こどものつかい" ], "comment": "Rank #1166 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to mark with a dot (point)\n\nHint: 点を・・・", "answers": [ "点を打つ", "てんをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1167 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to raise one's head; to come to the fore; to rise into importance; to gain strength; to rear its head\n\nHint: 頭を・・・", "answers": [ "頭を擡げる", "あたまをもたげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1168 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to catch a weasel asleep; to pluck out the eye of a live horse\n\nHint: 生き馬の・・・", "answers": [ "生き馬の目を抜く", "いきうまのめをぬく" ], "comment": "Rank #1169 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to win the favour of (favor); to be acknowledged (e.g. by a superior); to measure up to\n\nHint: 眼鏡に・・・", "answers": [ "眼鏡にかなう", "めがねにかなう" ], "comment": "Rank #1170 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sharpen one's fangs\n\nHint: 牙を・・・", "answers": [ "牙を研ぐ", "きばをとぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #1171 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get into the swing of (one's work); to hit one's stride\nfish and birds putting on some fat for winter and becoming more tasty as a result\n\nHint: 脂が・・・", "answers": [ "脂が乗る", "あぶらがのる" ], "comment": "Rank #1172 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "no exception; without exception; always the same\n\nHint: 例に・・・", "answers": [ "例に洩れず", "れいにもれず" ], "comment": "Rank #1173 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make sure; to make doubly sure\n\nHint: 駄目を・・・", "answers": [ "駄目を押す", "だめをおす" ], "comment": "Rank #1174 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be on everyone's lips; to be well-known; to be famous\n\nHint: 人口に・・・", "answers": [ "人口に膾炙する", "じんこうにかいしゃする" ], "comment": "Rank #1175 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "just managing; with great difficulty\n\nHint: やっと・・・", "answers": [ "やっとの事で", "やっとのことで" ], "comment": "Rank #1176 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "case that something major happens; event of an emergency; when it comes to the crunch\n\nHint: いざ・・・", "answers": [ "いざ鎌倉", "いざかまくら" ], "comment": "Rank #1177 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to wipe out; to put an end to\n\nHint: 跡を・・・", "answers": [ "跡を絶つ", "あとをたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1178 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to break off writing\n\nHint: 筆を・・・", "answers": [ "筆を折る", "ふでをおる" ], "comment": "Rank #1179 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "cannot contain one's anger\n\nHint: 腹の・・・", "answers": [ "腹の虫がおさまらない", "はらのむしがおさまらない" ], "comment": "Rank #1180 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be pressed for time; to be pressed by urgent business; to have one's pants on fire\n\nHint: 尻に・・・", "answers": [ "尻に火がつく", "しりにひがつく" ], "comment": "Rank #1181 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "from the best to the worst; all sorts of; full range\n\nHint: ピンからキリまで・・・", "answers": [ "ピンからキリまで", "ピンからキリまで" ], "comment": "Rank #1182 (16 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a cornered rat will bite a cat; despair turns cowards courageous\n\nHint: 窮鼠猫を・・・", "answers": [ "窮鼠猫を噛む", "きゅうそねこをかむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1183 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unconditionally (approving); wholeheartedly\n\nHint: 諸手を・・・", "answers": [ "諸手を挙げて", "もろてをあげて" ], "comment": "Rank #1184 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Like father, like son\n\nHint: 血は・・・", "answers": [ "血は争えない", "ちはあらそえない" ], "comment": "Rank #1185 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "so miserable that it is painful to look at; can't bear to look at; painful to watch\n\nHint: 見るに・・・", "answers": [ "見るに堪えない", "みるにたえない" ], "comment": "Rank #1186 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "just now\n\nHint: 今が・・・", "answers": [ "今が今", "いまがいま" ], "comment": "Rank #1187 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a fool of someone\n\nHint: 虚仮に・・・", "answers": [ "虚仮にする", "こけにする" ], "comment": "Rank #1188 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to open up a big lead (over one's opponent)\n\nHint: 水を・・・", "answers": [ "水をあける", "みずをあける" ], "comment": "Rank #1189 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get into trouble; to get busted\n\nHint: 泣きを・・・", "answers": [ "泣きを見る", "なきをみる" ], "comment": "Rank #1190 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hit the bottom; to bottom out\n\nHint: 底を・・・", "answers": [ "底を打つ", "そこをうつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1191 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to decide the outcome (e.g. game)\nto be very different; to be sharply contrasted\n\nHint: 明暗を・・・", "answers": [ "明暗を分ける", "めいあんをわける" ], "comment": "Rank #1192 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to see the light; to be awakened to the truth; to have the scales fall from one's eyes\n\nHint: 目から鱗が・・・", "answers": [ "目から鱗が落ちる", "めからうろこがおちる" ], "comment": "Rank #1193 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to die; to pass away\n\nHint: はか・・・", "answers": [ "はかなくなる", "はかなくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #1194 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "down to earth; reasonable; able to deal with\n\nHint: 話が・・・", "answers": [ "話が分かる", "はなしがわかる" ], "comment": "Rank #1195 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It is no use crying over spilt milk\n\nHint: 後悔先に・・・", "answers": [ "後悔先に立たず", "こうかいさきにたたず" ], "comment": "Rank #1196 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have lived together; to be close friends; to eat out of the same pot\n\nHint: 同じ釜の・・・", "answers": [ "同じ釜の飯を食う", "おなじかまのめしをくう" ], "comment": "Rank #1197 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "People will talk\n\nHint: 人の・・・", "answers": [ "人の口に戸は立てられず", "ひとのくちにとはたてられず" ], "comment": "Rank #1198 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "anybody can look good with the right clothes; clothes make the man; fine feathers make fine birds; clothes on a packhorse driver\n\nHint: 馬子に・・・", "answers": [ "馬子にも衣装", "まごにもいしょう" ], "comment": "Rank #1199 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "while alive (e.g. I won't allow ... while I'm alive); as long as one lives\n\nHint: 目の・・・", "answers": [ "目の黒いうち", "めのくろいうち" ], "comment": "Rank #1200 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sit down\n\nHint: 尻を・・・", "answers": [ "尻を据える", "しりをすえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1201 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in all parts of the world; in all countries; anywhere in the world; both in the Occident and the Orient\n\nHint: 洋の・・・", "answers": [ "洋の東西を問わず", "ようのとうざいをとわず" ], "comment": "Rank #1202 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feign friendliness; to play the hypocrite\n\nHint: 猫を・・・", "answers": [ "猫を被る", "ねこをかぶる" ], "comment": "Rank #1203 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to use abusive language; to curse; to call someone names\n\nHint: 悪態を・・・", "answers": [ "悪態を吐く", "あくたいをつく" ], "comment": "Rank #1204 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "indecent; shameful; unsightly; pathetic\n\nHint: 様は・・・", "answers": [ "様は無い", "ざまはない" ], "comment": "Rank #1205 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "time to pay the piper; time to pay the land tax (in kind)\n\nHint: 年貢の・・・", "answers": [ "年貢の納め時", "ねんぐのおさめどき" ], "comment": "Rank #1206 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to turn one's back (on the enemy)\n\nHint: 後ろを・・・", "answers": [ "後ろを見せる", "うしろをみせる" ], "comment": "Rank #1207 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take care doing something; to be prudent\n\nHint: 大事を・・・", "answers": [ "大事を取る", "だいじをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #1208 (15 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to narrow the focus; to focus attention (on); to concentrate (on); to zero in\n\nHint: 焦点を・・・", "answers": [ "焦点を絞る", "しょうてんをしぼる" ], "comment": "Rank #1209 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take form (shape)\n\nHint: 体を・・・", "answers": [ "体を成す", "たいをなす" ], "comment": "Rank #1210 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to worry; to suffer\n\nHint: 苦に・・・", "answers": [ "苦に病む", "くにやむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1211 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "at once; immediately\n\nHint: 時を・・・", "answers": [ "時を移さず", "ときをうつさず" ], "comment": "Rank #1212 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be put at a disadvantage; to get the short end of the stick\n\nHint: 割を・・・", "answers": [ "割を食う", "わりをくう" ], "comment": "Rank #1213 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to neither itch nor feel pain; to not be affected by something; to not feel the effects of something\n\nHint: 痛痒を・・・", "answers": [ "痛痒を感じない", "つうようをかんじない" ], "comment": "Rank #1214 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "showing no signs of ~~; there being no hint of ~~\nunthinkable\n\nHint: 気も・・・", "answers": [ "気も無い", "けもない" ], "comment": "Rank #1215 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to complain; to lodge a complaint\n\nHint: 文句を・・・", "answers": [ "文句を付ける", "もんくをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #1216 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to acknowledge; to understand; to appreciate\n\nHint: 諒と・・・", "answers": [ "諒とする", "りょうとする" ], "comment": "Rank #1217 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to chew out; to reprimand severely; to rake over the coals; to give a sound scolding; to tell someone off; to scold; to rebuke\nto press oil\n\nHint: 油を・・・", "answers": [ "油を絞る", "あぶらをしぼる" ], "comment": "Rank #1218 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put heads together; to gather (for discussion); to go into a huddle\n\nHint: 額を・・・", "answers": [ "額を集める", "ひたいをあつめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1219 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to grasp at straws; to resort to desperate measures\n\nHint: 藁に・・・", "answers": [ "藁にも縋る", "わらにもすがる" ], "comment": "Rank #1220 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go into the minutest details\n\nHint: 微に・・・", "answers": [ "微に入り細をうがつ", "びにいりさいをうがつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1221 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "clear-cut and straightforward\n(of a person) forward-thinking; honest; upright; frank\n\nHint: 竹を・・・", "answers": [ "竹を割ったよう", "たけをわったよう" ], "comment": "Rank #1222 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pass the baton (e.g. in a relay race)\nto pass the baton; to hand on the torch\n\nHint: バトンを・・・", "answers": [ "バトンを渡す", "バトンをわたす" ], "comment": "Rank #1223 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be troublesome; to require the aid and labour of others\n\nHint: 世話が・・・", "answers": [ "世話が焼ける", "せわがやける" ], "comment": "Rank #1224 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a display of one's originality (eccentricity); to deliberately act oddly (e.g. to get attention)\n\nHint: 奇を・・・", "answers": [ "奇を衒う", "きをてらう" ], "comment": "Rank #1225 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "clear and beautiful (of a woman's voice)\n\nHint: 鈴を・・・", "answers": [ "鈴を転がすよう", "すずをころがすよう" ], "comment": "Rank #1226 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "slow to act; slow in starting work\n\nHint: 腰が・・・", "answers": [ "腰が重い", "こしがおもい" ], "comment": "Rank #1227 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put a damper on proceedings (e.g. at a meeting or party, etc.)\n\nHint: 座が・・・", "answers": [ "座が白ける", "ざがしらける" ], "comment": "Rank #1228 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be faithful; to do one's duty\n\nHint: 義理を・・・", "answers": [ "義理を立てる", "ぎりをたてる" ], "comment": "Rank #1229 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go over the hump; to get successfully through the bulk of the work\n\nHint: 一山・・・", "answers": [ "一山越す", "ひとやまこす" ], "comment": "Rank #1230 (14 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have secret communication with; to have a tacit understanding with\n\nHint: 気脈を・・・", "answers": [ "気脈を通ずる", "きみゃくをつうずる", "気脈を通じる", "きみゃくをつうじる" ], "comment": "Rank #1231 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to complete one's journey\n\nHint: 草鞋を・・・", "answers": [ "草鞋を脱ぐ", "わらじをぬぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #1232 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw in the towel\n\nHint: タオルを・・・", "answers": [ "タオルを投げる", "タオルをなげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1233 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "calmly; composedly\n\nHint: 悠揚・・・", "answers": [ "悠揚迫らず", "ゆうようせまらず" ], "comment": "Rank #1234 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a mess of it; to make a hash of it; to fail and lose face; to embarrass oneself\nto spread miso (e.g. on konnyaku)\n\nHint: 味噌を・・・", "answers": [ "味噌をつける", "みそをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #1235 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go to the bottom of an affair; to inquire into the origin\n\nHint: 元を・・・", "answers": [ "元を正す", "もとをただす" ], "comment": "Rank #1236 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "having no choice but to carry on; having no choice but to go on; unable to change one's course of action; a man riding a tiger cannot disembark halfway through\n\nHint: 騎虎の・・・", "answers": [ "騎虎の勢い", "きこのいきおい" ], "comment": "Rank #1237 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "good manners even between friends; a hedge between keeps friendships\n\nHint: 親しき仲に・・・", "answers": [ "親しき仲にも礼儀あり", "したしきなかにもれいぎあり" ], "comment": "Rank #1238 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take charge during someone's absence\n\nHint: 留守を・・・", "answers": [ "留守を預かる", "るすをあずかる" ], "comment": "Rank #1239 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to look coldly at; to turn a cold shoulder\n\nHint: 白い眼で・・・", "answers": [ "白い眼で見る", "しろいめでみる" ], "comment": "Rank #1240 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "All things come to those who wait\n\nHint: 果報・・・", "answers": [ "果報は寝て待て", "かほうはねてまて" ], "comment": "Rank #1241 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "there is no leisure for the poor\n\nHint: 貧乏・・・", "answers": [ "貧乏暇なし", "びんぼうひまなし" ], "comment": "Rank #1242 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel relieved\n\nHint: 愁眉を・・・", "answers": [ "愁眉を開く", "しゅうびをひらく" ], "comment": "Rank #1243 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give rise to hostile comment; to arouse criticism; to provoke; to cause a controversy\n\nHint: 物議を・・・", "answers": [ "物議を醸す", "ぶつぎをかもす" ], "comment": "Rank #1244 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the end justifies the means; circumstances may justify a lie\n\nHint: 嘘も・・・", "answers": [ "嘘も方便", "うそもほうべん" ], "comment": "Rank #1245 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to grumble over one's wine cups\n\nHint: くだを・・・", "answers": [ "くだを巻く", "くだをまく" ], "comment": "Rank #1246 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "strike while the iron is hot\n\nHint: 鉄は熱いうちに・・・", "answers": [ "鉄は熱いうちに打て", "てつはあついうちにうて" ], "comment": "Rank #1247 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to use one's own money; to pay for from one's own pocket\n\nHint: 身銭を・・・", "answers": [ "身銭を切る", "みぜにをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #1248 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to mellow; to become softened by maturity\n\nHint: 角が・・・", "answers": [ "角が取れる", "かどがとれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1249 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a formal salutation (between gamblers); to formally greet; to pay one's respects\n\nHint: 仁義を・・・", "answers": [ "仁義を切る", "じんぎをきる" ], "comment": "Rank #1250 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not to be able to keep one's health; exceeding the limits of one's body; not to be able to maintain one's fortune\n\nHint: 身が・・・", "answers": [ "身が持たない", "みがもたない" ], "comment": "Rank #1251 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sieve; to sift; to winnow; to separate (wheat from chaff)\nto screen (candidates)\n\nHint: 篩に・・・", "answers": [ "篩にかける", "ふるいにかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1252 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be compatible; to get along well\n\nHint: 肌が・・・", "answers": [ "肌が合う", "はだがあう" ], "comment": "Rank #1253 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get teary-eyed\n\nHint: 熱いも・・・", "answers": [ "熱いものが込み上げる", "あついものがこみあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1254 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to carry weight; to be important; to have influence; to be a leading figure; to be esteemed\n\nHint: 重きを・・・", "answers": [ "重きをなす", "おもきをなす" ], "comment": "Rank #1255 (13 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "good for nothing (of people); derived from a large 'udo' plant being of no use (only the young, tender, plant can be eaten)\n\nHint: 独活の・・・", "answers": [ "独活の大木", "うどのたいぼく" ], "comment": "Rank #1256 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be proud\n\nHint: 鼻を・・・", "answers": [ "鼻を高くする", "はなをたかくする" ], "comment": "Rank #1257 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "disgusting; sickening; revolting; nauseating\n\nHint: 胸糞が・・・", "answers": [ "胸糞が悪い", "むなくそがわるい" ], "comment": "Rank #1258 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in minute detail\n\nHint: 細大・・・", "answers": [ "細大漏らさず", "さいだいもらさず" ], "comment": "Rank #1259 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the guilty are audacious; not showing remorse in spite of being in the wrong\n\nHint: 盗人・・・", "answers": [ "盗人猛々しい", "ぬすっとたけだけしい" ], "comment": "Rank #1260 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "by hook or by crook; by all possible means\n\nHint: 手を・・・", "answers": [ "手を替え品を替え", "てをかえしなをかえ" ], "comment": "Rank #1261 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "day in and day out; all the time\n\nHint: 明けても・・・", "answers": [ "明けても暮れても", "あけてもくれても" ], "comment": "Rank #1262 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cast amorous glances at a man (of a woman); to make eyes at; to give (someone) the eye; to make advances\n\nHint: 秋波を・・・", "answers": [ "秋波を送る", "しゅうはをおくる" ], "comment": "Rank #1263 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to regret bitterly; to be very sorry (for)\n\nHint: 臍を・・・", "answers": [ "臍を噬む", "ほぞをかむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1264 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "all pain, no gain; doing no good and a lot of harm; having no redeeming features; being a complete disadvantage; a hundred harms and not a single gain\n\nHint: 百害・・・", "answers": [ "百害あって一利なし", "ひゃくがいあっていちりなし" ], "comment": "Rank #1265 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to not mince matters; to speak frankly\n\nHint: 歯に・・・", "answers": [ "歯に衣着せぬ", "はにきぬきせぬ" ], "comment": "Rank #1266 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "it's the thought that counts\n\nHint: 気は・・・", "answers": [ "気は心", "きはこころ" ], "comment": "Rank #1267 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the time is ripe\n\nHint: 機が・・・", "answers": [ "機が熟す", "きがじゅくす" ], "comment": "Rank #1268 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "misery; distress\n\nHint: 塗炭の・・・", "answers": [ "塗炭の苦しみ", "とたんのくるしみ" ], "comment": "Rank #1269 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "complete loss of face\n\nHint: 面目・・・", "answers": [ "面目丸つぶれ", "めんぼくまるつぶれ" ], "comment": "Rank #1270 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "head over heels (often used mockingly); madly (in love)\n\nHint: 惚れ・・・", "answers": [ "惚れた腫れた", "ほれたはれた" ], "comment": "Rank #1271 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be betrayed\nto be brought to grief (by an enemy); to be given a hard time\n\nHint: 煮え湯を・・・", "answers": [ "煮え湯を飲まされる", "にえゆをのまされる" ], "comment": "Rank #1272 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "nothing to be afraid of; trivial; not amounting to much; can't do anything\n\nHint: 何するも・・・", "answers": [ "何するものぞ", "なにするものぞ" ], "comment": "Rank #1273 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "cat-and-mouse (race); lead changing hands many times\n\nHint: 追い・・・", "answers": [ "追いつ追われつ", "おいつおわれつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1274 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(to cast) pearls before swine; really big waste of resources\n\nHint: 猫に・・・", "answers": [ "猫に小判", "ねこにこばん" ], "comment": "Rank #1275 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to a greater extent than one has heard; going beyond one's expectations\n\nHint: 聞きしに・・・", "answers": [ "聞きしに勝る", "ききしにまさる" ], "comment": "Rank #1276 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "conventional and uninteresting; stereotypical and boring; commonplace\nunsociable; unfriendly; cold; indifferent\n\nHint: 曲が・・・", "answers": [ "曲がない", "きょくがない" ], "comment": "Rank #1277 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to appear in one's dream\n\nHint: 夢枕に・・・", "answers": [ "夢枕に立つ", "ゆめまくらにたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1278 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Lend me your ears a while\n\nHint: 物は・・・", "answers": [ "物は相談", "ものはそうだん" ], "comment": "Rank #1279 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "time is money\n\nHint: 時は・・・", "answers": [ "時は金なり", "ときはかねなり" ], "comment": "Rank #1280 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have one's own way (against all reason); to push through an unreasonable idea\n\nHint: 横車を・・・", "answers": [ "横車を押す", "よこぐるまをおす" ], "comment": "Rank #1281 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "inconsiderate; ruthless; merciless; lacking compunction\n\nHint: 遠慮会釈も・・・", "answers": [ "遠慮会釈もない", "えんりょえしゃくもない" ], "comment": "Rank #1282 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get credit; to win honor; to win honour\n\nHint: 面目を・・・", "answers": [ "面目を施す", "めんぼくをほどこす" ], "comment": "Rank #1283 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be no match for; to not hold a candle to\n\nHint: 足下に・・・", "answers": [ "足下にも及ばない", "あしもとにもおよばない" ], "comment": "Rank #1284 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "does not pay; not worth (one's) while\n\nHint: 間尺に・・・", "answers": [ "間尺に合わない", "ましゃくにあわない" ], "comment": "Rank #1285 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(so ashamed or embarrassed that) one does not know where to put oneself; feeling out of place\n\nHint: 身の・・・", "answers": [ "身の置き所がない", "みのおきどころがない" ], "comment": "Rank #1286 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to teach someone a lesson; to show someone a thing or two; to show someone what one can do\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目に物見せる", "めにものみせる" ], "comment": "Rank #1287 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to number more than ten; to be numerous\n\nHint: 十指に・・・", "answers": [ "十指に余る", "じっしにあまる" ], "comment": "Rank #1288 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to score points with (a person)\n\nHint: 点数を・・・", "answers": [ "点数を稼ぐ", "てんすうをかせぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #1289 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "He that fights and runs away may live to fight another day\n\nHint: 逃げるが・・・", "answers": [ "逃げるが勝ち", "にげるがかち" ], "comment": "Rank #1290 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to grow older; to advance in age; to be very aged\n\nHint: 年を・・・", "answers": [ "年を食う", "としをくう" ], "comment": "Rank #1291 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "right and proper; legal\n\nHint: 天下・・・", "answers": [ "天下晴れて", "てんかはれて" ], "comment": "Rank #1292 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sprinkle water on (something); to spray water on; to splash water on; to squirt water on\nto hinder; to hamper; to stifle; to throw cold water on\n\nHint: 水を・・・", "answers": [ "水を掛ける", "みずをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1293 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to meet (someone of higher status)\nto be recognized (esp. by someone of higher status); to be visible; to be seen; to be noticed\n\nHint: 御目に・・・", "answers": [ "御目にかかる", "おめにかかる" ], "comment": "Rank #1294 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "he who touches pitch shall be defiled therewith; one rotten apple spoils the barrel\n\nHint: 朱に・・・", "answers": [ "朱に交われば赤くなる", "しゅにまじわればあかくなる" ], "comment": "Rank #1295 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be enthralled by\nto be disguised as\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を窶す", "みをやつす" ], "comment": "Rank #1296 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to count on the abacus\nto calculate cost-benefit; to calculate profitability\n\nHint: 算盤を・・・", "answers": [ "算盤をはじく", "そろばんをはじく" ], "comment": "Rank #1297 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to leave everything to (someone)\n\nHint: 下駄を・・・", "answers": [ "下駄を預ける", "げたをあずける" ], "comment": "Rank #1298 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "still having a very small chance; still having a tiny shred of hope\n\nHint: 首の・・・", "answers": [ "首の皮一枚", "くびのかわいちまい" ], "comment": "Rank #1299 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "if you do a favor for somebody, you will get a return favor; if a fish is friendly toward water, water will be kind to the fish too; mutual back-scratching\n\nHint: 魚心・・・", "answers": [ "魚心あれば水心", "うおごころあればみずごころ" ], "comment": "Rank #1300 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have grown tense (of a situation); to have become critical (and to be on the verge of a major upheaval)\n\nHint: 風雲急を・・・", "answers": [ "風雲急を告げる", "ふううんきゅうをつげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1301 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stereotype; to squeeze into a pattern; to regiment\n\nHint: 型に・・・", "answers": [ "型に嵌める", "かたにはめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1302 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "capitalizing on the fame of a parent; riding a parent's coat-tails\n\nHint: 親の・・・", "answers": [ "親の七光", "おやのななひかり" ], "comment": "Rank #1303 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "History repeats itself\n\nHint: 歴史・・・", "answers": [ "歴史は繰り返す", "れきしはくりかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #1304 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be encouraged by initial success\n\nHint: 味を・・・", "answers": [ "味を占める", "あじをしめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1305 (12 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "clapping of wooden clappers signalling the beginning or end of a performance\n\nHint: 木が・・・", "answers": [ "木が入る", "きがはいる" ], "comment": "Rank #1306 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "seeing is believing; one eye-witness is better than many hearsays; a picture is worth a thousand words\n\nHint: 百聞は一見に・・・", "answers": [ "百聞は一見に如かず", "ひゃくぶんはいっけんにしかず" ], "comment": "Rank #1307 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "chance; opportunity; lucky break\n\nHint: 浮か・・・", "answers": [ "浮かぶ瀬", "うかぶせ" ], "comment": "Rank #1308 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to throw down the gauntlet\n\nHint: 手袋を・・・", "answers": [ "手袋を投げる", "てぶくろをなげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1309 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "shrill; piercing (scream, etc.)\n\nHint: 絹を・・・", "answers": [ "絹を裂くよう", "きぬをさくよう" ], "comment": "Rank #1310 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get a reputation as a philanderer\n\nHint: 浮名を・・・", "answers": [ "浮名を流す", "うきなをながす" ], "comment": "Rank #1311 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to threaten; to intimidate\n\nHint: 凄みを・・・", "answers": [ "凄みを利かす", "すごみをきかす" ], "comment": "Rank #1312 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have confidence in one's own abilities\n\nHint: 腕に・・・", "answers": [ "腕に覚えがある", "うでにおぼえがある" ], "comment": "Rank #1313 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "feeling as if in a dream\n\nHint: 夢か・・・", "answers": [ "夢か現か", "ゆめかうつつか" ], "comment": "Rank #1314 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "God doesn't give with both hands; God does not give two gifts; Heaven does not grant people more than one talent\n\nHint: 天は二物を・・・", "answers": [ "天は二物を与えず", "てんはにぶつをあたえず" ], "comment": "Rank #1315 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "witty and knowing; not to be underestimated; smooth operator\n\nHint: 隅に・・・", "answers": [ "隅に置けない", "すみにおけない" ], "comment": "Rank #1316 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to concur; to be the same (thought, opinion, etc.); to have the same way of doing\n\nHint: 軌を・・・", "answers": [ "軌を一にする", "きをいつにする" ], "comment": "Rank #1317 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to gain (put on) weight\n\nHint: 肉が・・・", "answers": [ "肉が付く", "ししがつく" ], "comment": "Rank #1318 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(to get something done) even if through hell and high water\n\nHint: 石に・・・", "answers": [ "石にかじりついても", "いしにかじりついても" ], "comment": "Rank #1319 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to advance to the next stage (e.g. in a tournament)\n\nHint: 駒を・・・", "answers": [ "駒を進める", "こまをすすめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1320 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It's all over now\n\nHint: 刀折・・・", "answers": [ "刀折れ矢尽きる", "かたなおれやつきる" ], "comment": "Rank #1321 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stop writing; to put down one's pen; to close (a letter)\n\nHint: 筆を・・・", "answers": [ "筆を擱く", "ふでをおく" ], "comment": "Rank #1322 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being crazy about something but being very bad at it\n\nHint: 下手の・・・", "answers": [ "下手の横好き", "へたのよこずき" ], "comment": "Rank #1323 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "One good turn deserves another\n\nHint: 人は・・・", "answers": [ "人は情", "ひとはなさけ" ], "comment": "Rank #1324 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "fluency; volubility\n\nHint: 立板に・・・", "answers": [ "立板に水", "たていたにみず" ], "comment": "Rank #1325 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to live on air\nto derive nourishment from an elemental portion of mist or fog (the goal of a mountain ascetic)\n\nHint: 霞を・・・", "answers": [ "霞を食う", "かすみをくう" ], "comment": "Rank #1326 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "in time of need; for a rainy day; in case of emergency\n\nHint: まさかの・・・", "answers": [ "まさかの時", "まさかのとき" ], "comment": "Rank #1327 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become famous\n\nHint: 世に・・・", "answers": [ "世に立つ", "よにたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1328 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to arrange not to contradict each other\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を合わせる", "くちをあわせる" ], "comment": "Rank #1329 (11 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "broad-minded\n(of a rikishi) tall, with long reach, making it harder for their opponent to get a grip on their mawashi\n\nHint: 懐が・・・", "answers": [ "懐が深い", "ふところがふかい" ], "comment": "Rank #1330 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "parents' partiality for their children; parents overvaluing their children\n\nHint: 親の・・・", "answers": [ "親の欲目", "おやのよくめ" ], "comment": "Rank #1331 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to interrupt; to jeer\n\nHint: 半畳を・・・", "answers": [ "半畳を入れる", "はんじょうをいれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1332 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to spend (money) like water; to spend (money) like it grows on trees; to throw around (one's money); to play ducks and drakes with\n\nHint: 湯水の・・・", "answers": [ "湯水のように使う", "ゆみずのようにつかう" ], "comment": "Rank #1333 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be right on target; to strike it rich\n\nHint: 一山・・・", "answers": [ "一山当てる", "ひとやまあてる" ], "comment": "Rank #1334 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be frank; to speak one's mind; to open one's heart; to have a heart-to-heart talk (with someone)\n\nHint: 胸襟を・・・", "answers": [ "胸襟を開く", "きょうきんをひらく" ], "comment": "Rank #1335 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "meeting all three important conditions; being a triple threat; being ideal\n\nHint: 三拍・・・", "answers": [ "三拍子揃う", "さんびょうしそろう" ], "comment": "Rank #1336 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "refusing to budge; adamant; intransigent; unyielding\n\nHint: 梃子で・・・", "answers": [ "梃子でも動かない", "てこでもうごかない" ], "comment": "Rank #1337 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "having thought for neither gain nor greed; only wanting to do something (thinking about nothing else)\n\nHint: 欲も・・・", "answers": [ "欲も得もない", "よくもとくもない" ], "comment": "Rank #1338 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not eating enough\nunsatisfied; dissatisfied with; leaving something to be desired\n\nHint: 食い・・・", "answers": [ "食い足りない", "くいたりない" ], "comment": "Rank #1339 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "tasteless; dry as dust; insipid; flat; dull\n\nHint: 砂を・・・", "answers": [ "砂を噛むよう", "すなをかむよう" ], "comment": "Rank #1340 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "there is only the thickness of the boat's planking between one and perdition; on a boat, one is only an inch or two from a watery grave\n\nHint: 板子・・・", "answers": [ "板子一枚下は地獄", "いたごいちまいしたはじごく" ], "comment": "Rank #1341 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to start (e.g. a scene, a war, etc.)\n\nHint: 幕を・・・", "answers": [ "幕を切って落とす", "まくをきっておとす" ], "comment": "Rank #1342 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "easily\n\nHint: 手も・・・", "answers": [ "手も無く", "てもなく" ], "comment": "Rank #1343 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "dogs and monkeys (esp. as an example of a bad relationship, like that between cats and dogs)\n\nHint: 犬と・・・", "answers": [ "犬と猿", "いぬとさる" ], "comment": "Rank #1344 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cheer; to raise somebody's spirits\n\nHint: 気を・・・", "answers": [ "気を引き立てる", "きをひきたてる" ], "comment": "Rank #1345 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be worth telling; to be worth confiding in\n\nHint: 語るに・・・", "answers": [ "語るに足る", "かたるにたる" ], "comment": "Rank #1346 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the proof of the pudding is in the eating; the proof is in the pudding; don't knock it till you've tried it\n\nHint: 物は・・・", "answers": [ "物は試し", "ものはためし" ], "comment": "Rank #1347 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "arrogant; impudent; haughty; boastful\n\nHint: 態度が・・・", "answers": [ "態度が大きい", "たいどがおおきい" ], "comment": "Rank #1348 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "He that knows little often repeats it\n\nHint: 馬鹿の・・・", "answers": [ "馬鹿の一つ覚え", "ばかのひとつおぼえ" ], "comment": "Rank #1349 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not getting a reply\n\nHint: 梨の・・・", "answers": [ "梨の礫", "なしのつぶて" ], "comment": "Rank #1350 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "feeling sad or downhearted; down in the dumps\n\nHint: 青菜に・・・", "answers": [ "青菜に塩", "あおなにしお" ], "comment": "Rank #1351 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to signal the winner of a match (by the referee raising his fan towards the winner)\nto declare someone the winner (of a competition)\n\nHint: 軍配を・・・", "answers": [ "軍配をあげる", "ぐんばいをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1352 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a risk for someone; to endanger oneself for someone; to gather chestnuts from a fire\n\nHint: 火中の・・・", "answers": [ "火中の栗を拾う", "かちゅうのくりをひろう" ], "comment": "Rank #1353 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to eke out a living; to barely manage to get by\n\nHint: 口を・・・", "answers": [ "口を糊する", "くちをのりする" ], "comment": "Rank #1354 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do wholeheartedly; to put one's heart into something\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を籠める", "こころをこめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1355 (10 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make an example of; to make a victim of; to hold up somebody (something) to ridicule; to single out someone for criticism\n\nHint: 槍玉に・・・", "answers": [ "槍玉に挙げる", "やりだまにあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1356 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pant; to gasp\n\nHint: 息急・・・", "answers": [ "息急き切る", "いきせききる" ], "comment": "Rank #1357 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "two halves of the whole; two wheels on which everything rolls\n\nHint: 車の・・・", "answers": [ "車の両輪", "くるまのりょうりん" ], "comment": "Rank #1358 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to rise in esteem; to become popular\nto rise in value (stocks)\n\nHint: 株が・・・", "answers": [ "株が上がる", "かぶがあがる" ], "comment": "Rank #1359 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to concede a point; to yield; to give in\n\nHint: 我を・・・", "answers": [ "我を折る", "がをおる" ], "comment": "Rank #1360 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "expensive to rent\nwrestler ranked too high for his abilities\n\nHint: 家賃が・・・", "answers": [ "家賃が高い", "やちんがたかい" ], "comment": "Rank #1361 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to weigh on a scale\nto weigh up options; to compare pros and cons\n\nHint: 秤に・・・", "answers": [ "秤に掛ける", "はかりにかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1362 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "adversity strengthens the foundations\n\nHint: 雨降・・・", "answers": [ "雨降って地固まる", "あめふってじかたまる" ], "comment": "Rank #1363 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "simple (e.g. matter); problem free\nhopeless; the end (i.e. leaving one at a loss of words); dumbfounding\n\nHint: 世話が・・・", "answers": [ "世話がない", "せわがない" ], "comment": "Rank #1364 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "You never know what might happen\n\nHint: 鬼が・・・", "answers": [ "鬼が出るか蛇が出るか", "おにがでるかじゃがでるか" ], "comment": "Rank #1365 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to vie with one's opponent\n\nHint: 向こうを・・・", "answers": [ "向こうを張る", "むこうをはる" ], "comment": "Rank #1366 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "find it against one's conscience (to do); too proud (to do)\n\nHint: 潔しと・・・", "answers": [ "潔しとせず", "いさぎよしとせず" ], "comment": "Rank #1367 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "dumplings rather than flowers; people are more interested in the practical over the aesthetic\n\nHint: 花よ・・・", "answers": [ "花より団子", "はなよりだんご" ], "comment": "Rank #1368 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "strapped for cash; hard up\n\nHint: 懐が・・・", "answers": [ "懐が寂しい", "ふところがさびしい" ], "comment": "Rank #1369 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "fellow sufferers pity each other\n\nHint: 同病・・・", "answers": [ "同病相憐む", "どうびょうあいあわれむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1370 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to close one's business\n\nHint: 看板を・・・", "answers": [ "看板を下ろす", "かんばんをおろす" ], "comment": "Rank #1371 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "skill learned in one's former days; using one's experience from the past; you never forget your own trade\n\nHint: 昔取・・・", "answers": [ "昔取った杵柄", "むかしとったきねづか" ], "comment": "Rank #1372 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "appearances can be deceiving; don't judge a book by its cover\n\nHint: 人は見かけに・・・", "answers": [ "人は見かけによらぬもの", "ひとはみかけによらぬもの" ], "comment": "Rank #1373 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to accept a challenge; to take up the gauntlet\n\nHint: 喧嘩を・・・", "answers": [ "喧嘩を買う", "けんかをかう" ], "comment": "Rank #1374 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "back-and-forth; neck-and-neck\n\nHint: 抜き・・・", "answers": [ "抜きつ抜かれつ", "ぬきつぬかれつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1375 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be divinely skilled\n\nHint: 神に・・・", "answers": [ "神に入る", "しんにいる" ], "comment": "Rank #1376 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "eating only a little; having a small appetite\n\nHint: 食が・・・", "answers": [ "食が細い", "しょくがほそい" ], "comment": "Rank #1377 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pull wires; to pull strings\n\nHint: 陰で・・・", "answers": [ "陰で糸を引く", "かげでいとをひく" ], "comment": "Rank #1378 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "between the devil and the deep sea; out of the frying pan into the fire\n\nHint: 前門の・・・", "answers": [ "前門の虎、後門の狼", "ぜんもんのとら、こうもんのおおかみ" ], "comment": "Rank #1379 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "preventing one's opponent from getting an underarm grip\nhaving weak defenses\n\nHint: 脇が・・・", "answers": [ "脇が甘い", "わきがあまい" ], "comment": "Rank #1380 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "whether one likes it or not; compulsorily; by force\n\nHint: 否応・・・", "answers": [ "否応無しに", "いやおうなしに" ], "comment": "Rank #1381 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "inscrutable are the ways of heaven; fortune is unpredictable and changeable\n\nHint: 人間万事塞翁が・・・", "answers": [ "人間万事塞翁が馬", "にんげんばんじさいおうがうま" ], "comment": "Rank #1382 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Names and natures do often agree\n\nHint: 名は体を・・・", "answers": [ "名は体を表す", "なはたいをあらわす" ], "comment": "Rank #1383 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "expresses shock at misbehaviour of a youngster; what must his parents be like?; I'd like to see his parents' faces\n\nHint: 親の・・・", "answers": [ "親の顔が見たい", "おやのかおがみたい" ], "comment": "Rank #1384 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be traced; to be tracked (by someone)\nto have a lover (for a woman)\n\nHint: 足が・・・", "answers": [ "足が付く", "あしがつく" ], "comment": "Rank #1385 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "more haste, less speed; slow and steady wins the race\n\nHint: 急が・・・", "answers": [ "急がば回れ", "いそがばまわれ" ], "comment": "Rank #1386 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "needless to say; it goes without saying\n\nHint: 論を・・・", "answers": [ "論を俟たない", "ろんをまたない" ], "comment": "Rank #1387 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to put away one's bedding\nto recover from an illness (and put away one's sickbed)\n\nHint: 床を・・・", "answers": [ "床をあげる", "とこをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1388 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "raising and lowering; praising and blaming\n\nHint: 上げ・・・", "answers": [ "上げたり下げたり", "あげたりさげたり" ], "comment": "Rank #1389 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to incur the wrath of god (e.g. by speaking ill of somebody behind their back); to get into trouble\nto warp one's mouth\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口が曲がる", "くちがまがる" ], "comment": "Rank #1390 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get back together (with a former partner)\n\nHint: 縒りを・・・", "answers": [ "縒りを戻す", "よりをもどす" ], "comment": "Rank #1391 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "smooth words make smooth ways; it's not what you say, it's how you say it\n\nHint: 物は・・・", "answers": [ "物は言いよう", "ものはいいよう" ], "comment": "Rank #1392 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "having no effect; waste of effort\n\nHint: 糠に・・・", "answers": [ "糠に釘", "ぬかにくぎ" ], "comment": "Rank #1393 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "easy profit\n\nHint: 濡れ手で・・・", "answers": [ "濡れ手で粟", "ぬれてであわ" ], "comment": "Rank #1394 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to \\\"see stars\\\" (i.e. after being hit in the head)\n\nHint: 目から火が・・・", "answers": [ "目から火が出る", "めからひがでる" ], "comment": "Rank #1395 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the mistake of a wise man\n\nHint: 千慮の・・・", "answers": [ "千慮の一失", "せんりょのいっしつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1396 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a pass at; to hit on; to call out to (in an attempt to seduce)\n\nHint: 粉を・・・", "answers": [ "粉をかける", "こなをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1397 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "living in obscurity; lying low; remaining unnoticed\n\nHint: 鳴か・・・", "answers": [ "鳴かず飛ばず", "なかずとばず" ], "comment": "Rank #1398 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to read between the lines\n\nHint: 行間を・・・", "answers": [ "行間を読む", "ぎょうかんをよむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1399 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(with an apologetic tone) undesirable state brought about by (my) lack of virtue; feeling morally responsible; mea culpa\n\nHint: 不徳の・・・", "answers": [ "不徳の致すところ", "ふとくのいたすところ" ], "comment": "Rank #1400 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a blunder; to bungle; to mess up; to make a foolish mistake\n\nHint: どじを・・・", "answers": [ "どじを踏む", "どじをふむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1401 (9 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have great influence over\n\nHint: 幅が・・・", "answers": [ "幅が利く", "はばがきく" ], "comment": "Rank #1402 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "once you're dead, that's it\n\nHint: 死んで・・・", "answers": [ "死んで花実が咲くものか", "しんではなみがさくものか" ], "comment": "Rank #1403 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to chill one's bones (e.g. because of cold, pain, etc.); to be very cold; to be scathing\n\nHint: 骨を・・・", "answers": [ "骨を刺す", "ほねをさす" ], "comment": "Rank #1404 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "showing no concern at all; being not at all bothered; devil-may-care attitude\n\nHint: 何処・・・", "answers": [ "何処吹く風", "どこふくかぜ" ], "comment": "Rank #1405 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feather one's own nest\n\nHint: 懐を・・・", "answers": [ "懐を肥やす", "ふところをこやす" ], "comment": "Rank #1406 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be blinded by greed\n\nHint: 欲に・・・", "answers": [ "欲に目が眩む", "よくにめがくらむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1407 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "like man, like wife; like marries like\n\nHint: 似た・・・", "answers": [ "似た者夫婦", "にたものふうふ" ], "comment": "Rank #1408 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to catch fire; to provoke; to catch fire from; to be ignited\n\nHint: 火が・・・", "answers": [ "火が付く", "ひがつく" ], "comment": "Rank #1409 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "never ceasing; never ending; endless\n\nHint: 跡を・・・", "answers": [ "跡を絶たない", "あとをたたない" ], "comment": "Rank #1410 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "nothing ventured, nothing gained\n\nHint: 虎穴に・・・", "answers": [ "虎穴に入らずんば虎子を得ず", "こけつにいらずんばこしをえず" ], "comment": "Rank #1411 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to attend a meeting; to have the honor of being present at a meeting; to soil the lowest seat by one's presence\n\nHint: 末席を・・・", "answers": [ "末席を汚す", "まっせきをけがす" ], "comment": "Rank #1412 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be meant for each other (of a man and woman); to be connected through fate; to be destined to marry (each other); to be tied by (the) red string (of fate)\n\nHint: 赤い糸で・・・", "answers": [ "赤い糸で結ばれる", "あかいいとでむすばれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1413 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "old-fashioned (in one's way of thinking)\n\nHint: 頭が・・・", "answers": [ "頭が古い", "あたまがふるい" ], "comment": "Rank #1414 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have one's legs become stiff, tired\n\nHint: 足が・・・", "answers": [ "足が棒になる", "あしがぼうになる" ], "comment": "Rank #1415 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to place one's arms under those of the opponent and lift them up, in order to prevent an overhand grip on one's mawashi\n\nHint: 腕を・・・", "answers": [ "腕を返す", "かいなをかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #1416 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "trivial; not amounting to much; not enough to cause a problem; not as much as expected\n\nHint: 何の・・・", "answers": [ "何の事はない", "なんのことはない" ], "comment": "Rank #1417 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "out of control; out of hand; unmanageable\n\nHint: 手が・・・", "answers": [ "手が付けられない", "てがつけられない" ], "comment": "Rank #1418 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It is hard to explain; It is hard to say\n\nHint: 曰く・・・", "answers": [ "曰く言い難し", "いわくいいがたし" ], "comment": "Rank #1419 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to meet face-to-face; to discuss unreservedly\n\nHint: 膝を・・・", "answers": [ "膝を突き合わせる", "ひざをつきあわせる" ], "comment": "Rank #1420 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "young at heart\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が若い", "きがわかい" ], "comment": "Rank #1421 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be particular about one's food; to have a discriminating palate\n\nHint: 舌が・・・", "answers": [ "舌が肥える", "したがこえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1422 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "mountain in the winter (usu. in haiku); sleeping mountain\n\nHint: 山眠・・・", "answers": [ "山眠る", "やまねむる" ], "comment": "Rank #1423 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to humble someone\n\nHint: 花を・・・", "answers": [ "花を折る", "はなをおる" ], "comment": "Rank #1424 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "intense antipathy (like a blazing fire); flames of rage\n\nHint: 瞋恚の・・・", "answers": [ "瞋恚の炎", "しんいのほのお" ], "comment": "Rank #1425 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be discouraged (from doing something); to have one's enthusiasm dampened\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気がそがれる", "きがそがれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1426 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "pie in the sky; castle in the air\n\nHint: 絵に・・・", "answers": [ "絵に描いた餅", "えにかいたもち" ], "comment": "Rank #1427 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "eye-popping; staggering\n\nHint: 目の・・・", "answers": [ "目の玉が飛び出る", "めのたまがとびでる" ], "comment": "Rank #1428 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "bold; daring; unflappable\n\nHint: 肝が・・・", "answers": [ "肝が太い", "きもがふとい" ], "comment": "Rank #1429 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to give birth\n\nHint: 身二つに・・・", "answers": [ "身二つになる", "みふたつになる" ], "comment": "Rank #1430 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become decrepit; to be in one's dotage; to become dull; to lose one's astuteness; to lose one's touch; to become senile; to lose one's edge; to go downhill\n\nHint: 焼きが・・・", "answers": [ "焼きが回る", "やきがまわる" ], "comment": "Rank #1431 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to hurt one's reputation; to be ashamed of oneself; to lose one's honour\n\nHint: 男が・・・", "answers": [ "男が廃る", "おとこがすたる" ], "comment": "Rank #1432 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "A curse will rebound on yourself as well; Curses, like chickens, come home to roost\n\nHint: 人を・・・", "answers": [ "人を呪わば穴二つ", "ひとをのろわばあなふたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1433 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be broad-minded enough to associate with various types of people; to possess a capacious mind\n\nHint: 清濁・・・", "answers": [ "清濁併せ呑む", "せいだくあわせのむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1434 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "All living things must die\n\nHint: 生者・・・", "answers": [ "生者必滅", "しょうじゃひつめつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1435 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Only the husband does not know\n\nHint: 知ら・・・", "answers": [ "知らぬは亭主ばかりなり", "しらぬはていしゅばかりなり" ], "comment": "Rank #1436 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Lose a fly to catch a trout; small sacrifice in a great cause\n\nHint: 大事の・・・", "answers": [ "大事の前の小事", "だいじのまえのしょうじ" ], "comment": "Rank #1437 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "soft-hearted; susceptible; sentimental; tender-hearted\n\nHint: 情に・・・", "answers": [ "情にもろい", "じょうにもろい" ], "comment": "Rank #1438 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have good luck\n\nHint: 有卦に・・・", "answers": [ "有卦に入る", "うけにいる" ], "comment": "Rank #1439 (8 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "innocent until proven guilty; suspicion alone is not grounds for punishment; in dubio pro reo\n\nHint: 疑わ・・・", "answers": [ "疑わしきは罰せず", "うたがわしきはばっせず" ], "comment": "Rank #1440 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have nerves of steel\n\nHint: 度胸が・・・", "answers": [ "度胸が据わる", "どきょうがすわる" ], "comment": "Rank #1441 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(feeling) proud\n\nHint: 肩身が・・・", "answers": [ "肩身が広い", "かたみがひろい" ], "comment": "Rank #1442 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "deep autumn (when the autumn has reached its climax)\n\nHint: 秋深・・・", "answers": [ "秋深し", "あきふかし" ], "comment": "Rank #1443 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Money rules the world\n\nHint: 金の・・・", "answers": [ "金の世の中", "かねのよのなか" ], "comment": "Rank #1444 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cut the Gordian knot\n\nHint: 快刀乱麻を・・・", "answers": [ "快刀乱麻を断つ", "かいとうらんまをたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1445 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "an eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth\n\nHint: 目に・・・", "answers": [ "目には目を、歯には歯を", "めにはめを、はにははを" ], "comment": "Rank #1446 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to insure (something)\n\nHint: 保険を・・・", "answers": [ "保険を掛ける", "ほけんをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1447 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to sharpen one's claws\n\nHint: 爪を・・・", "answers": [ "爪を研ぐ", "つめをとぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #1448 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "snail's pace\n\nHint: 牛の・・・", "answers": [ "牛の歩み", "うしのあゆみ" ], "comment": "Rank #1449 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "machination; secret plan; plot; trick up one's sleeve\n\nHint: 胸に・・・", "answers": [ "胸に一物", "むねにいちもつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1450 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be attracted (by); to take an interest (in)\n\nHint: 心を・・・", "answers": [ "心を引かれる", "こころをひかれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1451 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to try the patience of a saint\n\nHint: 仏の・・・", "answers": [ "仏の顔も三度", "ほとけのかおもさんど" ], "comment": "Rank #1452 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "person of strong constitution unexpectedly falling ill; sickness of a stout man; the devil getting sunstroke\n\nHint: 鬼の・・・", "answers": [ "鬼の霍乱", "おにのかくらん" ], "comment": "Rank #1453 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "what more can one say?; utterly at a loss for words (because of disbelief or disgust)\n\nHint: 何を・・・", "answers": [ "何をか言わんや", "なにをかいわんや" ], "comment": "Rank #1454 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "at the height of one's power or influence; at the peak of one's popularity\n\nHint: 今を・・・", "answers": [ "今を時めく", "いまをときめく" ], "comment": "Rank #1455 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "hopeless; unmanageable; incorrigible\n\nHint: 箸に・・・", "answers": [ "箸にも棒にもかからない", "はしにもぼうにもかからない" ], "comment": "Rank #1456 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a wonder lasts but nine days; gossip lasts just 75 days\n\nHint: 人の・・・", "answers": [ "人の噂も七十五日", "ひとのうわさもしちじゅうごにち" ], "comment": "Rank #1457 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to save an enemy from trouble instead of taking advantage of their weakness; to show humanity even to one's enemy; to help one's enemy in difficulty\n\nHint: 敵に・・・", "answers": [ "敵に塩を送る", "てきにしおをおくる" ], "comment": "Rank #1458 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to go to one's heart; to cut one to the quick; to give one a deep impression; to clutch at one's heartstrings; to hit home; to strike home; to strike a chord; to strike a note\n\nHint: 胸に・・・", "answers": [ "胸に応える", "むねにこたえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1459 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stick one's nose into (someone else's business); to meddle; to interfere; to butt in\n\nHint: 嘴を・・・", "answers": [ "嘴を挟む", "くちばしをさしはさむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1460 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to avoid; to dodge; to evade\n\nHint: 体を・・・", "answers": [ "体を躱す", "たいをかわす" ], "comment": "Rank #1461 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do in secret\n\nHint: 目を・・・", "answers": [ "目を掠める", "めをかすめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1462 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to enlighten\n\nHint: 蒙を・・・", "answers": [ "蒙を啓く", "もうをひらく" ], "comment": "Rank #1463 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "speaking inarticulately (slurring, lisping, etc.)\n\nHint: 呂律が・・・", "answers": [ "呂律が回らない", "ろれつがまわらない" ], "comment": "Rank #1464 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to apply pressure (on); to bring pressure upon; to lean on\n\nHint: 圧力を・・・", "answers": [ "圧力を掛ける", "あつりょくをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1465 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to blame; to find fault with\n\nHint: 難癖を・・・", "answers": [ "難癖を付ける", "なんくせをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #1466 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "absentmindedly; in spite of oneself\n\nHint: 我に・・・", "answers": [ "我にもあらず", "われにもあらず" ], "comment": "Rank #1467 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to not be able to concentrate on (due to distractions, etc.)\n\nHint: 手に・・・", "answers": [ "手に付かない", "てにつかない" ], "comment": "Rank #1468 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It depends on how you look at it\n\nHint: 物は・・・", "answers": [ "物は考えよう", "ものはかんがえよう" ], "comment": "Rank #1469 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be annoyed (by); to be offended (at); to be irritated (with)\n\nHint: かちんと・・・", "answers": [ "かちんと来る", "かちんとくる" ], "comment": "Rank #1470 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to present one's card\n\nHint: 刺を・・・", "answers": [ "刺を通ずる", "しをつうずる", "刺を通じる", "しをつうじる" ], "comment": "Rank #1471 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to pay attention to\n\nHint: 意を・・・", "answers": [ "意を用いる", "いをもちいる" ], "comment": "Rank #1472 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Even plain parents can produce a genius child; A great person may be born of perfectly ordinary parents\n\nHint: 鳶が・・・", "answers": [ "鳶が鷹を生む", "とびがたかをうむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1473 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have many visitors (of a home); to be prosperous (of a shop)\n\nHint: 門前市を・・・", "answers": [ "門前市をなす", "もんぜんいちをなす" ], "comment": "Rank #1474 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(girl) who outblooms even a flower; even the flower will blush (before her beauty)\n\nHint: 花も・・・", "answers": [ "花も恥じらう", "はなもはじらう" ], "comment": "Rank #1475 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "rubbernecking; the thrill of looking at something scary or unpleasant and wanting to look at it all the more because it is scary or unpleasant\n\nHint: 恐いも・・・", "answers": [ "恐いもの見たさ", "こわいものみたさ" ], "comment": "Rank #1476 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "similar things turning up one after another; bamboo shoots after rain\n\nHint: 雨後の・・・", "answers": [ "雨後の筍", "うごのたけのこ" ], "comment": "Rank #1477 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to compare and contrast two alternatives; to weigh the relative merits of A and B; to weigh one's options\nto try to have it both ways; to try to sit on two stools\n\nHint: 天秤に・・・", "answers": [ "天秤に掛ける", "てんびんにかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1478 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "whenever they come together\n\nHint: 寄ると・・・", "answers": [ "寄ると触ると", "よるとさわると" ], "comment": "Rank #1479 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become overly logical; to be hairsplitting\n\nHint: 理に・・・", "answers": [ "理に落ちる", "りにおちる" ], "comment": "Rank #1480 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the nail that sticks out gets hammered in; the best policy is to keep your head down\n\nHint: 出る・・・", "answers": [ "出る杭は打たれる", "でるくいはうたれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1481 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not non-existent; not completely lacking; there is some; certainly existent\n\nHint: 無きに・・・", "answers": [ "無きにしも非ず", "なきにしもあらず" ], "comment": "Rank #1482 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to exercise one's talent; to display one's ability\n\nHint: 腕を・・・", "answers": [ "腕を揮う", "うでをふるう" ], "comment": "Rank #1483 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep a secret when asked about it, but let it slip inadvertently when chatting on another occasion\n\nHint: 問うに・・・", "answers": [ "問うに落ちず語るに落ちる", "とうにおちずかたるにおちる" ], "comment": "Rank #1484 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to fabricate a web of lies\n\nHint: 嘘で・・・", "answers": [ "嘘で固める", "うそでかためる" ], "comment": "Rank #1485 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "stop talking nonsense; don't be ridiculous; give me a break\n\nHint: 馬鹿も・・・", "answers": [ "馬鹿も休み休み言え", "ばかもやすみやすみいえ" ], "comment": "Rank #1486 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(doing something) regardless of expense\n\nHint: 金に・・・", "answers": [ "金に糸目をつけない", "かねにいとめをつけない" ], "comment": "Rank #1487 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "failing to practice what one preaches; physician, heal thyself; doctors often neglect their own health\n\nHint: 医者の・・・", "answers": [ "医者の不養生", "いしゃのふようじょう" ], "comment": "Rank #1488 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It's pouring\n\nHint: 車軸を・・・", "answers": [ "車軸を流す", "しゃじくをながす" ], "comment": "Rank #1489 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "firm; flexible and hard to break; persevering\n\nHint: 腰が・・・", "answers": [ "腰が強い", "こしがつよい" ], "comment": "Rank #1490 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being very popular; being in great demand\n\nHint: 引く・・・", "answers": [ "引く手数多", "ひくてあまた" ], "comment": "Rank #1491 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to disturb the water; to wake a sleeping dog; to wake a sleeping child\n\nHint: 寝た子を・・・", "answers": [ "寝た子を起こす", "ねたこをおこす" ], "comment": "Rank #1492 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to flee from one's enemy; to turn tail\nto expose one's weakness to an adversary\n\nHint: 敵に・・・", "answers": [ "敵に後ろを見せる", "てきにうしろをみせる" ], "comment": "Rank #1493 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to change one's attitude quickly\nto flip over one's hand\n\nHint: 手の・・・", "answers": [ "手の平を返す", "てのひらをかえす" ], "comment": "Rank #1494 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "sickness and health start with the mind\n\nHint: 病は・・・", "answers": [ "病は気から", "やまいはきから" ], "comment": "Rank #1495 (7 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to surrender one's chastity to a man\n\nHint: 肌を・・・", "answers": [ "肌を許す", "はだをゆるす" ], "comment": "Rank #1496 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be allowed to practice with a partner of higher skill (esp. in sumo)\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を借りる", "むねをかりる" ], "comment": "Rank #1497 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "triumphant (over a mediocre achievement); boastful; as if one had grabbed a demon by the neck\n\nHint: 鬼の・・・", "answers": [ "鬼の首を取ったよう", "おにのくびをとったよう" ], "comment": "Rank #1498 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to eat a boxed lunch\n\nHint: 弁当を・・・", "answers": [ "弁当を使う", "べんとうをつかう" ], "comment": "Rank #1499 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "well then, (shall we); well then, (I'll)\ngoodbye\n\nHint: いざ・・・", "answers": [ "いざさらば", "いざさらば" ], "comment": "Rank #1500 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to err; to take the wrong path; to go astray\n\nHint: 身を・・・", "answers": [ "身を誤る", "みをあやまる" ], "comment": "Rank #1501 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be inferior to; to be outdone; to compare unfavourably with\n\nHint: 一籌を・・・", "answers": [ "一籌を輸する", "いっちゅうをしゅする" ], "comment": "Rank #1502 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cry against; to denounce publicly\n\nHint: 非を・・・", "answers": [ "非を鳴らす", "ひをならす" ], "comment": "Rank #1503 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to keep to oneself (secret, etc.)\n\nHint: 胸に・・・", "answers": [ "胸に納める", "むねにおさめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1504 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lend a hand; to render assistance\nto bare one shoulder\n\nHint: 片肌・・・", "answers": [ "片肌脱ぐ", "かたはだぬぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #1505 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "experience is the best teacher; custom makes all things easy; you learn best by doing; practice makes perfect; it is better to grow accustomed than to be taught\n\nHint: 習う・・・", "answers": [ "習うより慣れよ", "ならうよりなれよ" ], "comment": "Rank #1506 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not worth doing; waste of effort\n\nHint: 暖簾に・・・", "answers": [ "暖簾に腕押し", "のれんにうでおし" ], "comment": "Rank #1507 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unavoidable; inevitable; cannot be helped; of necessity\n\nHint: 是非に・・・", "answers": [ "是非に及ばず", "ぜひにおよばず" ], "comment": "Rank #1508 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "hard-nosed; strong-willed; determined; unyielding; stubborn; resolute; assertive; headstrong\n\nHint: 鼻っ柱が・・・", "answers": [ "鼻っ柱が強い", "はなっぱしらがつよい" ], "comment": "Rank #1509 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "shameless; bold; brazen\n\nHint: 面の・・・", "answers": [ "面の皮が厚い", "つらのかわがあつい" ], "comment": "Rank #1510 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to show mercy; to show sympathy; to have compassion; to be kind\n\nHint: 情けを・・・", "answers": [ "情けを掛ける", "なさけをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1511 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "victory depends on the luck of the day (i.e. it isn't always the strongest who wins)\n\nHint: 勝負は時の・・・", "answers": [ "勝負は時の運", "しょうぶはときのうん" ], "comment": "Rank #1512 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "intending to persuade someone and instead being persuaded oneself; going for wool and coming home shorn; the biter bit; the mummy hunter himself becomes a mummy\n\nHint: ミイラ取りが・・・", "answers": [ "ミイラ取りがミイラになる", "ミイラとりがミイラになる" ], "comment": "Rank #1513 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to leave a bad impression behind\n\nHint: 跡を・・・", "answers": [ "跡を濁す", "あとをにごす" ], "comment": "Rank #1514 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "when in Rome, do as the Romans do\n\nHint: 郷に・・・", "answers": [ "郷に入っては郷に従え", "ごうにいってはごうにしたがえ" ], "comment": "Rank #1515 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have guts; to be unwavering in one's resolution\n\nHint: 腹が・・・", "answers": [ "腹が据わる", "はらがすわる" ], "comment": "Rank #1516 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "let sleeping dogs lie; if it ain't broke, don't fix it\n\nHint: 触らぬ神に・・・", "answers": [ "触らぬ神に祟りなし", "さわらぬかみにたたりなし" ], "comment": "Rank #1517 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to depend on somebody for food and lodging\nto be treated coldly; to be kept in a low position\n\nHint: 冷飯を・・・", "answers": [ "冷飯を食う", "ひやめしをくう" ], "comment": "Rank #1518 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to increase in value; to gain prestige\n\nHint: 箔が・・・", "answers": [ "箔が付く", "はくがつく" ], "comment": "Rank #1519 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be found out; to be seen through; to be exposed; to come to light; to be revealed\n\nHint: 底が・・・", "answers": [ "底が割れる", "そこがわれる" ], "comment": "Rank #1520 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be brief and to the point; to be succinct\n\nHint: 簡に・・・", "answers": [ "簡にして要を得る", "かんにしてようをえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1521 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Even the prosperous inevitably decay (from the Humane King Sutra); sic transit gloria mundi\n\nHint: 盛者・・・", "answers": [ "盛者必衰", "じょうしゃひっすい" ], "comment": "Rank #1522 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be infatuated; to be hooked on\n\nHint: 現を・・・", "answers": [ "現を抜かす", "うつつをぬかす" ], "comment": "Rank #1523 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take great risks\n\nHint: 虎の・・・", "answers": [ "虎の尾を踏む", "とらのおをふむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1524 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "on the least pretext; at the drop of a hat\n\nHint: 何かと・・・", "answers": [ "何かと言えば", "なにかといえば" ], "comment": "Rank #1525 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "out of the question; preposterous\n\nHint: 沙汰の・・・", "answers": [ "沙汰の限り", "さたのかぎり" ], "comment": "Rank #1526 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "otherwise; else; if not so\n\nHint: 然も・・・", "answers": [ "然もないと", "さもないと" ], "comment": "Rank #1527 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to find a new master\n\nHint: 主を・・・", "answers": [ "主を取る", "しゅうをとる" ], "comment": "Rank #1528 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "focus of one's attention; what one is looking for\n\nHint: 目の・・・", "answers": [ "目の付け所", "めのつけどころ" ], "comment": "Rank #1529 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "not doing as one is told; disobedient; unruly\n\nHint: 言う事を・・・", "answers": [ "言う事を聞かない", "いうことをきかない" ], "comment": "Rank #1530 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "All's grist that comes to his mill; turn everything to good account; turn anything to profit\n\nHint: 転んで・・・", "answers": [ "転んでもただでは起きない", "ころんでもただではおきない" ], "comment": "Rank #1531 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "sleep brings up a child well; a well-slept child is a well-kept child\n\nHint: 寝る・・・", "answers": [ "寝る子は育つ", "ねるこはそだつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1532 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to open hostilities; to be at war\n\nHint: 干戈を・・・", "answers": [ "干戈を交える", "かんかをまじえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1533 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "act on one's emotions; be carried away by one's feelings; get (become) emotional\n\nHint: 感情に・・・", "answers": [ "感情に走る", "かんじょうにはしる" ], "comment": "Rank #1534 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "truth is stranger than fiction\n\nHint: 事実は小説よりも・・・", "answers": [ "事実は小説よりも奇なり", "じじつはしょうせつよりもきなり" ], "comment": "Rank #1535 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Haste makes waste\n\nHint: 短気・・・", "answers": [ "短気は損気", "たんきはそんき" ], "comment": "Rank #1536 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "love is blind\n\nHint: 恋は・・・", "answers": [ "恋は盲目", "こいはもうもく" ], "comment": "Rank #1537 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "together; abreast; side-by-side\n\nHint: 轡を・・・", "answers": [ "轡を並べて", "くつわをならべて" ], "comment": "Rank #1538 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "accept one who comes to you\n\nHint: 来る・・・", "answers": [ "来る者は拒まず", "くるものはこばまず" ], "comment": "Rank #1539 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "After pleasure comes pain; There is no pleasure without pain; There is no rose without a thorn; Take the good with the bad\n\nHint: 楽あ・・・", "answers": [ "楽あれば苦あり", "らくあればくあり" ], "comment": "Rank #1540 (6 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to soar high (building, etc.)\n\nHint: 天を・・・", "answers": [ "天を摩する", "てんをまする" ], "comment": "Rank #1541 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have a good eye (from having seen fine art, etc.); to be a connoisseur\n\nHint: 目が・・・", "answers": [ "目が肥える", "めがこえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1542 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to spur (on); to expedite; to encourage\n\nHint: 拍車を・・・", "answers": [ "拍車を掛ける", "はくしゃをかける" ], "comment": "Rank #1543 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "soft on women\n\nHint: 鼻の・・・", "answers": [ "鼻の下が長い", "はなのしたがながい" ], "comment": "Rank #1544 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to use one's influence\n\nHint: 顔を・・・", "answers": [ "顔を利かす", "かおをきかす" ], "comment": "Rank #1545 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "exchanging sake cups\n\nHint: 差し・・・", "answers": [ "差しつ差されつ", "さしつさされつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1546 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be frightened\n\nHint: 胸を・・・", "answers": [ "胸を冷やす", "むねをひやす" ], "comment": "Rank #1547 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cover up; to hush up; to shroud in darkness\n\nHint: 闇から闇に・・・", "answers": [ "闇から闇に葬る", "やみからやみにほうむる" ], "comment": "Rank #1548 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the grass is always greener on the other side of the fence\n\nHint: 隣の・・・", "answers": [ "隣の芝生は青い", "となりのしばふはあおい" ], "comment": "Rank #1549 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It's hard to tell a poor thinker from a sleeping one; They to whom only bad ideas come might as well be asleep; Poor thinking is futile; Inadequate ideas are worse than none at all\n\nHint: 下手の・・・", "answers": [ "下手の考え休むに似たり", "へたのかんがえやすむににたり" ], "comment": "Rank #1550 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to survive without problems; to manage to avoid further problems\n\nHint: 事無きを・・・", "answers": [ "事無きを得る", "ことなきをえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1551 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the three Rs; reading, writing and arithmetic\n\nHint: 読み・・・", "answers": [ "読み書き算盤", "よみかきそろばん" ], "comment": "Rank #1552 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to become hard and fibrous; to go to seed; to have passed one's prime; to have lost the first bloom of one's youth\n\nHint: 薹が・・・", "answers": [ "薹が立つ", "とうがたつ" ], "comment": "Rank #1553 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "When one door is shut, another is open; The world is as kind as it is cruel\n\nHint: 捨て・・・", "answers": [ "捨てる神あれば拾う神あり", "すてるかみあればひろうかみあり" ], "comment": "Rank #1554 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "temptation one can't resist; setting a wolf to mind the sheep; trusting a cat with milk\n\nHint: 猫に・・・", "answers": [ "猫に鰹節", "ねこにかつおぶし" ], "comment": "Rank #1555 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a burnt child dreads the fire; once bitten twice shy; to become over cautious from a bad experience\n\nHint: 羹に・・・", "answers": [ "羹に懲りて膾を吹く", "あつものにこりてなますをふく" ], "comment": "Rank #1556 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to feel anxious; to feel uneasy; to worry\n\nHint: 気が・・・", "answers": [ "気が揉める", "きがもめる" ], "comment": "Rank #1557 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take the blame; to cover oneself in mud\n\nHint: 泥を・・・", "answers": [ "泥を被る", "どろをかぶる" ], "comment": "Rank #1558 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to cavil at a person's words; to use somebody's words to trip him up\n\nHint: 言葉尻を・・・", "answers": [ "言葉尻を捉える", "ことばじりをとらえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1559 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have the personal support of (an influential person); to be under the patronage of\n\nHint: 息が・・・", "answers": [ "息が掛かる", "いきがかかる" ], "comment": "Rank #1560 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to piss in the wind; to harm oneself in an attempt to harm someone else; to spit into the sky\n\nHint: 天に・・・", "answers": [ "天に唾する", "てんにつばする" ], "comment": "Rank #1561 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "extraordinary; preposterous; outrageous; absurd\n\nHint: 途方も・・・", "answers": [ "途方も無い", "とほうもない" ], "comment": "Rank #1562 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "The day is short, and the work is much; My goal is still a long way off\n\nHint: 日暮・・・", "answers": [ "日暮れて道遠し", "ひくれてみちとおし" ], "comment": "Rank #1563 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to disappear completely, leaving nothing behind\n\nHint: 地を・・・", "answers": [ "地を掃う", "ちをはらう" ], "comment": "Rank #1564 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "he that fights and runs away may live to fight another day; sometimes you have to lose to win\n\nHint: 負けるが・・・", "answers": [ "負けるが勝ち", "まけるがかち" ], "comment": "Rank #1565 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Heaven's net has large meshes, but nothing escapes\n\nHint: 天網恢恢疎に・・・", "answers": [ "天網恢恢疎にして漏らさず", "てんもうかいかいそにしてもらさず" ], "comment": "Rank #1566 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to gain fame; to make one's name\n\nHint: 名を・・・", "answers": [ "名を揚げる", "なをあげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1567 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to stir up trouble for oneself; to scare out a snake by poking at the brush\n\nHint: 藪を・・・", "answers": [ "藪をつついて蛇を出す", "やぶをつついてへびをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #1568 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "the greater embraces the less; better too big than too small\n\nHint: 大は小を・・・", "answers": [ "大は小を兼ねる", "だいはしょうをかねる" ], "comment": "Rank #1569 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Easy come, easy go; Lightly comes, lightly goes; Soon gotten soon spent\n\nHint: 悪銭身に・・・", "answers": [ "悪銭身につかず", "あくせんみにつかず" ], "comment": "Rank #1570 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a woman's heart and autumn weather (are both fickle)\n\nHint: 女心と・・・", "answers": [ "女心と秋の空", "おんなごころとあきのそら" ], "comment": "Rank #1571 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "like father, like son; the apple doesn't fall far from the tree\n\nHint: 蛙の・・・", "answers": [ "蛙の子は蛙", "かえるのこはかえる" ], "comment": "Rank #1572 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "a thorn in one's side; a pain in the butt (often someone higher in rank, ability, etc.); nuisance; something in the way\n\nHint: 目の・・・", "answers": [ "目の上の瘤", "めのうえのこぶ" ], "comment": "Rank #1573 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be experienced in the ways of the world; to taste the bitter and the sweet\n\nHint: 酸いも・・・", "answers": [ "酸いも甘いも噛み分ける", "すいもあまいもかみわける" ], "comment": "Rank #1574 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "quick bath\n\nHint: 烏の・・・", "answers": [ "烏の行水", "からすのぎょうずい" ], "comment": "Rank #1575 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to call one's ability into question; to weigh one's ability\n\nHint: 鼎の・・・", "answers": [ "鼎の軽重を問う", "かなえのけいちょうをとう" ], "comment": "Rank #1576 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to meet someone in person; to have the pleasure of meeting\n\nHint: 謦咳に・・・", "answers": [ "謦咳に接する", "けいがいにせっする" ], "comment": "Rank #1577 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "you can't give (use) what you don't have; nothing comes from nothing; you can't shake sleeves you don't have\n\nHint: 無い・・・", "answers": [ "無い袖は振れぬ", "ないそではふれぬ" ], "comment": "Rank #1578 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "strongly and repeatedly urging (demanding, requesting, pressing)\n\nHint: 矢の・・・", "answers": [ "矢の催促", "やのさいそく" ], "comment": "Rank #1579 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "It's good to have a girl first and then a boy\n\nHint: 一姫・・・", "answers": [ "一姫二太郎", "いちひめにたろう" ], "comment": "Rank #1580 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "(cast) pearls before swine\n\nHint: 豚に・・・", "answers": [ "豚に真珠", "ぶたにしんじゅ" ], "comment": "Rank #1581 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to talk big; to be bombastic\n\nHint: 大風呂敷を・・・", "answers": [ "大風呂敷を広げる", "おおぶろしきをひろげる" ], "comment": "Rank #1582 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Don't forget your first resolution\n\nHint: 初心・・・", "answers": [ "初心忘るべからず", "しょしんわするべからず" ], "comment": "Rank #1583 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "whatever misfortune happens; even if spears fall out of the sky\n\nHint: 槍が・・・", "answers": [ "槍が降っても", "やりがふっても" ], "comment": "Rank #1584 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to get jealous; to grow horns\n\nHint: 角を・・・", "answers": [ "角を出す", "つのをだす" ], "comment": "Rank #1585 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Patience is the only way\n\nHint: 忍の・・・", "answers": [ "忍の一字", "にんのいちじ" ], "comment": "Rank #1586 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "neither one thing nor the other; too short for a belt, too long for a sleeve tie\n\nHint: 帯に・・・", "answers": [ "帯に短し襷に長し", "おびにみじかしたすきにながし" ], "comment": "Rank #1587 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to lead a stingy life; to scrimp and save; to pinch pennies; to light one's fingernail (instead of a candle)\n\nHint: 爪に・・・", "answers": [ "爪に火をともす", "つめにひをともす" ], "comment": "Rank #1588 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to have loose bowels\n\nHint: 腹が・・・", "answers": [ "腹が下る", "はらがくだる" ], "comment": "Rank #1589 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "any event can bring about an effect in an unexpected way; if the wind blows the bucket makers prosper\n\nHint: 風が・・・", "answers": [ "風が吹けば桶屋が儲かる", "かぜがふけばおけやがもうかる" ], "comment": "Rank #1590 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to do as one wishes; to suit one's convenience\nfor something to happen as one expects\n\nHint: 心に・・・", "answers": [ "心に任せる", "こころにまかせる" ], "comment": "Rank #1591 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "being excessively cautious; knocking on a strong stone bridge before crossing it\n\nHint: 石橋を・・・", "answers": [ "石橋を叩いて渡る", "いしばしをたたいてわたる" ], "comment": "Rank #1592 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be famous; to be celebrated; to be worthy of the name\n\nHint: 名に・・・", "answers": [ "名に負う", "なにおう" ], "comment": "Rank #1593 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to spend all of one's free time; to spend one's time without constraint\n\nHint: 暇に・・・", "answers": [ "暇に飽かす", "ひまにあかす" ], "comment": "Rank #1594 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "state of uncertainty; limbo; leaving unfinished with the intention of inflicting suffering; dragging out tortuously; half-killing a snake\n\nHint: 蛇の・・・", "answers": [ "蛇の生殺し", "へびのなまごろし" ], "comment": "Rank #1595 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "fast-talking; always having another argument ready; not able to keep one's mouth shut; never at a loss for words\n\nHint: 口が・・・", "answers": [ "口が減らない", "くちがへらない" ], "comment": "Rank #1596 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to shade an account; to add something extra\n\nHint: 色を・・・", "answers": [ "色を付ける", "いろをつける" ], "comment": "Rank #1597 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "extremely disappointing; extremely frustrating; mortifying; vexing\n\nHint: 泣くに・・・", "answers": [ "泣くに泣けない", "なくになけない" ], "comment": "Rank #1598 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "Spare the rod and spoil the child; If you love your children, send them out into the world\n\nHint: かわいい子に・・・", "answers": [ "かわいい子には旅をさせよ", "かわいいこにはたびをさせよ" ], "comment": "Rank #1599 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "great vigor; tremendous energy; forceful enough to knock down birds in flight\n\nHint: 飛ぶ鳥を・・・", "answers": [ "飛ぶ鳥を落とす勢い", "とぶとりをおとすいきおい" ], "comment": "Rank #1600 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to grow old\n\nHint: 年を・・・", "answers": [ "年を拾う", "としをひろう" ], "comment": "Rank #1601 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "relationships (formed by wealth) will end when the money ends\n\nHint: 金の・・・", "answers": [ "金の切れ目が縁の切れ目", "かねのきれめがえんのきれめ" ], "comment": "Rank #1602 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to wheedle a person into doing something\nto carry a portable shrine\n\nHint: 御輿を・・・", "answers": [ "御輿を担ぐ", "みこしをかつぐ" ], "comment": "Rank #1603 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "very shrewd; highly intelligent; very smart\n\nHint: 目か・・・", "answers": [ "目から鼻へ抜ける", "めからはなへぬける" ], "comment": "Rank #1604 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to make a hasty escape; to flee helter-skelter\n\nHint: 風を・・・", "answers": [ "風を食らう", "かぜをくらう" ], "comment": "Rank #1605 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "children are a bond between husband and wife\n\nHint: 子は・・・", "answers": [ "子は鎹", "こはかすがい" ], "comment": "Rank #1606 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to take a lesson from (a wise person); to follow in the footsteps of\n\nHint: 爪の・・・", "answers": [ "爪の垢を煎じて飲む", "つめのあかをせんじてのむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1607 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "to be lazy\n\nHint: 体を・・・", "answers": [ "体を惜しむ", "からだをおしむ" ], "comment": "Rank #1608 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" },
	{ "question": "unavoidable; inevitable\n\nHint: 退っ・・・", "answers": [ "退っ引きならぬ", "のっぴきならぬ", "退っ引きならない", "のっぴきならない" ], "comment": "Rank #1609 (5 occurrences in 1300 novels)" }
	]
}
